<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Homeward bound</title>
	  <link>/homeward-bound</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2013-01-31T08:21:00+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/homeward-bound</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>This morning I find myself at Raleigh Airport (RDU) waiting to board a plane - a few days ahead of my original return schedule.</p>

<p>Due to some family medical issues back home, I have decided to cut my trip short and head home early.</p>

<p>Most of last night was spent rearranging flights. I’m now flying home via Detroit and LA back into Melbourne. It’s going to be a long haul, but with only about 4 hours sleep last night, I’m hoping to sleep well during the flights.</p>

<p>Well America - it’s been short, but its been fun… I even got to experience a “Tornado Watch” last night with high winds and tornado threats moving through the Raleigh area yesterday and overnight.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Flying Saucer</title>
	  <link>/the-flying-saucer</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2013-01-27T18:30:26+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/the-flying-saucer</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So it’s a Sunday afternoon in Raleigh, North Carolina. I find myself downtown with not much to do - as most places are closed.</p>

<p>On a cool afternoon, I now find myself at <a href="http://www.beerknurd.com">The Flying Saucer</a> - possibly the best bar I have been to in the Northern Hemisphere (and defiantly the US!)</p>

<p>With over 200 beers available, made up from both local brew craft and imported, where else should I be for a belated solo Australian day party? These guys know how to do beer. Every option is covered - even direct from the cask.</p>

<p>Further the daily “fire sale” which is on local beers today, means I can sample the local drop (which is quite handy to be honest) at $3 a pint!!</p>

<p>To be honest, I never have the yanks credit for any beer I had ever tasted - up until now! They can brew it like the best when it comes to local brew craft style beers. Pity none of these make out shores back in Australia.</p>

<p>Today I have eventually settled on a beer from the New Belgium beer company called “Fat Tire”. It’s an Amber Ale (from Fort Collins, CO) and defiantly delivers.</p>

<p>My “runner-up” for today is one if the locals (from Raleigh, NC) - a wheat beer by Lonerider called “Shotgun Betty”. This was a classic wheat beer with a nice banana follow thru.</p>

<p>To be honest, I would quite happily sit on either of these beers all arvo. But with limited time and variety and experimentation the key I have ended up tasting a wide range of brews from across the US. These two I mention though are the finishers for the afternoon and will happily see me home tonight.</p>

<p>You can join up to the UFO club at the bar also. Members who manage to drink their way to 200 beers are immortalised on a flying saucer on the roof or wall of the bar. The putter ring of the saucer indicating how many times you have reached the 200 brew milestone.</p>

<p>Unfortunately with my short time here I doubt I will come close to qualifying for my own saucer.</p>

<p>Given I was in transit for 26 hours yesterday, I have declared today to be my own personal and informal Australia Day. And I find the Flying Saucer a most enjoyable place to celebrate the day.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20130127-165641.jpg" alt="20130127-165641.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20130127-165652.jpg" alt="20130127-165652.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20130127-165700.jpg" alt="20130127-165700.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20130127-165707.jpg" alt="20130127-165707.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20130127-165713.jpg" alt="20130127-165713.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20130127-165722.jpg" alt="20130127-165722.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20130127-193141.jpg" alt="20130127-193141.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Only in America #1</title>
	  <link>/only-in-america-1</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2013-01-27T11:03:26+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/only-in-america-1</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>To kick off my “Only in America” series of posts (I am assuming there will be more than one), I bring to you some pictures of a locally “pimped ride” I came across in the car park of a local mall on my morning walk.<br />
<img src="/assets/images/img_16281.jpg" alt="Pimped Ride" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/img_1627.jpg" alt="Pimped Ride" /></p>

<p>I can only assume, that, much like the unique creatures that evolve in places such as Easter Island, this vehicle has similarly been forced to evolve and adapt to survive in local conditions.  I believe this one is particularly adapted to the snowy and icy conditions that are being experienced in the local area.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Touchdown - USA</title>
	  <link>/touchdown-usa</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2013-01-26T20:33:54+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/touchdown-usa</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So its now late evening in Raleigh, North Carolina, and I have checked into my hotel after some 26 hours of travel.</p>

<p>The fleeting moments that I saw of both Los Angeles (airport) and Atlanta (airport) have not really left much of a lasting impression.  LA was busy, and the queues started from the moment you left your seat on the plane.  Atlanta was somewhat more organised and low key - however it was later in the day.  Raleigh was almost closed.</p>

<p>Stepping outside the Raleigh airport onto the sidewalk to get a cab - the 0c temperature forced me to raid my bag for in search for my beanie - its cold compared to Melbourne this time of year.  There were even small clumps of snow/ice on the runway as we taxied into the airport.</p>

<p>Tired and smelly, I checked into my room and headed downstairs to catch a quick meal before the kitchen closed for the night.  A tasty quesadilla and a few locally brewed “North Carolina Pale Ales” has seen me contented for the evening.</p>

<p>The remainder of the evening will no doubt be lost to sleep.  Who knows what tomorrow will hold, but with a maximum forecast temperature of only 7c, I have no doubt it will involve my new thermals, beanie and jumpers.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>America - the business trip</title>
	  <link>/america-the-business-trip</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2013-01-25T19:11:17+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/america-the-business-trip</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Tonight, I find my self making final rushed preparations for a business trip to America (well lets be honest here… the fact that they are my “final preparations” does not also mean that they are not my first round of preparations either!).</p>

<p>So tomorrow morning I will find myself sitting on a Virgin Australia flight for the best part of 14 hours.  This constitutes leg one of my outward journey, and will take me from Melbourne to Los Angeles.  A few short hours after that, I will find myself on the second leg of my journey on board a Delta Airlines domestic flight out of Los Angeles headed for Atlanta.  Finally, the third leg of my journey will get me from Atlanta to my destination, Raleigh, North Carolina (Where? did I hear you say…).</p>

<p>So some 26 hours after leaving the warmth of my home in Melbourne, I will find my self in near freezing Raleigh - hailing a cab, heading for the hotel.</p>

<p>As I said, this is a business trip - so i’m not sure how much sight seeing I will be able to get packed into my eight short days - but being my first visit to America, I will be keen to soak up what I can.</p>

<p>On the way in I have one day to “acclimatise” before we get down to business.  I have about the same on the outward trip.  During these days I am hoping to see all of what Raleigh has to offer… I’m sort of assuming that two days may be sufficient??</p>

<p>Regardless, I am sure it will wet my appetite for a further more adventurous trip back at some point in the future.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
