<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title></title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Turkey - The Wrap Up</title>
	  <link>//turkey-the-wrap-up</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-05-27T06:41:51+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//turkey-the-wrap-up</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>We still have a day and a half left in Istanbul. Other than our last minute shopping and revisiting the Bazaar’s we are winding down and getting ready to come home.</p>

<p>We thought this was a good time to reflect on what we have done, and wanted to provide a brief wrap up of everything we have done while in Turkey.</p>

<p><strong>Gallipoli</strong><br />
Gallipoli was probably on top of our list. It was absolutely beautiful, and the historical significance almost meant it was a must do for us - and we weren’t disappointed.</p>

<p><strong>Istanbul (general)</strong><br />
Istanbul is great. Depending on how adventurous you are, will depend on how much you get out of Istanbul. Delving deep into the streets and alleys to uncover hidden, off the beaten track gems is great. But even we haven’t had time to explore everything. The tourist sights (Blue Mosque, Aya Sophia, Grand Bazaar, Spice Bazaar, Taksim Square) are always a must see for first time visitors such as myself - but I’m sure Laura is starting to get sick of them by now.</p>

<p><strong>Troy</strong><br />
Troy was interesting - probably more so from the Myth and Legend perspective than anything. To be able to say I have stood in Troy is quite amazing. Overall it’s not the most exciting of places however, and the tour is only an hour or so long. Defiantly worthwhile given we were in the area, but not something I would be making the 12 hour round bus trip for on it’s own.</p>

<p><strong>The Princes Island</strong><br />
The Princes Island is one of those curious sites. While you want to make sure you see it - and don’t get me wrong it was a nice place - there isn’t actually that much to do. Possibly this was one of the places we were least prepared for, and didn’t have much time to dig too deeply… So we could quite easily have missed the good stuff?</p>

<p>So what was our favourite? Basically the order in which they appear above is reflective of how highly each ranked.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Princes Island Ferry</title>
	  <link>//princes-island-ferry</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-05-26T14:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//princes-island-ferry</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Today we find ourselves jumping on the tram in Sultanahmet and heading down to the ports to grab a ferry out to the Princes Island.</p>

<p>By now we are used to the tram system - buy your token and ride. The port is at the end of the line which makes things even simpler.</p>

<p>Getting off at the port we are confronted by a wall of people - apparently everyone else has the same idea… After all it is the weekend.</p>

<p>We fall into the current of people an get towed along to where the ferries depart. Lining up to buy our ferry token, the line moves quickly - apparently the locals all know what they are doing and can easily read the instructions (which are all in Turkish). We arrive at the front of the queue - its our moment in the spotlight. No stress, there are only a dozen or so people queueing behind you.</p>

<p>Confronted by the simplicity of the ferry token machine I find myself frozen.. There are only 2 buttons.. Which do I press? And what the hell will I get for the 20TL I just inserted? Reading the display on the machine it appears I will get 1x of something, and 2x of something else, totalling 6TL. Now I know the token cost 4TL, so my powers of deduction lead me to believe I will get one of them based on the prices shown.</p>

<p>Pressing one of the buttons an hoping, I watch as the numbers confusingly tick up. 2x what I believe to be the ferry tokens, and 4x something else (lucky they are only 1TL each…).</p>

<p>A quick glance at Laura and we decide to lock it in - pressing the other button and hoping our money has been well spent.</p>

<p>Suddenly it’s like wining the jackpot at the pokies - as the remainder of my 20TL is returned to me in 1TL coins. Thankfully mixed into the drop is also 2 tokens for the ferry - and not soon enough from the looks of those patiently waiting behind the dumb tourists.</p>

<p>Tokens in hand, and now weighed down by a fist full of change we make out way to the boarding gates and onto the ferry. Inside we find ourselves a nice comfy seat next to a window and settle in for the trip - which we have no idea how long it will take.</p>

<p>Cruising out into the Bosporus, we decide to pass the time with a glass of Turkish tea or cia (pronounced chia) which the locals seem to have formed more than a mild addiction to.</p>

<p>Several stops and a bit over an hour later we start approaching Princes Island.</p>

<p>Off the ferry and onto the island, we find a local horse drawn cart and decide to take the island tour - we’re gluttons for tourist traps. While it was a nice ride around the island, and definitely allowed us to see much more in the afternoon we had on the island than we could have by foot, I’m still to be convinced it was worth the 60TL we paid.</p>

<p>After seeing the sights by horse drawn cart, we decided to head to the water front to grab a bite to eat. Unfortunately the little voice inside our heads didn’t scream out to us “Tourist Trap Ahead!”. It was as plain as the nose on your face. Nicely set out tables right on the water front. Anyway we sat, we ate, and we enjoyed. Then the bill arrived - needless to say this was by far our most expensive meal in Turkey yet (by a factor of two). Almost 100TL later we grabbed our bottle of water, paid and departed. Don’t get me wrong - the meal was good… Just not 100TL good.</p>

<p>So after a pleasant afternoon on Princes Island we grab another ferry back to Istanbul. The ferry trip is an experience in itself - almost a floating Grand Bazaar. There are people trying to sell everything to you. One guy in particular has mastered the art and commands the audience well - and converts his performance into multiple sales.</p>

<p>His sales performance is comedic and grand. He wouldn’t be out of place as the ring leader of a circus. First item is a retractable walking stick. He pulls it from his bag and extends it, and waits… “ooohh” he cry’s and the audience follow. Next he walks around using the stick demonstrating just how good it is. But wait.. It also has suspension built in. “ooohh” the crowd cry. But wait it also has a compass built in. “oooohhh” the crowd cry with applause. Also it has a small torch which he turns on and off to demonstrate. “ooooohhhh” the crowd cry again with further dramatic applause. Finally he collapses the walking stick back - so simple, so easy. “oooohhh” the crowd cry. And for the finale… Now with the walking stick fully collapsed, he swings it over his shoulder and scratches his back. The crowd erupt with laughter and cheers. “How much you pay?”… “10TL.. This is all.”</p>

<p>Moments later he is flooded by people waving their 10TL notes at him. He has easily made his days pay with this crowd.</p>

<p>But that’s not all - out comes the orange juicer. The crowd are again In the palm of his hand, and the show continues… And the money flows in.</p>

<p>Notably there are others on the ferry also trying to sell their wears - but none in as dramatic and comedic fashion. This guy is a genuine performer. It’s almost worth 10TL just for the show and the laughs - it also helps to pass the time on the ferry, and before we know it we’re arriving back into Istanbul.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Random Turkey Photos</title>
	  <link>//random-turkey-photos</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-05-25T14:26:14+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//random-turkey-photos</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-172300.jpg" alt="20120525-172300.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-172315.jpg" alt="20120525-172315.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-172329.jpg" alt="20120525-172329.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-172341.jpg" alt="20120525-172341.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-172409.jpg" alt="20120525-172409.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-172452.jpg" alt="20120525-172452.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-172518.jpg" alt="20120525-172518.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-172553.jpg" alt="20120525-172553.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Grand Bazaar</title>
	  <link>//the-grand-bazaar</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-05-25T13:20:58+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//the-grand-bazaar</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So after getting in pretty late last night from our two day tour down to Gallipoli and Troy, we had a pretty slow morning all tolled.</p>

<p>After eventually getting up and going we had out sights set on one thing, and one thing only - the Grand Bazaar.</p>

<p>Weaving our way through the streets of Sultanahmet, we headed in the general direction of the Bazaar… It’s almost as if the traders can sense your approach - must be the smell of fresh wallets in the air. The lead up to the Bazaar itself is surrounded but other smaller traders and stalls, a micro bazaar units own right.</p>

<p>Walking through the outside stalls and passing though the arched entry way into the Grand Bazaar you immediately sense the scale of the place, and mere meters inside you have been consumed by the labyrinth of alleys and narrow streets that run up and down - there is no escaping the seduction of the vendors within the Grand Bazaar now. You are on their turf and you will play by their rules, and doubtless to say - they will win you over, and “help you spend your money” (as one vendor quoted to us) in any which way you fancy.</p>

<p>Pausing to soak it all in is difficult. There Bazaar is typically awash with vendors, tourists, and everything in between. Today we have encountered what I am told is a slow day - even so the place is still buzzing - however I could imaging the place being easily twice as busy.</p>

<p>Finding a quieter place to the side of one of the alleys we did manage to pause and observe. The ceilings are painted with featuring frescos,the streets and alleys are lined with stalls and shops - each overflowing with the specific wares on offer, be it plates and ceramics, carpets, jewelry, trinkets, clothes (all knock off’s), any type of leather product you would want, bags, spices, Turkish delights, or musical instruments.</p>

<p>Walking past each store, the vendors will offer to show you their goods or attempt to coax you into their store - “Come inside, I’ll show you good price…”, or “I have others, come in…”. They are all typically very polite about it, which makes it even more difficult to ignore them or say no and keep walking. They are very attuned to our cultural style (or just bloody good guesses) and pick up immediately where we are from - “Your an Aussie… from Melbourne?”. Not one got it wrong.</p>

<p>Again this is part of the buying process - this is their ‘foot in the door’ so to speak. They know once they can get you to respond - its on… Just like fishing, they keep casting out into the crowd their bait of words, hoping for a bite. Once they have this, it’s their job to carefully reel you in and hopefully land the purchase - at an inflated price, but one that has come down considerably through the haggling process.</p>

<p>While they vendors can often have a poor reputation, and stories are told all too often about someone getting stuck in a carpet shop, being feed apple tea until the point of hallucination, and then waking up two days later to find they just spent $1,000 on a knock off carpet they didn’t even like - and have no way to get home… To be honest our feeling was that they vendors were actually all fairly well mannered. Some would defiantly be more persistent than others, but this is their lively hood. At no point did we feel pressured into purchasing anything. You do need to be strong, and you do need to have an idea of what your prepared to spend. The vendors know their bottom price and won’t let you push them below it. If this is still higher than your expectation, then continue to shop. If you keep getting the same answer, then you may need to reset your expectation, or keep looking. There is also a line between quality and cost. Often the vendors will see you pushing for a cheaper price, and will move to show you a different piece - “this one is the same, but cheaper” - now you have to ask why… Typically it will be of lower quality, and suddenly the bargaining you have just done on the better item has been rest without you knowing because you’ve been moved to a completely different product - a cheaper knock off version that no doubt has similar mark ups applied.</p>

<p>Doubtless to say, you need to go to the Grand Bazaar in the right frame of mind. Be prepared to look around for the price you think is fair. Be prepared to bargain. Be prepared to not get it your way. And most of all - be prepared to enjoy the experience. You shouldn’t go to the Grand Bazaar expecting to get one over on the vendors. You need to set out your budget and if you come in under or around it then be happy for the experience. If you end up spending way too much money and feel you were ripped off - this is not the vendors fault. You were not prepared, and not strong enough to keep your cash in your wallet.</p>

<p>And one last piece of advise - its only a bargain if you actually need it.</p>

<p>Anyway all told we had a great afternoon out at the Grand Bazaar. We managed to pick up a few pieces we liked at prices we thought were reasonable.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-160708.jpg" alt="20120525-160708.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-160719.jpg" alt="20120525-160719.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-160734.jpg" alt="20120525-160734.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-160748.jpg" alt="20120525-160748.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Mythical Troy</title>
	  <link>//mythical-troy</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-05-24T13:45:33+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//mythical-troy</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So after out day in Gallipoli, our tour takes us across the narrows of the Dardanelles to Canakkale which is in the Asian side of Turkey, an where we spend the night before heading of to nearby Troy (Troya) in the morning.</p>

<p>Troy is about a 30 minute bus ride out of Canakkle. We arrive to an overcast drizzling morning - its about now we wished we had packed our rain coats!</p>

<p>Walking through the archeological site that is Troy was very interesting, and our local guide again provided lots of details and background about the site.</p>

<p>One interesting fact relates to the site of Troy itself. Troy of legend and myth was a sea port - the actual location is somewhat inland (although the Dardanelles are visible from the high vantage point).</p>

<p>The belief is that thousands of years ago when Troy was prospering it was actually a sea port as described in the legends and myths. It is thought that heavy silting bought on by earth quakes in the region over time forced the narrowing of the mouth of the Dardanelles which in turn caused the sea to subside and form solid land - which is now in use as extremely fertile cropping country.</p>

<p>As with many other cities within Turkey, Troy saw its fair share of occupying rulers - the Trojans, the Greeks, and the Romans. Each new occupation saw dramatic reshaping of the earlier Troy - either because it had been raised to the ground from the conflict, or the new rulers wanting to inject their own cultural influences on the region.</p>

<p>This resulted in 9 different levels of Troy - all built on top of the ruins of the previous, and clearly visible as you walk through the archeological site.</p>

<p>All in all it was a very interesting tour. The only downside is the 6 hour bus ride back to Istanbul, which included the obligatory stop at the purpose built tourist trap buffet and shopping complex - glad we ate before we left 5TL for 2 Kebabs in Canakkale or 13TL each for crappy buffet in the middle of nowhere).</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-112106.jpg" alt="20120525-112106.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-112120.jpg" alt="20120525-112120.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-112131.jpg" alt="20120525-112131.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-112157.jpg" alt="20120525-112157.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-112028.jpg" alt="20120525-112028.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Gallipoli</title>
	  <link>//gallipoli</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-05-23T10:35:02+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//gallipoli</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Today we are on an overnight tour that will take us down to Gallipoli (Gelibolu) and then overnight in Canakkale (on the Asian side of Turkey), and the a tour through historic Troy before heading back to Istanbul later in the evening of the second day.</p>

<p>The trip from Istanbul down to Gallipoli took almost 5 hours on our small private tour bus - 11 people in group all up.</p>

<p>Arriving into the Gallipoli peninsular, our first stop was in Eceabat (historically a Greek town known as Maydos, but renamed by the Turks) - the reason for stopping here is so we can have our fill at the local tourist trap.</p>

<p>After lunch the actual tour started. Our guide joined us and we headed off for ANZAC cove. Over the course of the next 5 hours we visited many of the important and historic sites (including the landing beach, war graves, shrapnel valley, the Nek, Lone Pine, and the all important high ground - Chunuk Bair, that are spread around the peninsula.</p>

<p>The scenery around ANZAC cove and the views from Chunuk Bair were breath taking, and it is so hard to believe that almost 100 years ago this was the site of such a bloody battle where thousands of young ANZAC’s and Turks alike lost their lives. The cold reminder of this is littered everywhere… just out of sight but there if you know where to look, and what your looking for. Small pieces of shrapnel and bullets litter the ground and are very easy to find especially after a good rain.</p>

<p>Seeing first hand the terrain that the ANZAC’s faced on arrival really makes you think how anyone survived. The short length of beach, the high limestone cliffs, the overgrowth - how anyone made it to the top alive in the dark is beyond belief.</p>

<p>One of the hardest things for me to comprehend was how close the trenches were together - the best example of this is on the way up to Chunuk Bair where the single lane road is all that separates the trenches - Turkish trenches on the right, ANZAC trenches on the left. Absolutely amazing… No more than 6-7 meters separating the two - quite literally the width of the single lane road.</p>

<p>All up I am extremely glad to have done the tour. Our guide was excellent and provided lots of detail and stories about each of the sites we visited.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120524-083725.jpg" alt="20120524-083725.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120524-083811.jpg" alt="20120524-083811.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120524-083830.jpg" alt="20120524-083830.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120524-083844.jpg" alt="20120524-083844.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120524-083856.jpg" alt="20120524-083856.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120524-083911.jpg" alt="20120524-083911.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120524-083938.jpg" alt="20120524-083938.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120524-083953.jpg" alt="20120524-083953.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120524-084008.jpg" alt="20120524-084008.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120524-084015.jpg" alt="20120524-084015.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120524-084028.jpg" alt="20120524-084028.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120525-001612.jpg" alt="20120525-001612.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Istanbul Day 2 - Blue Mosque, Aya Sophia, Spice Bazaar, Taksim Square and Kebabs</title>
	  <link>//istanbul-day-2-blue-mosque-aya-sophia-spice-bazaar-taksim-square-and-kebabs</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-05-22T07:10:54+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//istanbul-day-2-blue-mosque-aya-sophia-spice-bazaar-taksim-square-and-kebabs</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So our second full day in beautiful Istanbul has been packed with sight seeing - all the usual touristy places: The Blue Mosque, Aya Sophia, The Spice Bazaar, and Taksim Square (notably we are leaving the Grand Bazaar for a later day).</p>

<p>Up and out reasonably early this morning our hotel is well positioned only a short walk to both the Blue Mosque and Aya Sophia. Up the hill and to the Blue Mosque first.</p>

<p>Joining the hundreds of other tourists that had already made their way to the Mosque, you find yourself queuing to get through the doors. Inside the Mosque is beautiful - massive low hanging chandeliers light the large inside space. Patterned carpets decorate the floors throughout and are used to assist in alignment for prayer.</p>

<p>After taking in the beauty of the Blue Mosque, it’s a short walk across the square to the Aya Sophia. By the time we had arrived here a large queue had now formed - although we found it moved quickly. Buying our tickets and passing through the security screening we entered the grounds of the Aya Sophia. Entering the Aya Sophia reminded me of many of the large ancient cathedrals we have visited throughout Europe. Inside is a massive open area with huge ceiling frescos, and low hanging chandeliers.</p>

<p>Upstairs contains some beautifully delicate mosaic frescos made up of thousands of tiny intricate tiles. Some of the mosaics have been damaged over time, but considering their age are actually remarkably well preserved.</p>

<p>After the first two touristy sights now ticked off the list, we decided to walk the streets of Istanbul and headed deeper into Saltanahmet before turning towards the sea to locate the Spice Bazaar. Our wanderings took us up and down many different and diverse streets and lane ways. We find one of the best and fun ways to explore a city is without a map and only a general sense for where you are headed - you always end up uncovering some little gem that makes your time in the city great. Today we found what I would have to describe as the best kebab place in the world.</p>

<p>In a little side street, not too far from the Spice Bazaar, we were drawn to a small kebab shop, called Sehzade Erzurum Cag Kebabi. The feature that drew our attention was a large wood fire and slow roasting lamb spit in the front of the store. The smell was amazing. This wasn’t your typical take-away fast food kebab place… This was the real deal, and we couldn’t pass it up.</p>

<p>Sitting down right next to the lamb spit, the wait staff quickly sorted our order out - two lamb kebabs each, bread, salad, chilli, and spiced onion. Sitting right next to the spit gave us the opportunity to watch the master kebab chief at work, carefully turning the spit to identify the best cooked meat, then craftily cutting and threading it onto a skewer. By this time our mouths were well and truly watering - nothing smells quite as good as lamb cooking over the fire… And I can assure you the taste was absolutely amazing!</p>

<p>After our fill of succulent lamb kebabs for lunch, we continued on wandering the streets and eventually found our way to the Spice Bazaar. Walking inside is a dizzying display of every spice, tea, nougat and sweat preserved fruits you could imaging - with the occasional plate, shoe or carpet store springing up in between. Resisting the urge to enter into any purchase we pushed on through the crowds and eventually emerged on the other side and back into the open street.</p>

<p>Next we crossed the river and continued walking in the aim of finding Taksim square. After a for walk we decided we had made a wrong turn at some point having now passed the port and the university - which we knew were close but not where we wanted to be. Unfortunately with the water on our right, this meant we had to go left… Up the really big hill. So, with no other option, up we went. After about a kilometer of walking up what could only politely be described as a bloody steep hill we emerged in Taksum square - to the relief of us both. What better time than now to pull up a seat in a cafe and indulge in a short break and a cool drink.</p>

<p>Taksim square was abuzz with people - all seemingly coming and going from nowhere. So after looking around for a while we headed back down the hill via the pedestrian street walkway to take in some of the retail sector.</p>

<p>At the bottom of the hill we decided to jump onto a tram and headed back to the hotel to rest up for a few hours before heading back out later tonight for dinner.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120522-171321.jpg" alt="20120522-171321.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120522-171345.jpg" alt="20120522-171345.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120522-171403.jpg" alt="20120522-171403.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120522-171427.jpg" alt="20120522-171427.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120522-171444.jpg" alt="20120522-171444.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120522-171458.jpg" alt="20120522-171458.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120522-171616.jpg" alt="20120522-171616.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120522-171627.jpg" alt="20120522-171627.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120522-1715481.jpg" alt="20120522-171548.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120522-171524.jpg" alt="20120522-171524.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120522-1715341.jpg" alt="20120522-171534.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120522-1715081.jpg" alt="20120522-171508.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Istanbul awakes</title>
	  <link>//istanbul-awakes</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-05-21T21:10:50+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//istanbul-awakes</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So after our first day in Istanbul I can confess it has well and truly won me over. There is something about Istanbul… Something I can’t quite put my finger on… something that has defiantly drawn me in.</p>

<p>This morning I find myself waking early - possibly due to jet lag, possibly due to the prayer calls - but I’m not complaining in the least. I headed up to the roof top terrace of our hotel to sit and watch as Istanbul slowly comes to life as the sun rises.</p>

<p>The outlook is across the Golden Horn and the Bosporus, with the Blue Mosque over my right shoulder and the Aya Sophia over my left. What could be more pleasant than this.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20120522-081159.jpg" alt="20120522-081159.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>We're in Istanbul, not Constantinople...</title>
	  <link>//were-in-istanbul-not-constantinople</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-05-21T07:20:45+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//were-in-istanbul-not-constantinople</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Wow, long flight overnight again. Seems like forever ago that we were checking in to our flight in KL airport. Anyway the flight was reasonably uneventful again (which in the case of air travel is actually a positive attribute).</p>

<p>We landed in at Ataturk airport in Istanbul at about 6am this morning. Apparently the Visa fee’s have increased… Last time Laura was here the Visa cost $20 USD, they now weigh in at a more hefty $60 USD (or $45 Euro). I guess when it comes time to find more money from taxes it’s easier to get it from the visitors than upset the locals.</p>

<p>Anyway Visas securely pasted into our passports, we collected our baggage and located our driver - he’s the guy holding the sign “Laura Modric”. A short ride into town later and we were checking into our hotel Tria in Sultanahmet - conveniently located between the Bosporus, Aya Sophia and the Blue Mosque - and all clearly visible from the hotels roof top terrace (somewhere I can see we will spend a number of evenings watching the sun setting with a refreshing beverage or five).</p>

<p>So were spending the morning chilling out a bit, catching up on some sleep and planning out what we want to do over the next few days.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Preparing the Turkey - The lead up to our Istanbul trip</title>
	  <link>//preparing-the-turkey-lead-up-to-istanbul-trip</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-05-06T05:44:04+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//preparing-the-turkey-lead-up-to-istanbul-trip</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So Laura and I will be heading off to Turkey in a few weeks.  While Laura has been to Turkey twice previously, this will put a tick in the “done” column on my travel bucket list.</p>

<p>The more people we talk to about Turkey, the better it sounds - I haven’t met anyone yet with a bad story, and actually all the stories I have heard sound fantastic.</p>

<p>It will be a reasonably whirlwind trip this time, about 11 days in total made up of 2 days in Kuala Lumpur on the way over, then the rest of our time in Turkey being mainly concentrated in Istanbul with an overnight trip to Gallipoli (to see the ANZAC war memorials and battle fields) and historic Troy.</p>

<p>So as our preparations continue, the excitement is building - and the clock is ticking until we leave.  While in Istanbul I am planning on taking a lot of photos - what is there not to like about a city so full of vibrant colours, culture and postcard like scenes such as  the Blue Mosque, the Grand Bazaar, the Spice Bazaar, and the Ayasofya.</p>

<p>With luck we will have internet access during our trip, so I will be able to sit back in the evenings enjoying a refreshing local beverage or two, possibly smoking on a Shisha Pipe, and reflect on the events of the day to distil the essence of our day into a blog post.</p>

<p>Until then… elveda  (goodbye in Turkish - according to Google translate at least :) )</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
