<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title></title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Day Dreaming - Day 3</title>
	  <link>/day-dreaming-day-3</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-12-11T18:46:31+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/day-dreaming-day-3</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So day three of our stay on Day Dream Island has come, and now almost past.</p>

<p>Today was made up of not a lot, but all of which was thoroughly relaxing.</p>

<p>After a late breakfast, we headed over to “Lovers Cove” for some more snorkelling. It was a clear morning so the visibility was incredible.</p>

<p>After our snorkelling, we lounged on the deck at Lovers Cove looking out over the ocean gathering a few rays of sun, before heading back pool-side once the bar had opened.</p>

<p>Mid-morning and early afternoon were spent in and out of the pool, before retreating back to the room to ready for a surprise that Laura had organised for us in the afternoon.</p>

<p>2pm came around, and we headed off to the day spa for the couples indulgence relaxation package - 2.5hrs of indulgent massage, and spa therapy to really wind-down at the end of a quick break.</p>

<p>It must have been good because, I found myself drifting in and out of sleep during the entire session… Could also have been something to do with the champagne before, during, and after ;-)</p>

<p>It was an amazing way to top off 3 days away, and a great surprise from my wife.</p>

<p>This evening, we find ourselves looking out over the ocean on the southern end of Day Dream Island, watching the sun go down, waiting for tonight’s open air movie to start - wonder if we will make it more than 5min tonight…</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121211-183947.jpg" alt="20121211-183947.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121211-184006.jpg" alt="20121211-184006.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121211-184045.jpg" alt="20121211-184045.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121211-184126.jpg" alt="20121211-184126.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121211-184145.jpg" alt="20121211-184145.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>5 things I would take to a desert island</title>
	  <link>/5-things-i-would-take-to-a-desert-island</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-12-10T17:47:29+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/5-things-i-would-take-to-a-desert-island</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So my last post got me thinking… What are the 5 things I would take to a desert island.</p>

<p>Having now been “stranded” (a term I use extremely loosely) on Day Dream island for two days, I feel I have had enough experience to make a fully qualified answer to the question I pose.</p>

<p>The 5 things I would bring to a desert island are (and bare with me…):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Resort style facilities</li>
  <li>Resort staff</li>
  <li>Enough food to last a lifetime</li>
  <li>Enough grog to last a life time… I’m talking top shelf also. If your stranded you don’t want to go without ;-)</li>
  <li>My best friends (this includes my beautiful wife Laura!). Why should I suffer like this alone ;-)</li>
</ul>

<p>So let me hear your comments.. What would you take?<br />
Serious, or not… Lets hear it.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Day Dreaming - Day 2</title>
	  <link>/day-dreaming-day-2</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-12-10T17:23:46+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/day-dreaming-day-2</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Another sun filled day in paradise… well on Day Dream Island at least.</p>

<p>After a slightly cloudy and overcast morning, the day had turned out superbly.</p>

<p>Laura did here obligatory site inspection (as a travel agent, it’s part of the deal). Meanwhile I walked to the other end of the island in search of water and water holding appliances - of which we are now owners of.</p>

<p>Today was our swimming/snorkelling day. We hired our equipment, and living on the edge as we do, we went without the recommended stinger suits. While it is currently stinger season, I suspected its more of “would you like fries with that…” season.</p>

<p>Needless to say, we swam, we sore, we didn’t get stung… On the body or in the wallet…</p>

<p>After picking up our gear we walked to the south end of he island and found the rainforest walk - with lots of nice outlooks over the water to neighbouring islands. The rainforest walk leads down to Lovers Cove, one of the better secluded beaches on the island - and only open to guests.</p>

<p>While the fish and coral are not comparable to the outer reef, what we saw was still nice, and the bath temperature water makes the whole experience much more enjoyable.</p>

<p>Lunch was somewhat an involved process. Somehow we got forgotten… Oops… And buy the time we got our meal (a gin &amp; tonic, vodka &amp;amp cranberry, and 2 beers later), we were too hungry to complain that Laura’s meal, while close, wasn’t exactly what she ordered. Something we will get over…</p>

<p>Pool time next, and a few more refreshing beverages lead to a great, and relaxing afternoon.</p>

<p>Now we find ourselves relaxing on our balcony, looking out across the resort and the ocean view with a bottle of sparking, and some subtle Afro Cuban All Stars playing off an iPhone in the background. Couldn’t really find a better way to chill out for an afternoon.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121210-172208.jpg" alt="20121210-172208.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121210-172223.jpg" alt="20121210-172223.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121210-172244.jpg" alt="20121210-172244.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121210-172257.jpg" alt="20121210-172257.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121210-172313.jpg" alt="20121210-172313.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Day Dreaming - Day 1</title>
	  <link>/day-dreaming-day-1</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-12-10T07:20:32+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/day-dreaming-day-1</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So we hit the ground running in our first day on Day Dream Island, and went straight into relaxation overdrive.</p>

<p>The day pretty much rolled on as follows:</p>

<ul>
  <li>leisurely stroll around the island</li>
  <li>lunch</li>
  <li>cocktails by the pool</li>
  <li>cocktails in the pool</li>
  <li>cocktails by the beach</li>
  <li>cocktails in the lounge</li>
  <li>relaxation hydrotherapy session</li>
  <li>dinner right at the beach front, with an amazing view out across the water</li>
  <li>open air cinema with some popcorn as a few beers</li>
</ul>

<p>After a 4am start, we quickly discovered ourselves succumbing to the effects of the early start and the relaxing effects of the day - both of us were out like a light at the open air cinema, 5min into the move ;-)</p>

<p>Needless to say, after a brief stroll home, our first day ended there - it was 8pm.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121210-071154.jpg" alt="20121210-071154.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121210-071208.jpg" alt="20121210-071208.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121210-071225.jpg" alt="20121210-071225.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121210-071235.jpg" alt="20121210-071235.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Day Dream Begins</title>
	  <link>/the-day-dream-begins</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-12-09T10:04:56+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/the-day-dream-begins</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So the Day Dream begins…</p>

<p>Waking up at 4am this morning, making the chilly journey out to the airport, we have flown north to Hamilton Island, and are now sitting on the upper deck of the ferry that will take us to Day Dream Island.</p>

<p>While the weather is somewhat overcast, with the very odd dot of rain here and there, it is still very warm, and quite hot when the sun breaks through. The first challenge will be to not get sunburnt on our transfer across to Day Dream.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121209-100414.jpg" alt="20121209-100414.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20121209-101005.jpg" alt="20121209-101005.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
