<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Peru here we come</title>
	  <link>//peru-here-we-come</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-29T03:58:53+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//peru-here-we-come</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/peru-nazca-lines.jpg" alt="" title="Peru - Nazca Lines" />
It’s been a few days since we have had a chance to grab a seat in front of a computer (probably a good thing), so I will try to fill you all in on what we have been up to in the last few days.</p>

<p>We started our Intrepid tour of Peru on Friday. We all met in a small hotel in Miraflores (a suburb of Lima). There are 13 of us in the group, and we all get along really well. The group is a really well balanced mix of people and ages - mostly Australians, and some Poms.</p>

<p>The first day comprised a short walking tour of Lima, which took us to the San Francisco church and the catacombs underneath. Laura and I had already seen the catacombs during our week in Lima, so passed and instead decided to check out the church, which was closed when we visited the first time.</p>

<p>One thing we noticed immediately (on attempting to make our local payment), was they hate, and will bluntly reject any US notes that are even slightly damaged. This is a real pain, as the banks and ATM’s dish them out freely. The result was we got stuck with a couple of spare US notes that are very difficult to pass off to anyone. Oh well… lessons learned. I’m sure the europeans won’t be as picky.</p>

<p>Anyway, we left Lima in the afternoon and headed south for Pisco. Pisco was recently (back in August) devastated by an earthquake, and around 600 people were killed. Unfortunately the city is still in ruin so there is not too much to take in here (from a tourists perspective).</p>

<p>Pisco is the city that gives its name to Peru’s national drink, the Pisco Sour (as you may have read, we have enjoyed a few of these). Pisco is made out of grapes grown in the Pisco region. Its essentially a distilled wine, and varies in potency from regular wine at about 12% to a very highly distilled alcohol at about 60-70%. Pisco sour is made with a form of Pisco that sits somewhere in the middle, and is mixed with lemon or lime juice, sugar syrup, and egg white, which is all blended together. The egg white gives it a frothy head. Its then topped with wither bitters, or more commonly cinnamon. Its rather refreshing on a warm day. Traditionally its intended as an aperitif, but is commonly drunk at any time (by us at least :))</p>

<p>From Pisco, we took a short bus ride down to the coast - passing a number of fish processing factories on the way (pin pointing the source of the strong fishy smell in the area). From a small coastal port we took a fast boat out to the Paracas islands. These are a set of small islands just off the coast which host heaps of bird life and sea lion colonies. On the larger of the islands was a huge candelabra figure etched into the side of the mountain face - this was pretty impressive to see, and gave us a taste for what we could expect later in Nazca.</p>

<p>From the coastal port we began heading inland for Nazca. The landscape in this area is essentially barron desert. Its very arid, and not many features except the odd tree, and mountains on either side.</p>

<p>We stopped in at a desert oasis on the way to Nazca for lunch. This was littery exactly how the cartoons picture them - it’s the middle of the desert, sand dunes for miles, then as you come over the top of one, you can see the other side, and instead of more sand, there is a small lake and some lush greenery with a hotel and some shops surrounding the lake.</p>

<p>We had the option to sand board here, but considering the head, and my previous experiences with large sand dunes I decided against it, considering we had a further 3 hours to Nazca. We didn’t really feel like sitting on the bus full of sand. It would have stuck to everything considering how hot it was.</p>

<p>So we settled for a light lunch, a few crevasses (beers), and a walk round the oasis instead.</p>

<p>We headed off to Nazca after lunch. Again more desert that was only broken up as we approached Nazca, and had to start going through some small mountains. This was pretty exciting after a few hours of desert. Coming into Nazca, we stopped at a roadside tower on the Nazca plains to observe some of the famous Nazca lines. Not a great view but gave us a taste.</p>

<p>Our hotel in Nazca was pretty nice - air con, pool, etc. It’s actually been the best so far.</p>

<p>Last night we headed out for a meal and a local Peruvian show, which featured some native dancing, as well as an Andean band, which was pretty great. I had the Ceveche - a Peruvian specialty of raw fish marinated in lemon/lime juice and vinegar (which sort of cooks the fish on the outside, and presumably kills any nasties?). It was quite nice - would defiantly have it again.</p>

<p>Today we took a (very small) plane (3 passengers) to fly out over the Nazca plains to see the lines from the air. This was great, a little nerve racking at times, and nauseating, but defiantly worth it. Just as we were about to head back, the lady in the front (also from our tour group) popped… projectile vomiting all over the side window and panel in front of her. The plane was defiantly too small for this. The smell nearly set us off in the back seat, but we managed to hold it together and got back in one piece - although our stomachs were a little stirred up.</p>

<p>Tonight were waiting for the overnight bus (about 11pm) to pick us up and take us to Araquipa. This is where we will start getting into the altitude, so light meals tonight and no grog…</p>

<p>Anyway, looking forward to whats to come.</p>

<p>Love you all</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Peruvian Highlights Tour Begins</title>
	  <link>//peruvian-highlights-tour-begins</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-27T00:31:01+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//peruvian-highlights-tour-begins</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>We meet up with our tour group last night in Miraflores (just out of Lima) in the hotel we were staying in for the night.</p>

<p>Our tour group is pretty good - a mix of both young and older people, but all lovely.</p>

<p>We left Lima this afternoon and after a 3-4 hour bus ride we have arrived in Pisco - the city where the national drink gets its name from.</p>

<p>The earthquake in Peru last year has hit this place pretty hard, and a lot of places have been flattened - luckily our hotel wasn’t one of them.</p>

<p>The first impressions of Pisco - you step off the bus and the distinct aroma of fish is in the air - I would describe it more of a fish flavoured cat food smell… well its only for a night.</p>

<p>Anyway, hope to be able to post some pics soon as we get access to a USB port.</p>

<p>Till then - Love you all</p>

<p>Lucas &amp; Laura</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Touchdown in Lima</title>
	  <link>//touchdown-in-lima</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-21T01:45:02+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//touchdown-in-lima</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/peru-lima-dinner.jpg" alt="" title="Peru - Lima dinner" />
So we flew out of Santiago this morning (bright and early) into Lima, Peru.</p>

<p>I probably should have mentioned it earlier, but was only reminded about the fantastic view from the airplane window as you approach Santiago - floating through the clouds between the various snow capped mountains. It was an awesome experience. However, coming into Lima today topped it.</p>

<p>There was a lot of low clouds around Lima today and this made for a fantastic approach in the airplane, with the peaks of mountains breaking though into the clear air above the cloud. It was like a sea of white with little islands scattered around.</p>

<p>Once we landed in Lima, we negotiated immigration and customs - not quite the same experience you would get in Australia, quite simple, and not much too it, although it is Sunday!</p>

<p>We got into our arranged cab - a clapped out white Nissan wagon with big crack up through the windscreen - and headed for the Hostel (about a 30min ride) - what an experience… That imaginary third lane that exists somewhere between the lane that you expect to be in and the lane that the oncoming traffic is in was used by all, including our driver. Also in two lanes of one way traffic you can fit three cars! I think the lines on the road are more decorative than law.</p>

<p>This first experience made us a little nervous, but we arrived at our hostel in one piece.</p>

<p>We settled in and headed out to explore the neighbour hood. Our hostel is right on the cost, with the beach about a 5 min walk away. Unfortunately there is a heavy sea mist at the moment so visibility is minimal, but we expect a spectacular view and sunsets when it clears (hopefully in the next day or two).</p>

<p>The local neighbourhood has some nice places to get local food. We selected one about 2 min up the road and grabbed the Arroz con Mariscos (rice with seafood) - this was brilliant, very fresh and nice flavors.</p>

<p>Anyway, were back at the hostel now and will probably take it easy tonight and try to put together some idea of what we want to get up to here in Lima.</p>

<p>No photos yet - but hope to get some soon.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Our last day in Santiago</title>
	  <link>//our-last-day-in-santiago</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-20T00:57:33+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//our-last-day-in-santiago</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/chile-santiago-markets.jpg" alt="" title="Chile - Santiago Markets" />
So today is our last day in Santiago. We started out by heading to the post office to send off a few post cards to family back home. Right next to the post office in the Plaza de Armas is a huge old church where we went to mass.</p>

<p>From there we went onto the Marceto Centro (the central market) which is basically a cut down version of the Victoria Market in Melbourne.</p>

<p>Next onto the Museum of Pre-Colombian times. This was great - a lot of history and really interesting artifacts to view from the Aztec, Mays &amp; Inca times.</p>

<p>Tonight were off for our last meal in Santiago, and a few drinks before an early flight to Lima, Peru tomorrow morning.</p>

<p>Again, there are a few more pictures up in our Santiago gallery - enjoy :)</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>In and around Santiago</title>
	  <link>//in-and-around-santiago</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-19T02:39:35+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//in-and-around-santiago</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/chile-dusk-in-santiago.jpg" alt="" title="Chile - Dusk in Santiago" />
So we have settled our selves in and found our feet here in Santiago. We have managed to explore most of what the city has to offer (we think).</p>

<p>We have visited many of the beautiful old buildings (Churches, etc), as well as the various parks and gardens that are around the city.</p>

<p>For us, the big let down of Santiago is the smog! Its bad. No doubt there is worse, but it blocks what is one of Santiago’s best assets - the mountains. Santiago is surrounded by mountains. On one side the Andes, and on the other the costal mountain range. But unfortunately, you can barely make them out through the smog, and there is no hope for a good photo :(.</p>

<p>Yesterday we jumped on a tour out to Valparaso and Viña del Mar - two lovely cities basically on top of each other, about 2 hours bus ride to the north west of Santiago. These two cities are built on the Pacific Ocean, in fact some of Valparaso has actually been re-claimed from the ocean.</p>

<p>Today we toured the remainder of Santiago. Jumping on a Touris Tek double decker bus which takes you around the city, allowing you to get on/off at any of the 11 set stops. This worked pretty well for us, as we were able to skip the areas we had already seen and concentrate on the areas we hadn’t.</p>

<p>The main high light - and we do mean high - was the aerial cable car ride through the park at Cerro San Cristobal. This was 2km of hell for us, neither of us being great with hights - but provided a spectacular view of the smog covered mountains ;). The views were really spectacular.</p>

<p>Once at the top we visited the shrine to San Cristobal, and the small chapel as well. Getting down the mountain was less stressful. The Finacula (a cable tram up the side of the hill) was great.</p>

<p>So after a couple of long days we are pretty buggered, and hoping to get a good night sleep. Both of us have struggled a little with jet lag - sudden burst of being awake at 1am, 4am, etc… Trying to force ourselves into a regular sleep pattern, but its hard.</p>

<p>So what does tomorrow bring. We are hoping to go to a local mass at one of the many ancient churches. Mass in spanish should be different, and the atmosphere of the old churches is something to experience.</p>

<p>Oh… by the way, I have added a few more photos to the Santiago picture album - enjoy, we are :)</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Santiago pictures</title>
	  <link>//santiago-pictures</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-16T23:49:03+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//santiago-pictures</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/chile-santiago-streets.jpg" alt="" title="Chile - Santiago streets" /></p>

<p>I have managed to post some of our pictures from around the neighbourhood where we are staying. There are not too many up there yet, but I hope to be able to get more up soon. Its difficult due to the size of my image files, and not being able to resize them easily in internet cafe’s… oh well.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Hola! The trip begins.</title>
	  <link>//hola-the-trip-begins</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-15T15:47:24+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//hola-the-trip-begins</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Hi all,</p>

<p>After a reasonable, but long flight we touched down in Santiago yesterday afternoon (14th). After some sleep, we had our first dinner here, which consisted of a packet of Corn chips &amp; a bottle of local red wine called ´Carmen´ - made the choice easy.</p>

<p>After some more sleep last night we had a light breakfast where we are staying, and have headed out to try and get a feel for the place. Hope to do some tours during the week to see the sights, etc.</p>

<p>The city is reasonably nice. We are staying in the european area, which has nice buildings and cobble stone streets. The rest of the city is basically like any other - very busy. The smog here is noticeable, although not too bad.</p>

<p>We hope to have some photos up here shortly.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Modrich Blog - Travel, Stories, Experiences...</title>
	  <link>//the-modrich-blog-travel-stories-experiences</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-03T23:10:34+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//the-modrich-blog-travel-stories-experiences</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Welcome to The Modrich Blog.</p>

<p>Here we want to share our travels, stories and experiences with anyone wanting to listen :)</p>

<p>We started this blog mainly to allow our family to follow us throughout out travels as we are about to embark on what will possibly be the “trip of our lives” spending 3 months travelling through South America and Europe - so fun times ahead for sure.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
