<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Working in Durban (RSA)</title>
	  <link>/working-in-durban-rsa</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-09T07:42:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/working-in-durban-rsa</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So I have been in Durban for a few days now. Mostly work meetings with clients and not much down time to get out and see the place (im not hear for leisure!).</p>

<p>We have ventured out and visited a number of the local cafes to grab a meal here and there and to get out of the hotel - but for the most nothing beyond the walls of the compound we are staying in or the offices of our clients.</p>

<p>We did get out to the local shopping centre one evening to visit out client retail outlet and to get a better feel for their operation - but again - this was not a social visit.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2aeb0-durban.png" alt="Durban - South Africa" /> Durban - South Africa</p>

<p>We are staying about 20km north of the Durban CBD itself - and the are is a mix of residential and industrial.</p>

<p>The weather has been quite nice - around 22c each day and down to about 12c over night.  Very pleasant compared to the brisk mornings we have had in Melbourne recently.</p>

<p>Today is actually a public holiday here in South Africa - so I am using the local down time to put together my notes  session earlier in the week and to plan and pre for the remainder of the week ahead.</p>

<p>Given the nice weather, I decided that today my office would be the back deck of the hotel where we are staying it - nice warm sunshine, a good view across the lake to the 18th hole of the local golf course (looks like a lovely day for a round!) and plenty of monkeys and mongoose to keep me company.</p>

<p>This afternoon, we took some time out to venture out and take a drive through Durban and the surrounding area on the way to an early dinner.</p>

<p>Durban downtown was a mix of new and old buildings - and I have the feeling some areas that you really don’t want to get too close to. We passed through quickly and headed back north to the beach suburb of Umhlanga - which was quite nice and obviously a more wealthy part of town.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/399fc-sunrisefrommyroomsunrisefrommyroom.jpg" alt="Sunrise from my room" /> Sunrise from my room</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/13bfa-cheekymonkiescheekymonkies.jpg" alt="Cheeky Monkey @ Hotel" /> Cheeky Monkey @ Hotel</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f1f22-img.jpg" alt="Moses Mabhida Stadium in Durban" /> Moses Mabhida Stadium in Durban</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Headed to South Africa (for Work)</title>
	  <link>/headed-to-south-africa-for-work</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-06T03:39:24+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/headed-to-south-africa-for-work</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Tonight I boarded a flight from Melbourne destined for Durban, South Africa - via Perth (on Virgin Australia) and Johannesburg (on South African Airlines).</p>

<p>This will be my first time on the African continent (only Antarctica left now!!) - and im not really sure what to expect. So many stories, some good and some bad.</p>

<p>This is a work trip however, and I am not anticipating much time for rest and relaxation or sight-seeing - but will endeavour to find some time to take a brief look around Durban one there, and possibly pick up a few gifts for the family back home.</p>

<p>So I now find myself now sitting in Perth airport with 3hrs+ to spare before my connecting flight to JoBerg. Perth airport a lot more modern than I expected, and probably one of the most modern I have been to.</p>

<p>Getting through immigration and across the border was a breeze - probably the best experience I have ever had. I suspect my swift transit through boarder control is aided by the electronic passport control used for outbound passengers. I am familiar with this when coming back into Melbourne after an international flight, but this is the first time I have seen it used for outbound passengers…</p>

<p>Let me tell you - it’s a bloody dream compared to the queues you normally face in Melbourne.</p>

<p>So with 3hrs+ to kill, I find myself - along with pretty much every one else bound for South Africa - at the bar in the international departures lounge.</p>

<p>Its a picture of tired people huddled in small groups around every chair and table in the small bar, with many others (myself included) spilling out into the common area. Many of us sucking in as much power as out devices will take ahead of the coming 11hr flight to JoBerg.</p>

<p>A few local drops (Rogers by Little Creatures being my personal favourite), are helping to reset the body clock into a slumber mode for the coming flight. With a full week of work ahead of me once I hit the ground in Durban, I need to try and adjust to the new time zone rapidly. I find beer helps ;)</p>

<p>So as I am quickly running out of words to type - and at the risk of rambling on… I guess this is good night.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The City of Angels</title>
	  <link>/the-city-of-angels</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-24T20:04:35+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/the-city-of-angels</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Earlier in the week (Monday 17th Aug) we left New York behind us (sad to leave but we have to move on), and flew across the country to Los Angeles.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/70530-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We weren’t actually staying in L.A. but just south in Anaheim as we planed to take Archie to Disneyland.</p>

<p>We arrived into our hotel in the early evening and checked in. We had a large suite on the top floor which was quite big compared to all the places we had stayed at on the trip - the only downside was, while being two rooms, it was actually only a single bed room with two queen sized beds - we got over that pretty quickly though.</p>

<p>After settling in for a bit we headed down to the restaurant in the hotel to get Archie fed. The restaurant wasn’t anything to write home about, but it provided a reasonable range of food and drinks and was adequate.</p>

<p>After dinner we booked our tickets to Disneyland and headed off to bed - tired after the long day and still operating on New York time.</p>

<h2 id="disneyland-park">Disneyland Park</h2>

<p>We woke early the next morning (Tuesday 18th Aug), as the plan was to get to the park at opening time (8am) to maximise our time inside.</p>

<p>We caught the local ART bus from the hotel ($5 for a day ticket) and in under 10 min we were pulling into the Disneyland bus hub.</p>

<p>Off the bus, we cleared security and then entered the park. Coincidentally it’s currently Disneyland’s 60th (Diamond) anniversary - and additional festivities were occurring to celebrate.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f9a49-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We wandered through Disneyland main street and up toward the castle taking it all it.</p>

<p>Everything was perfect and clean - quite unbelievable considering the number of people they have through the gates on a daily basis.</p>

<p>We decided to take Archie on his first ride - the Snow White ride - it looked harmless enough. We waited in line and then boarded out 4-seater trolley car and off we went. About 10 seconds into the trip we quickly realised that the story of Snow White is actually quite dark - and this was well represented in the ride - very dark with lots of loud scary noises - witches and things jumping out at you… Archie was not a fan - in fact he was bloody terrified! Oops…</p>

<p>Luckily the ride wasn’t long - but the poor little guy was not very happy at the end of it. We took a breather and then decided to try our luck again - Pinocchio.</p>

<p>Oops… Another luck out… Much the same as Snow White, there is also a dark side to the Pinocchio story - which again was well emphasised in the ride. Archie was not a happy camper again!</p>

<p>Looking to recover from the past two terrifying experiences we had just submitted out son to - we saw the Dumbo ride - much like a carousel, but you can control the up and down motion - thankfully he loved this and all was good in the world once again.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/65915-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>From then on we selected Archie friendly rides - the animal train, Its A Small World, the Disneyland train, Whiney the Poo, etc.</p>

<p>We wandered our way through the park with no real plan. We manage to bump into Donald Duck, Mickey Mouse and Woody and snagged some happy snaps with these characters.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/a75a5-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/06c5d-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/bbf9b-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>By about 2pm we decided to head back to the hotel to put Archie down for a sleep. We all took some time out, either catching up on some sleep ourselves or having a dip in the pool.</p>

<p>We headed back to the park at about 4pm - just in time to watch the parade down Main Street - before continuing to explore the areas of the park we had yet to visit.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/39572-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/117b5-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Later in the evening we managed to find a ‘reasonable’ place to sit and watch the evening light show parade which was then followed by the fireworks show - a great end to a great (and very long) day.</p>

<p>At this time Archie was doing incredibly well to still be awake - so we headed home to hit the hay.</p>

<h2 id="the-outlets-at-orange">The Outlets at Orange</h2>

<p>Wednesday (19th Aug) we decided to head out shopping at the local Outlets in Orange. This turned out to be quite a big day out. While I don’t have anything else to compare it to - the outlets served out ‘needs’ well… We walked away all burdened down with bags containing new clothes, shoes and other bits and pieces. While the exchange rate isn’t as good as it was a few years ago - there were still some good bargains to be had - and we did!</p>

<h2 id="home-time">Home time</h2>

<p>Thursday (20th Aug) was our last day in Anaheim, and also the last day of our trip. We had a late flight back to Australia so didn’t need to be back to LAX until later in the evening - which meant we had pretty much a full day to do what we wanted.</p>

<p>Carmen decided to head out to do some more shopping and sightseeing on the ART buses. Laura, Jo, Archie and I decided to lay low and chill out at the hotel - although that lasted about an hour.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/79b67-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Laura and I decided to head out for a walk - and it was while walking that we discovered an alternate route to Disneyland… only 10 min walk away… oh well. We also discovered Downtown Disneyland - a restaurant and shopping precinct right next to the Disneyland Parks. Had we realised this was here we would likely have walked up each evening for a few drinks and dinner - there was a lot of choice, and while it was more expensive than the hotel (it is part of Disneyland after all), it would have provided a bit more atmosphere and variety. Oh-well… we know for next time.</p>

<p>Basically the remainder of our day ended up being spent at Disneyland Downtown. You would have thought that by now we would have had out fill of shopping… It appears there was room for a few additional items (like my new Collectors Edition Star Wars Lego Tie Fighter - which only just fit in my suit case).</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/90c73-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>In the early afternoon we all headed back to the hotel and met up before jumping into our transfer back to LAX.</p>

<p>We arrived fairly early to LAX - the freeway flowed fairly well - which allowed us to check in and pass through security fairly quickly.</p>

<p>We waited out time out in duty free shops and food outlets before boarding our Qantas flight back home.</p>

<p>The holiday was over - only 15hrs to go and we will be home - leaving behind the perfect Californian weather.</p>

<p>I wonder how long it will take for our tans to fade in the cooler Melbourne weather. I am looking forward to a great coffee however.</p>

<p>Once the dust settles, I will probably put together a bit of a retrospective of the trip to highlight our favourite parts - and any pictures which didn’t make it into the original posts.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e8418-img_0101.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f87fe-img_0116.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/d8e69-img_0121.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e0bc0-img_0126.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/14b18-img_0128.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1c9a7-img_9686.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/d8aa6-img_9761.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/86ee5-img_9765.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8ca6a-img_9776.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/363ac-img_9790.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/bef95-img_9798.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/66285-img_9982.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f31da-img_9985.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ace5f-img_9995.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>New York, New York</title>
	  <link>/new-york-new-york</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-16T11:12:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/new-york-new-york</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><strong>Updated 24-Aug-2015:</strong> As promised, more pictures have now been added to this post.</p>

<p>Sorry for the delay in getting this next blog post published. There was so much to see and do in New York and we were constantly on the go so by the time we got home to our apartment each night we were buggered - and the last thing I felt like doing was sitting down in front of the computer - so I have saved it all up and have put it together as one big blog post.</p>

<p>So buckle up, you’re in for a big read. Enjoy… We did.</p>

<h2 id="touchdown-nyc">Touchdown NYC</h2>

<p>We arrived into JFK airport on Sunday afternoon (9th August) and met our friend Carmen who had flown 20 odd hours from Melbourne to join us. We then waited around the arrivals hall for about the next hour waiting for our transfer shuttle to turn up - a little annoying to say the least. After two phone calls a big white Ford van eventually pulled up. We loaded our gear into the back and piled in with the other travellers. After swinging past another terminal for another pickup - and to make sure the van was packed to capacity - we finally left the airport.</p>

<p>The drive into Manhattan took about an hour. It’s a long and unglamorous drive through the outer boroughs of New York. We eventually made it to the Queensborough Bridge and the skyscrapers of Manhattan were now clearly visible.</p>

<p>The traffic was no better on Manhattan. We wound our way through the many streets - up, across, down, back - dropping travellers of at various hotels scattered through out the midtown area.</p>

<p>We finally arrived at our apartment block in Midtown and checked in. We were in a pretty good location on 49th street between 6th and 7th Ave - right next to the Broadway theatre district, Times Square, and The Rockefeller centre.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8c67b-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Rather tired after a long day of travel, we decided to keep dinner quick and simple - Pizza from the place next door.</p>

<h2 id="the-highline-and-chelsea-market">The Highline and Chelsea Market</h2>

<p>Monday morning we all woke up fresh and ready to go. We decided to get out and about walking to see as much as we could on foot - which ended up being quite a big day of walking.</p>

<p>From our apartment on 49th street we walked down 7th Ave through Times Square and then on through the fashion district to about 35th street before heading across town to 9th Ave to find the start of the <a href="http://www.thehighline.org">Highline</a>.</p>

<p>The Highline is an old train line that is elevated up above street level and has been transformed into a green space and walking trail.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/3e378-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The Highline weaves its way down to the <a href="http://www.chelseamarket.com">Chelsea Market</a> at 14th street - those of you who are good at math may have already determined that’s 35 block down and more than a few across town.</p>

<p>The walk down to Chelsea Market on the Highline was quite enjoyable and provides a very different perspective of the city from the elevated vantage point.</p>

<p>About halfway down the Highline we spotted a sign for a cafe - good time for a coffee break. We descend the stairs from the Highline back to street level and across the road found a trendy little cafe with amazing coffee and cakes - the guy working there even knew what a Babycino was so Archie was in luck.</p>

<p>The barista was a master at his trade… After travelling for so long without access to good coffee, what we encountered here was nothing but fantastic - the equal to any great cafe in Melbourne.</p>

<p>After our short stop, we headed back up to the Highline to continue our walk. It wasn’t long before we got to the Chelsea market - but before venturing back down to street level to enter the market we looked around the street traders that were setup on the Highline. Here we found my need food love - ice cream sandwiches.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2d59a-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>A small freezer cart was setup on the Highline from <a href="http://www.meltbakery.com">Melt Bakery</a> - the first people to bring ice cream sandwiches into New York - and for only $4 they are truly something. Coming in at variety of flavours, we went with the Morticia, a crispy chocolate biscuit enclosing a chocolate and rum infused ice cream - absolutely delicious.</p>

<p>After our ice cream sandwich indulgence, we headed down to street level and into the market.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/74080-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>It was now right on lunch time, and the market was very busy with tourists and locals alike. We wandered through the busy market place, in and out of stores exploring the wares on offer. Beautiful fresh fruit and veggies, fresh meats and seafood - pretty much anything you could want - as well as a few trinket shops for souvenirs.</p>

<p>After wandering through the hustle and bustle of the market for a while we ended up at the street foods area and decided it was time for lunch - on the menu, Mexican tacos from Los Tacos No.1, and Korean kimchi ramen noodle soup from Mok-Bok , all delicious.</p>

<p>After spending time at the market we headed back to the Highline and made the walk (some 40 odd blocks) back home for an afternoon rest.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/5c76f-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>In the evening we headed out again, on foot, toward the Flatiron district to a place we had been told was good - the <a href="https://www.shakeshack.com">Shake Shack</a> in Madison Square Park. The park was nicely lit-up in the early evening, and we found some seats before joining the queue to order our meals. The queue was long, but moved quickly.</p>

<p>Something I have noticed in New York is the efficiency with which they serve large numbers of people quickly. Be it a line for food, the theatre or other, what appears a long line often moves quick quickly.</p>

<p>We ordered burgers, fries and drinks and enjoyed them in the park - Archie love watching the squirrels running about in the nearby trees.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/5787a-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>It had been a long day for Archie and was now 9pm and well past his bed time, so Laura and I hailed a cab to get him back to the apartment and to bed. Jo and Carmen wandered their way back on foot and arrived home a little later (after some shopping on 5th Ave).</p>

<p>All up we had walked about 16km today - no wonder the feet and legs were a little tired.</p>

<h2 id="a-rainy-day">A Rainy Day</h2>

<p>We woke Tuesday morning to a rainy day - an overnight thunderstorm had been forecast and it didn’t disappoint. I had to make a mad early morning dash to the nearest supermarket for a resupply of milk, yoghurt, bananas and other breakfast essentials. Without a rain jacket I decided to brave it in one of my already worn stinky t-shirts and bathers - the t-shirt needed to be washed anyway and the bathers would dry quickly.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f4ccc-img_8839.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Unfortunately I was up and out a little too early - after a mad dash two blocks to the supermarket, I found it wasn’t open for another hour. So I hit up a local deli across the street and found everything I needed to get us through breakfast.</p>

<p>I was completely drenched by the time go back to the apartment - but the breakfast resupply mission had been accomplished.</p>

<p>We used the time during the morning to plan out some of the things we wanted to get out and see.</p>

<p>So what to do on a rainy day? Shopping is a great indoor activity… Macy’s it was then… You could spend a whole day in this place… If you were so inclined…</p>

<p>The rain eventually cleared and the sun had even come out a little by the afternoon - so we set out again in search for a place for dinner. We had heard of a nice steak place down on the East side near 2nd street, so we ventured out to find it.</p>

<p>After some wandering around we eventually found the place… However it was a little more up market than we were looking for - especially with a tired 18 month old in tow. Unfortunately we headed decided on a Plan B… So more wandering around.</p>

<p>We eventually found what looked to be a reasonable pub and headed in for a meal. It turned out to be one of the most expensive meals we had in New York - and by far the lowest in quality. We had obviously walked into the local tourist trap - but what can you do when you’re hungry and grizzly 18 month old needs some dinner.</p>

<p>Don’t get me wrong - I have eaten at worse places, and the meals were ok, but very expensive for what you got on reflection.</p>

<p>After dinner we wandered back home to the apartment to get the little man to bed.</p>

<h2 id="a-walk-in-the-park">A Walk In The Park</h2>

<p>Wednesday morning we decided to hit Central Park for the day. Central Park was about 10 blocks uptown from where we were staying - a fairly easy walk, but we decided to save our legs for the park and catch the subway instead.</p>

<p>The 7th Ave and 49th Street subway station was just on the corner of our street. We decided to buy weekly subway passes for $30 (plus $1 for the card) as these provided unlimited travel on the subway, and considering we were here for a few days would easily work out much cheaper than buying out tickets a ride-at-a-time.</p>

<p>We arrived at the south gate of Central Park and started our wandering. First stop was the Central Park Carousel - we couldn’t go past the carousel with out giving Archie a ride.</p>

<p>After our brief stop, we continued walking up through the sheep meadow and across to the Imagine Park - a memorial park for John Lennon.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/a5897-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We then continued our walk along the side of the lake and found the Friends fountain - where a few obligatory tourist snaps were taken.</p>

<p>By about lunchtime we had found our way (conveniently) to the Central Park Boat House Restaurant and Cafe - so decided to have lunch here.</p>

<p>After lunch we continued our walk through the park - this place is absolutely enormous. By early afternoon we had only walked about one third of the length of the park - mind you we were not in a rush, and it was a great escape from the hustle and bustle of the busy New York streets.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/61668-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>On our way back home we walked past the Central Park Zoo and were just in time to watch the clock tower go off - Archie loved the music and the animal statues dancing around the bottom of the clock.</p>

<p>All up, we had a big and enjoyable day in the park - even if we didn’t get to see all of it (we need to leave something for next time we visit!).</p>

<h2 id="world-trade-centre-memorial-wall-street-and-katzs-dinner">World Trade Centre Memorial, Wall Street and Katz’s Dinner</h2>

<p>We had a lot planned for Thursday. We caught the subway downtown and then started walking through some of the neighbourhoods on our way to the World Trade Centre memorial site.</p>

<p>On our way we happened to find (not by accident!) the Ghost Busters fire station - so some obligatory tourist photos here. We continued our walk downtown and were amazed by the number of skyscrapers in the area.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/7a58b-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Arriving at the World Trade Centre memorial site was quite amazing - you come out from behind towering buildings into what is now a big peaceful open space. It’s hard to believe there were two towering buildings standing on that site - and what is harder to believe is the destruction and chaos that would have been going on during the September 11 incident. It was quite an odd feeling walking into the area.</p>

<p>The memorial area has been done very nicely - tow large water fountains now reside in the place where the towers once stood. It is truly something to see.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/80c17-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>From the World Trade Centre site we continued our walk down through Wall Street - a fairly unexciting area of town if I am completely honest. As a tourist in New York, its something you need to come and see - but now I have seen it, I doubt I will have a need to come back.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/17dd8-img_9102.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We continued our walk down to the ferry terminal. Here Carmen and Jo jumped on a ferry across to Stanton Island, which Laura and I decided to head up to the Lower East side to visit <a href="http://katzsdelicatessen.com">Katz’s Deli</a> - famous for a number of reasons, but most people associate it with the “I’ll have what she’s having” scene from When Harry met Sally.</p>

<p>We jumped on the subway and then walked a few blocks to find the diner. Wow… talk about organised chaos. Luckily we arrived just outside the lunchtime peak - which meant we didn’t have to line up outside on the street to get in.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/649e7-img_9129.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Walking in a big guy hands you a ticket and says simply… “Don’t loose it. You need it to get out.” Initially it was all a bit too much to take in - Laura, Archie and I stood there amongst the crowd of people just looking around and processing what to do next… oh yeah… lunch - lets order some lunch.</p>

<p>To order food you approach a very long counter - the counter is divided into separate areas - depending on what you want. Given the number of people inside, we decided just to order something from where we were - a cheese steak sandwich and a cheeseburger (we were at the grill). When you order, you give you ticket to the guy behind the counter. He then makes some marks on the ticket and adds up the order price and writes it on the ticket. This happens every time you order something - and the total on your ticket gets updated.</p>

<p>While eating we were able to take sometime to observe the ‘process’ of how to get out of the deli. Basically your ticket is your way out. You have to pay to be let out. Loose your ticket and you are up for a minimum $50 - and probably a lot of grief from the big guys on the door.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fb531-img_9148.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The queue to get out was quite long - but every now and then one of the guys working the line would come down and ask if anyone had paid by credit card - if you paid by card you can just walk out… The line of for cash payment was huge.</p>

<p>Looking around we discovered the credit card payment area at the end of the food service counter - near the soft drinks (where else). Importantly there was no line - so off I went. All paid and straight out the door. As we left we handed over our two tickets (Laura’s and mine) and our credit card receipt.</p>

<p>“All good” the big guy on the door said… “But where’s his ticket. He’s gotta have a ticket” the guy said pointing to Archie. At this point I was confused. “Really?” I thought… “He can’t be serious.”</p>

<p>“But you only gave us two…” I started to say when the other big guy on the door started to laugh and said, “Did you see this guy… He was about to have a nervous breakdown…”</p>

<p>Oh they were joking… And at my expense… They are (way) bigger than me - so I guess we call that funny.</p>

<p>No harm done and I did see the funny side. I suspect it’s a common routine with the tourists.</p>

<p>After having more than our fill at Katz’s we caught the subway home before heading back out for dinner in the evening.</p>

<h2 id="friday">Friday</h2>

<p>Friday we set off to cross the bridge and see Williamsburg and Brooklyn. We encountered a bit of trouble on the subway with the ‘easy-way’ being shut down due to signal faults (apparently fairly common thing in the underground). So we replanned our route and headed off again.</p>

<p>We made it into Williamsburg and started walking around the neighbourhood - Williamsburg apparently has some trendy little streets and shops. The streets in and around the train station were pretty grim - not really much to write home about. To begin with we were starting to wonder if we had wasted our time - but slowly as we continued to walk deeper into the neighbourhood more and more hipsters started appearing, and then a trendy cafe or two, and then some shops… we had found what had been promised.</p>

<p>We grabbed a coffee in a trendy little cafe called Oslo before continuing on. Latte, Cold Brew Ice Coffee and a bite to eat - just what we needed.</p>

<p>At this point I had grown quite fond of Cold Brew Ice Coffee, and in the heat and humidity I could see the appeal over a hot coffee. You see a lot of New Yorkers drinking iced coffee rather than hot coffee.</p>

<p>Continuing into Williamsburg we found the main shopping strip which was full of trendy little cafes and shop - the girls were in and out of most shops all up and down the strip, while Archie and I people watched out on the curb - occasionally venturing into a shop now and then when something caught my intrigue.</p>

<p>We headed to Cafe De La Esquina for lunch - a Mexican styled diner. The food was great - spicy tacos, nachos, quesadilla, and the drinks were packed full of tequila.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1c74c-img_9214.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After lunch Laura and Carmen wanted to continue exploring the shops in Williamsburg, and I needed to get Archie home for a sleep - so Jo, Archie and I headed back to the train station.</p>

<p>Rather than heading straight back home we decided this was a good opportunity to walk across the Brooklyn Bridge - and take in the sights along the way.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2b505-img_9284.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The walk across the bridge was really enjoyable - but crowded. There are two lanes - one for pedestrians and one for bikes - make sure you stay in the correct lane as the bike riders get really cranky when the tourists wander across into their lane to grab a photo of the bridge or lower Manhattan.</p>

<p>The walk in itself took around 30 min - and it was quite warm in the early afternoon.</p>

<p>After our walk we made it back to the apartment and put Archie down for a snooze - and got a bit of relief from the heat in the air-conditioned room. The girls arrived home not much later and without too much damage done to the credit cards.</p>

<p>Laura and Carmen had discounted tickets to go and see Les Miserables on Broadway, and I managed to get myself a ticket to Penn &amp; Teller on Broadway.</p>

<p>We put Archie down for the night and Jo was kind enough to baby site while we went out to our shows. Carmen, Laura and I set out for a drink before the show. A few nights before Carmen and Laura had found a cool little Cuban bar in the theatre district, which they wanted to take me to.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/93c7a-img_9316.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><a href="http://victorscafe.com">Victors Cafe</a> was very cool and very Cuban. A dimly lit room, bar on one side table and chairs down the other and a small band playing Cuban music at the front - awesome. We ordered a round of drinks and enjoyed the music and atmosphere before parting ways to head off and see our shows.</p>

<p>Penn &amp; Teller were fantastic - I would really recommend anyone go and see them if they have the chance. Absolutely astounding and engaging - it was a great show. I am still dazzled and amazed by their performance.</p>

<p>After the show Penn &amp; Teller were getting photos and signing autographs for the fans out in the foyer of the theatre. The queue was massive - so while I would have liked to meet them, I decided against lining up.</p>

<p>I got a message from Laura who said they were just at intermission - apparently Les Miserables is a long show… So I decided to head up to the top of the Marriot hotel where the Penn &amp; Teller show had been held to their View Bar. The View Bar on level 64 has a rotating floor, which gives you a 360 degree view of the city.</p>

<p>A whiskey sour and two beers later I had gone the full circle and decided to head back down and meet up with the girls. As I got to the ground floor I noticed that Penn &amp; Teller were still there (an hour later). I also noticed there were only 3 people left in the queue… make that 4!</p>

<p>A few minutes later I was shaking hands with both Penn &amp; Teller, getting my photo taken and having the ticket and playbook signed - my day was made!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1a9ca-img_9363.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>I then met up with the girls and we headed home.</p>

<h2 id="carmens-birthday">Carmen’s Birthday</h2>

<p>Saturday was Carmen’s Birthday - we had spent some of our rare spare time in the days prior researching and planning what to do.</p>

<p>Carmen had a few recommended places that we thought we would checkout. First brunch on the lower east side near Soho.</p>

<p>We took the subway down to the lower east side and wandered through the funky back streets - cool shops and cafes everywhere.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/0e854-img_9480.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We arrived at our brunch destination - <a href="http://public-nyc.com">Public</a>. Public is a trendy little restaurant cafe that was awarded a Michelin Star in 2015, and offers awesome meals and drinks - including a Gin and Juice bar where you can mix your straight Gin with any number of the freshly prepared fruit juices and condiments (fresh fruit wedges, select herbs, etc).</p>

<p>We ordered a selection of meals from the brunch menu and enjoyed. I also topped out my brunch with a Bloody Mary (or two).</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/09a7d-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/c2b0c-img_9478.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f7308-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After brunch we continued our walk through the local streets. I found an old fashioned barber and decided to get myself a beard trim - its been growing wild for the past month or so and was starting to look a bit straggly. First a shaping trim with electric clippers followed by a close shave with an old fashioned cut-throat razor. 20 min later we were all cleaned up and ready to go - presentable once again (some might think at least).</p>

<p>The girls continued to wander through the streets in and our of all the shops - looking, admiring and occasionally purchasing.</p>

<p>I happened across a hat shop and thought that Archie and I looked pretty smart in flat caps - so we laid down our cash and bought them.</p>

<p>Given we were in the general area of <a href="http://www.meltbakery.com">Melt Bakery</a> we decided it was a good time to get another of their fantastic ice cream sandwiches. $4 later we were eating another of these delicious delights.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/63a46-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Given that Carmen and Jo hadn’t been with Laura and i when we visited <a href="http://katzsdelicatessen.com">Katz’s Deli</a> and that it was just around the corner - we decided to swing past there also on our way home. This time the deli was packed and there was a line down the sidewalk to get in - so we just peeked in through the window to get a view.</p>

<p>Laura and Carmen wanted to head back to the <a href="http://www.chelseamarket.com">Chelsea Market</a> for more shopping - so Jo and I headed back to the apartment to get Archie to bed. On our way back we existed the subway on 6th Ave about 2 blocks from home - what was gong on… the whole avenue was shut down and there were market stalls (for about 20 blocks) up and down the avenue. So we wandered for a while to checkout the stalls and street food.</p>

<p>Later that evening we set back out to the lower east side to a restaurant we had made reservations in for Carmen’s birthday dinner - <a href="http://beautyandessex.com">Beauty &amp; Essex</a>.</p>

<p>Beauty &amp; Essex is a beautiful and funky restaurant that is tucked in behind a pawn shop. You walk into the pawn shop off the street and through a big heavy door into an urban hideout that is dimly lit and nicely styled.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/69fa7-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Dinner was awesome - they suggest a tapas / share plates so we went with a selection of different options - all absolutely delicious.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/81d4d-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After dinner we headed back home to the apartment and then wandered over to the Rockefeller centre to book tickets to the Top of the Rock - the observation deck at the top of the building. Our session was at 9:50pm, so we went home and chilled out a bit before heading back.</p>

<p>The express elevator had us up to the 65th floor in no time at all. Outside the girls were ok - but I was packing it. The view of the city at night was awesome… as long as I wasn’t too close to the glass wall edge. Talk about vertigo… wow.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/d4c52-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We went up further to the top observation deck - which I actually found a bit easier as you could see the next level down.</p>

<p>Looking over the city on a hot balmy night was a great experience from the Top of the Rock.</p>

<h2 id="harlem-gospel">Harlem Gospel</h2>

<p>Earlier I the week we had booked ourselves tickets to see the Harlem Gospel Choir at BB Kings Blues Bar just off Broadway. It was a brunch show starting around 12.</p>

<p>Before heading out to the gospel show, we wandered down to Times Square to see if we could get Jo some tickets to a show - she was the only one of us yet to get to a Broadway show. She managed to get herself some discounted tickets to a matinee show of An American in Paris - which was on her ‘too see’ list.</p>

<p>We headed down to the BB King Blues Bar for lunch (brunch) and to see the gospel choir. We had decent seats in a booth to the left of the stage, and the music was great. Archie loved it - up and dancing to the classic gospel songs being belted out (quite well) by the choir.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/b1be6-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We left the choir show as soon as it finished and walked up to Times Square to get Jo to here matinée show.</p>

<p>We finished up the day with a stroll back through Central Park and up and down 5th Ave with some shopping.</p>

<p>Tomorrow (Monday) we are off to Los Angeles and Disneyland.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/c729d-img_8757.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/a5b5c-img_8817.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/32e3e-img_8760.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/9164f-img_8880.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/32652-img_8884.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/5e70b-img_8928.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/4e7f0-img_8944.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/b406c-img_8948.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/96027-img_8990.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/6cdaa-img_8691.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/de2d2-img_8693.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/6086c-img_8858.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e8aae-img_8870.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/bb614-img_8988.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fdb23-img_9014.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/3e89e-img_9018.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/a19bc-img_9041.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/9fafb-img_9072.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e4179-img_9137.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/0be8c-img_9150.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/998e0-img_9170.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/7f4a2-img_9181.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/5ebed-img_9188.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8526c-img_9192.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/13d65-img_9198.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e1f8e-img_9280.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/11bb0-img_9323.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/c86ff-img_9483.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/10ced-img_9484.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/94809-img_9485.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/5fa86-img_9504.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/6c476-img_9541.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e8af5-img_9542.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/226db-img_9544.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/d7c8f-img_9548.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/45d42-img_9549.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/cb3b7-img_9550.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/b5caf-img_9556.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/a08b2-img_9564.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1c9e7-img_9625.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/0fff3-img_9639.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/15070-img_9667.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/b9824-img_9669.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>London Gin Club in Soho</title>
	  <link>/london-gin-club-in-soho</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-09T01:09:27+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/london-gin-club-in-soho</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Last night was our final night in London. Laura and I left Archie with Mum and Jo and then headed out to Soho to find the London Gin Club - something Laura had kindly tracked down for me and thought it would be a great way to spend our last night in London.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f64df-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The club is in an old small pub - pretty casual and unpretentious - which was exactly what we were looking for.</p>

<p>We were greeted at the door and asked if we had a reservation - the place was packed.</p>

<p>“No… Sorry we don’t” we replied.</p>

<p>“Ok - let me see what we can do. Follow me” the waitress said.</p>

<p>We followed down a narrow spiral staircase into the Gin Cellar below and were seated at a small two seater table amongst other Gin drinkers.</p>

<p>The Gin menu was extensive. I settled on one of the tasting boards, while Laura had a Gin cocktail.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/de3aa-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The tasting board arrived - 4 vials of selected Gins and accompanying garnishes for each. Two large ice filled glasses then arrived - each Gin deserves its own fresh glass.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/6de7a-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The waitress then guided me through the tasting process - first pour the vial of Gin directly over the ice and then taste. Next add some of the premium tonic water that had been provided and taste. Finally add the paired garnish and taste again - then enjoy the rest of the drink. This process was repeated for each of the 4 Gins.</p>

<p>The night went quickly as we both enjoyed sitting in the balmy room down stairs sipping Gin. Later the waitress offered to move us upstairs where it was much cooler - so up we went - and enjoyed more Gin.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/7efb0-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/93cea-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Given we were flying he next day we wanted to avoid completely writing ourselves off. Not a good idea with an 18 month in tow - so after a few more drinks we called it a night and headed home - very happy with our evening out.</p>

<p>I would really recommend anyone who enjoys the odd Gin to look this place up next time they are in Soho - well worth it.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/51c44-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/035de-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>London and Bath</title>
	  <link>/london-and-bath</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-08T07:32:57+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/london-and-bath</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So we arrived into London on Thursday afternoon (6th August) from Paris after catching the EuroStar train across the channel.</p>

<p>We were expecting a little more from the EuroStar – the name builds up a certain expectation – and we were left wanting. It probably didn’t help that the air conditioning in our carriage was on the blink either – making for quite a warm journey indeed. Thankfully one of the staff members was extremely helpful and did everything he could to make our journey more comfortable. He initially started handing out bottles of water, but seeing the sweat pumping out of Archie he decided to try and move us. After a little exercise in seat logistics he eventually found us two sets of two seats – we wouldn’t all be sitting together, but at least we would all be a little more comfortable in an better air conditioned carriage. The journey would have been horrible without this – as Archie was really getting quite irritable in the heat.</p>

<p>The train journey from Paris to London was around 2 hours, with barley 20min of that spent in the channel tunnel. Emerging on the English side of the tunnel you immediately notice grey sky… We are definitely in England.</p>

<p>Coming from the dry and often dusty 34-36c daily temperatures of Paris, the lower 25-27c temperatures that were forecast for the next few days in London would be very welcome.</p>

<p>After arriving into our station we discover that there is a tube strike on today – meaning no trains running at all in the Underground. This was going to be interesting. The queue for taxi’s was long, and after getting in one, the roads were quite clogged. Thankfully we got a nice driver who got us to our new home as fast as he could – and 20 Pound later we had arrived.</p>

<p>Our new neighbourhood is a bit rough – I suspect the local riff-raff live directly across the road – and fully expect to be kept up to all hours with dogs barking and kids screaming. People seem to park their cars wherever they want and on whatever side of the road suit them.</p>

<p>I feel like walking across the road to that house and setting a few things straight before we get started – Kensington Palace… who do they think they are…</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/de664-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Well so it seems William and Kate are our neighbours – literally a misguided drop-punt would have your footy over their fence – I suspect Will would be a pretty good sport and kick it back however.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ee14b-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>So it appears we are not in a scrubby neighbourhood at all, but rather the Royal Borough of Kensington and Chelsea – the X-Trail would look rather ‘out-of-place’ here I can tell you. Most car bonnets seem to be emblazon with either a three-point-star, four joined hoops, a horse, a big B or R. I think you get my drift – not to many Toyota’s or Nissan’s.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/97d0f-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Most of the cars are pitch black, with drivers at the ready. Our street (Prince of Wales Terrace) seems to be some sort of a waiting bay – drivers come and sit in their expensive luxury cars, some get out and polish the duco back to an immaculate shine – all waiting for whoever they work for to call.</p>

<p>Anyway, Will and Kate have been pretty good neighbours so far – not a peep – I’m not even sure if they are at home. I was hoping Will might sneak across the road for a quite pint at the end of the day (once the kids are in bed) – but we haven’t seen him in the Goat (our closest pub).</p>

<p>On the last two evenings we have enjoyed having a picnic dinner in Kensington Gardens, right at the back of the Palace – Archie has become quite fond of the ducks at the big pond.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/0466a-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Yesterday (Friday), Laura, Jo, Archie and I all jumped on a regional train and headed for Bath. Mum had been there recently so she did her own thing in and around London for the day.</p>

<p>The trip up to Bath took around 2hrs, but the journey was well worth the wait – Bath is beautiful… and I think next time we might have to stay there for a few days.</p>

<p>Big old streets, white sandstone buildings, big blossoming gardens and all immaculately clean. We spent the whole day wandering around Bath – there is just so much to take in.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/47615-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Laura and Jo went to the Jane Austin house, while Archie and I went to check out the smallest pub in Bath and have a local pint. Small was right – no room to swing a cat, let along a pram. The pram got folded up and Archie and I sat on the remaining 2-seater table next to the bar (there were only 4 in total inside).</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/0e2bc-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After our (my) pint of local ale, we headed back to meet up with the girls and headed down to the river for some lunch.</p>

<p>We continued to drift around Bath for the remainder of the day before catching the train back to London in the late afternoon.</p>

<p>Today we set out reasonably early and caught the train to the Tower of London. Getting there early was a great plan – there was no queue and we went straight in. Laura and I missed the Tower of London last time we were here (2008), so had it on the list to see this time round. We spend a good hour or so wandering around the grounds, and Archie seemed to enjoy himself – entertaining the Beefeaters.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/3aee6-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Laura, Archie and I left Jo and Mum at the tower (not literally) – they had booked a show in the afternoon and we wanted to see a few more sights before heading home to get Archie off to bed for the afternoon.</p>

<p>We caught the train up to Westminster – Saturdays in London in summer are full on. Tourists everywhere. Coming out of Westminster station we could hardly move. I think it took as about 25 min to get from the station, across the road to see Big Ben, across to Westminster itself before heading back toward St. James Garden – it was packed.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/d4841-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The walk up through St. James garden was beautiful, and London turned on an incredible day for us to be out walking. We wandered up through the gardens to Buckingham Palace then continued on to Hyde Park Corner before diverting off to see Harrods.</p>

<p>After a walk through Harrods, and some lunch, we headed back to the train station and home.</p>

<p>We are not waiting for Jo and Mum to get home from their show so we can ‘change the guards’ and leave Archie with Mum and Jo for the evening while Laura and I head out for dinner and a few drinks – Soho is the plan… but we will see what eventuates.</p>

<p>Tomorrow we fly to New York!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/49a2f-img_8275.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8e890-img_8292.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/b30e8-img_8312.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/74d52-img_8317.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/9b774-img_8369.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/109cc-img_8442.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/3e849-img_845628129.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/aa85a-img_8456.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/c28f3-img_8482.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Exploring more of Paris</title>
	  <link>/exploring-more-of-paris</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-05T09:26:53+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/exploring-more-of-paris</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Today has been much hotter than yesterday - about 34c - and after the big day we had yesterday we decided to take it a little easier and just hit a few of the sights - with the Eiffel Tower the first on the list.</p>

<p>We headed off reasonably early from the apartment (while it was still cool) and headed across the river, past Notre Dame, and then onto the train station we thought would take us straight to the Eiffel Tower - unfortunately that part of the line (and the station) are closed for works… there go those plans and our early start.</p>

<p>After a brief chat with some helpful tourist information staff we were on our way again - however we ‘re-interpreted’ their instructions removing a change of train line and swapping it for a small walk - which ended up being quite pleasant.</p>

<p>It wasn’t long before the Eiffel Tower appeared from behind the many other tall buildings along the street - at least we were on track. A pleasant walk through some gardens brings us to the base of the tower - and its only 9:15am… We made it in pretty good time - only 20 busloads of people in front of us.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e24c6-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After a brief group conference at the base of the tower - and based on the size of the line for the elevator, we decided to walk up the stairs - how bad could 669 stairs be after all?</p>

<p>The thighs were burning for the first few flights - carrying an 18 month old added to the burn - but in the end we made it up to the first level.</p>

<p>A well-earned coffee while we looked out over Paris was that much more enjoyable having earned it by walking the stairs.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/5eeea-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Not being an enthusiast of heights (in fact I hate them), level one of the tower was actually pretty easy - except for the glass flooring in the centre - which Archie seemed to be attracted to.</p>

<p>The first time Archie ventured out onto the glass flooring he didn’t realise and then froze stiff once he looked down - but quickly realised he was ok and kept going. From then on it was a game - and I suspect he realised both mum and dad didn’t like going near it. He would quickly get himself just out of arms reach - just to taunt us I am sure.</p>

<p>We ventured up the next set of stairs and made it to level 2 - for an even better view of the city. A good number of photos later we made the journey back down the 669 stairs to the ground - and were glad for the early start, as the queues were much longer now.</p>

<p>From here our group went in two different directions. Mum and Jo jumped on one of the hop-on-hop-off buses to get a better look around the city while Laura, Maddie and I took Archie back to the apartment for a sleep - 2 minutes later he was asleep in the pram.</p>

<p>We arrived back at the apartment just as the little man was waking up - a good hour of sleep under his belt, and just in time for lunch. For lunch, we decided to check out the Falafel bar about 5 doors down from the apartment - it was awesome. For 6.50 Euro we got a falafels, salads, cooked eggplant, hummus and yoghurt in a nice fresh pocket bread - it was absolutely beautiful… and for desert… 2 doors up… we sampled decadent éclairs from <a href="http://leclairdegenie.com">L’Eclair de Genie</a> - which as the name suggests - were magical. We had Chocolate, Strawberry and Pistachio, and Salted Caramel.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/39845-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ab853-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After lunch we headed out to the Jardin du Tuileries. Laura and Maddie headed to the Museum at the end of the gardens; while Archie and I sat in a restaurant beer garden under the trees and watched the people flow by. It was here I discovered Hoegaarden Rosee (regular Hoegaarden wasn’t available) - it’s a lighter version of Hoegaarden (3%) that is mixed with a red berry juice. I wasn’t quite sure what to expect - but it was actually quite refreshing on a warm afternoon.</p>

<p>The girls got back from the museum and joined me (and Archie) for a few drinks at the restaurant in the park under the trees. It wasn’t long and the entire group was re-united when Mum and Jo came walking across the park and found us. From here we headed back home - we were done for the day.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/c65e9-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Back at the apartment we let Archie run around and play for a before heading out for dinner. The girls had found a nice secluded square a few streets down from where we were staying that was enclosed by 5 or 6 nice little restaurants. We sat down and ordered - tonight we had the dry sausage (two types of salami and prosciutto) as well as 3 types of cheese to start and then the girls all had a mixed grill, and I had the confit d’oie (goose) - which was delightful. It was my first time eating goose, and I will be back!</p>

<p>We are now all sitting around the little table in the apartment. The girls are playing cards, and eating gelato - while I punch out another blog post and sip away at the last of the limoncello we were still carrying with us from Tuscany.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ea179-img_8127.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2c3b8-img_8129.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/25c66-img_8142.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/af6ed-img_8222.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/887d6-img_8230.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fd1ca-img_8232.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>A big day in Paris</title>
	  <link>/a-big-day-in-paris</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-04T07:59:07+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/a-big-day-in-paris</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Today has been a very BIG day or us in and around Paris - and we are all knackered.</p>

<p>I’m sitting at the small kitchen table in our apartment - my back to the open window to catch the breeze. Today has been substantially cooler than any day we have encountered on our trip so far - about 28c max with most of the morning and afternoon around 18-25c - which made it actually quite pleasant for the amount of walking we ended up doing. It just wouldn’t have been possible on a hotter day.</p>

<p>After leaving the apartment at about 8:30am this morning we arrived back home at about 5:30pm - knackered and armed with groceries for a quick dinner. We suspect we have stretched Archie to his limit - he only had an hour sleep in the pram while we were out, and as we arrived home he was well and truly into his extremely tired and silly state.</p>

<p>The little man is down now and the house is peaceful - a very different situation only 30min ago - when he was fighting the need to sleep. But all is calm and the little guy is off with an early night - and I expect him to sleep through after the day we have had.</p>

<p>So… back to today…</p>

<p>The plan was to head to Versailles to see the palace and walk the gardens, an then try to get to Monet’s garden before coming back into Paris to fill out the rest of the afternoon with other sights. As it turned out things went about 50% right. It appears something went wrong in our planning and research - Monet’s garden is nowhere near Versailles (as we had thought it was). Oops. Unfortunately this meant mum wasn’t able to see one of the main things she had really come to Paris to see - but it’s a great excuse to come back.</p>

<p>Getting to Versailles was pretty simple on the Paris train system - with a short walk up to the Palace. We never wanted or expected to go inside the Palace - we just wanted to walk through the garden. When we arrived at the Palace (around 10am) the queue for the Palace tour was massive. There were almost as many people here as were in St. Peters square in Rome. It was crazy. Luckily the lines for the gardens were not nearly as long - quite small actually.</p>

<p>The gardens were what you would expect - immense, immaculate, and impressive. We wandered for hours.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/c4f94-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/4bf71-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After leaving the Palace we decided to head back into town where we had passed a produce market to pick up some lunch before continuing back to the train station to figure out how to get to Monet’s garden. All a little wiry from the morning walking we decided maybe it would be best to get a Taxi - we expected was only about 10km away.</p>

<p>After waiting (about 30min) for the Taxi drivers to come back to their cars from their lunch breaks, we asked to go to Monet’s garden. The Taxi driver looked at us oddly. Luckily we asked for an estimate of how much it would cost. $150 Euro came the reply.</p>

<p>Shit - something was wrong here. Either we are being ripped off or we have miscalculated. Either way we are not getting in the Taxi. We decided to ask the staff at the train station - who were very helpful and told us it was two trains and then a bus. Based on their directions we used the GPS on our phone and figured out we were about 60km away - the Taxi driver probably wasn’t trying to rip us off… It would probably cost $150 Euro to go that distance in a Taxi in Paris.</p>

<p>We abandoned our effort to see Monet’s garden at this point.</p>

<p>We decided to catch the train back into Paris and see some more of the sights. We got off at the Louvre station and walked around - only to discover the Louvre is closed on Tuesdays… another false start.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/d7c03-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>From the Louvre we walked up to the Champs Elysee, and then onto the Arch De Triumph - which was a fair walk in the late afternoon after having already spent much of the morning walking through Versailles.</p>

<p>All now a little wiry, we decided to catch the train back to Saint Paul station which is right near our apartment, grab some groceries and have dinner in tonight.</p>

<p>So, after a bottle of white wine and a few Hoegaarden beer the wiriness of the day has moved on to a more subtle comfortable tiredness.</p>

<p>I expect we will all sleep well tonight.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/94891-img_8041.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/15f4b-img_8045.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/4a5c8-img_8050.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8f48c-img_8053.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/33def-img_8058.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/3c1fa-img_8061.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/23cc8-img_8068.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ae758-img_8079.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f6040-img_8080.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/a586c-img_8110.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>On to Paris</title>
	  <link>/on-to-paris</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-03T09:37:59+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/on-to-paris</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>This morning we were up early - but not as early as previous travel days - 6:30am is manageable.</p>

<p>We have taxis booked to take us to the TGV train station so we can catch the TGV fast train to Paris - 1st class.</p>

<p>Aix-en-Provence has been great, and the 3 nights we have had here have been really relaxing - even Archie let us sleep in until 8am on on occasion, which was a welcome treat.</p>

<p>Our Taxi’s pull up to our apartment, and we divide into two groups to head for the TGV station - Laura, Archie and I in the BMW, the others in the Mercedes. The Taxi’s in France (at least in Aix) are significantly better than those back home in Melbourne.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/936f0-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The TVG ride was very pleasant. We were on the top deck which provided us we a slightly better view of the country side than earlier train rides where we had opted for the bottom deck on account of the numerous large and heavy suitcases. This time however, as our seats were pre-booked, we managed to lug the cases up the stairway to the top deck.</p>

<p>Being first on the train has advantages in being able to stow your bags with plenty of room. It also has disadvantages - as more people get on the train their bags pile on top of yours. Fortunately Paris is the end of the line - so there was no rush to dig through the pile of baggage to claim our bags and get of - we simply wait for everyone else to move out then simply follow.</p>

<p>Stepping off the train you immediately feel like you’re in Paris - something is just different. Walking out of the station confirms it. The typical Parisian architecture surrounds you. We have arrived in Paris.</p>

<p>We head for the Taxi rank and queue with everyone else. The Taxi rank attendant spots Laura pushing Archie in his pram and pulls us out of the line and arranges a special large Taxi for our group. There are definitely advantages to travelling with young children - I’m not sure we would get (or expect) this type of service back home in Australia - kid or no kid… you all line up and wait.</p>

<p>A brief taxi ride gets us to the reception office of the apartments where we will be staying. We drop our bags there, as the apartment is not quite available and head across the road for some lunch.</p>

<p>After lunch we head back to the reception office and go through the run-down of the apparent and the head off for the brief 500m walk around the corner and up the street to find where we will call home for the next 3 nights.</p>

<p>We arrive to a large solid door. Laura enters the code and we enter into a courtyard area. Here we wait to be met by one of the young ladies who manage the apartments. She takes us through a second security door and then up to the 3rd floor and shows us into the apartment.</p>

<p>There is a small elevator, which we will use for our bags. The elevator has a 2 person maximum - but I am confident it is almost impossible to exceed limit given the dimensions of the lift are only 1 meter deep by 50cm wide. The bags make it up safely.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fedce-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The apartment is old but refurbished and contains a number of modern amenities - but not air-conditioning and minimum overnight temperatures of around 21-22c… only a single fan. I am sure we will survive - the windows are all open and there is a nice breeze flowing through.</p>

<p>The streets around our apartment are beautiful and typically Parisian (could they be anything else in Paris?). There are cafes and little eateries scattered all about our neighbourhood. We are all looking forward to the next few days.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/74eda-img_7972.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>This evening we took a short walk from the apartment out onto the nearby Rue de Rivoli - a very main street which leads up toward the Louvre. We then detoured in toward the Seine river, and across to see Notre Dame.</p>

<p>We didn’t make it to the Lourve tonight - it was too hot to be out walking too far (34c), and it was already 6:30pm, so time to find some dinner for Archie (and the rest of us).</p>

<p>We headed back toward our apartment and settled into La Favourite - a local cafe which had been recommended to us. The meals and drinks were all very nice - including my Whiskey Sour.</p>

<p>Anyway - we have a biggish day planned for tomorrow. Up early to try and get it all done before it gets too hot - and then back to the apartment and shade (or a local bar) to wait out the heat of the day. No wonder the Parisians all leave Paris at this time of year - its stinking hot.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/d11ac-img_7939.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/d12d4-img_7967.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/bbbcf-img_7971.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/be486-img_7972.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f7b0c-img_7974.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ad36d-img_7977.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/c3ede-img_7979.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>In and around Aix-en-Provence</title>
	  <link>/in-and-around-aix-en-provence</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-01T21:56:57+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/in-and-around-aix-en-provence</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>It’s been good to be back in one place for a few days. It’s still warm, but a lot cooler than where we have been in Italy - which makes getting out during the day a lot more manageable - especially for Archie our 18-month-old.</p>

<p>Aix-en-Provence is a beautiful old city - two main grand carriage ways (streets) with many, many cobble stone lined streets leading off them in all directions. It’s very easy to get tangled - but also easy to get your way back to the main streets if you need to.</p>

<p>Yesterday started with Mum and I heading out to a local patisserie to by breakfast for everyone - fresh croissants (literally straight out of the oven), and a mixed assortment of other nice French pastries. Unfortunately the coffee we bought from the same place wasn’t exactly the great coffee experience we were looking for. Appears they may be either great at making pastries or great at making coffee - and few are great at both. We survived and the freshly made pastries were absolutely delicious.</p>

<p>The remainder of the day was spent basically exploring the city. We just wondered through the streets seeing what we could see. We hopped on the local street explorer shuttle and took the 45 min audio tour of the city, which helped to give us some of the history of the city as well as some general reference points for us to head back to.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/dfea2-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/608bd-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>In the late afternoon our wanderings lead us back to the Cours Mirabeau - where the markets were just being set up. Walking through the markets I couldn’t resist trying some of the freshly baked artisanal madeleines, and ended up buying one of each flavour (almond, citrus, orange, chocolate, and plain) us for afternoon tea - they were delicious, and possibly repeatable tomorrow afternoon.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ee443-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>In the late evening the temperature had cooled even further which made it very pleasant for an evening walk before dinner. We settled on what looked to be a nice little place in a side street a few streets back from the main streets. It was quieter and fortunately less smokers were here (actually none which is very rare in France).</p>

<p>Something about the French - they love smoking, and they love dogs. Dogs in restaurants. Dog in department stores. Dogs in the streets. Dogs at the airport. Dogs on the trains. Dogs everywhere. It seems that your dog literally has the same access privileges you do - so if you can go, so can the dog. Just makes me wonder how a department store like H&amp;M deal with a dog incident in women’s wear?</p>

<p>The restaurant we had selected for dinner was a good mix of traditional French food (which I was after), as well as more ‘recognisable’ foods - which fit the balance of our group well.</p>

<p>Our small group ordered a wide variety of dishes - Foie gras, roasted Camembert with Jamon and salad, chicken milanese and lasagne. I had the escargot and magret de canard (duck) done medium rare - so it was still a very blushing pink. It was all very delicious.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fd1c3-img_7887.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/d096f-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8e3f9-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>For desert I had a shot of black coffee and the 3 desert tasting plate which consisted of a small slice of lemon meringue tart, a small panacotta with red berry coulis and a small creme brulee - absolutely delicious.</p>

<p>Unfortunately we timed dinner a little late tonight. After a big day walking Archie didn’t last the distance - so Laura took him back to our apartment to put him to bed while we finished up. Dinner might need to be a little earlier tomorrow night.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/5c648-img_7779.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/332fc-img_7780.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/80963-img_7788.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/19d91-img_7806.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1bb05-img_7816.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/6d61f-img_7819.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/0ffe1-img_7829.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e7780-img_7834.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fc41b-img_7836.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/121ad-img_7839.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f0938-img_7843.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/00934-img_7885.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1b31b-img_7886.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/3c8ef-img_7889.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1ee58-img_7890.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/123d1-img_7891.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
