<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title></title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Preparing the Turkey - The lead up to our Istanbul trip</title>
	  <link>/blog//preparing-the-turkey-lead-up-to-istanbul-trip</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-05-06T05:44:04+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blog//preparing-the-turkey-lead-up-to-istanbul-trip</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So Laura and I will be heading off to Turkey in a few weeks.  While Laura has been to Turkey twice previously, this will put a tick in the “done” column on my travel bucket list.</p>

<p>The more people we talk to about Turkey, the better it sounds - I haven’t met anyone yet with a bad story, and actually all the stories I have heard sound fantastic.</p>

<p>It will be a reasonably whirlwind trip this time, about 11 days in total made up of 2 days in Kuala Lumpur on the way over, then the rest of our time in Turkey being mainly concentrated in Istanbul with an overnight trip to Gallipoli (to see the ANZAC war memorials and battle fields) and historic Troy.</p>

<p>So as our preparations continue, the excitement is building - and the clock is ticking until we leave.  While in Istanbul I am planning on taking a lot of photos - what is there not to like about a city so full of vibrant colours, culture and postcard like scenes such as  the Blue Mosque, the Grand Bazaar, the Spice Bazaar, and the Ayasofya.</p>

<p>With luck we will have internet access during our trip, so I will be able to sit back in the evenings enjoying a refreshing local beverage or two, possibly smoking on a Shisha Pipe, and reflect on the events of the day to distil the essence of our day into a blog post.</p>

<p>Until then… elveda  (goodbye in Turkish - according to Google translate at least :) )</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
