<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title></title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Working in Durban (RSA)</title>
	  <link>/blog//working-in-durban-rsa</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-09T07:42:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blog//working-in-durban-rsa</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So I have been in Durban for a few days now. Mostly work meetings with clients and not much down time to get out and see the place (im not hear for leisure!).</p>

<p>We have ventured out and visited a number of the local cafes to grab a meal here and there and to get out of the hotel - but for the most nothing beyond the walls of the compound we are staying in or the offices of our clients.</p>

<p>We did get out to the local shopping centre one evening to visit out client retail outlet and to get a better feel for their operation - but again - this was not a social visit.</p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/2aeb0-durban.png" alt="Durban - South Africa" /> Durban - South Africa</p>

<p>We are staying about 20km north of the Durban CBD itself - and the are is a mix of residential and industrial.</p>

<p>The weather has been quite nice - around 22c each day and down to about 12c over night.  Very pleasant compared to the brisk mornings we have had in Melbourne recently.</p>

<p>Today is actually a public holiday here in South Africa - so I am using the local down time to put together my notes  session earlier in the week and to plan and pre for the remainder of the week ahead.</p>

<p>Given the nice weather, I decided that today my office would be the back deck of the hotel where we are staying it - nice warm sunshine, a good view across the lake to the 18th hole of the local golf course (looks like a lovely day for a round!) and plenty of monkeys and mongoose to keep me company.</p>

<p>This afternoon, we took some time out to venture out and take a drive through Durban and the surrounding area on the way to an early dinner.</p>

<p>Durban downtown was a mix of new and old buildings - and I have the feeling some areas that you really don’t want to get too close to. We passed through quickly and headed back north to the beach suburb of Umhlanga - which was quite nice and obviously a more wealthy part of town.</p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/399fc-sunrisefrommyroomsunrisefrommyroom.jpg" alt="Sunrise from my room" /> Sunrise from my room</p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/13bfa-cheekymonkiescheekymonkies.jpg" alt="Cheeky Monkey @ Hotel" /> Cheeky Monkey @ Hotel</p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/f1f22-img.jpg" alt="Moses Mabhida Stadium in Durban" /> Moses Mabhida Stadium in Durban</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Headed to South Africa (for Work)</title>
	  <link>/blog//headed-to-south-africa-for-work</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-06T03:39:24+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blog//headed-to-south-africa-for-work</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Tonight I boarded a flight from Melbourne destined for Durban, South Africa - via Perth (on Virgin Australia) and Johannesburg (on South African Airlines).</p>

<p>This will be my first time on the African continent (only Antarctica left now!!) - and im not really sure what to expect. So many stories, some good and some bad.</p>

<p>This is a work trip however, and I am not anticipating much time for rest and relaxation or sight-seeing - but will endeavour to find some time to take a brief look around Durban one there, and possibly pick up a few gifts for the family back home.</p>

<p>So I now find myself now sitting in Perth airport with 3hrs+ to spare before my connecting flight to JoBerg. Perth airport a lot more modern than I expected, and probably one of the most modern I have been to.</p>

<p>Getting through immigration and across the border was a breeze - probably the best experience I have ever had. I suspect my swift transit through boarder control is aided by the electronic passport control used for outbound passengers. I am familiar with this when coming back into Melbourne after an international flight, but this is the first time I have seen it used for outbound passengers…</p>

<p>Let me tell you - it’s a bloody dream compared to the queues you normally face in Melbourne.</p>

<p>So with 3hrs+ to kill, I find myself - along with pretty much every one else bound for South Africa - at the bar in the international departures lounge.</p>

<p>Its a picture of tired people huddled in small groups around every chair and table in the small bar, with many others (myself included) spilling out into the common area. Many of us sucking in as much power as out devices will take ahead of the coming 11hr flight to JoBerg.</p>

<p>A few local drops (Rogers by Little Creatures being my personal favourite), are helping to reset the body clock into a slumber mode for the coming flight. With a full week of work ahead of me once I hit the ground in Durban, I need to try and adjust to the new time zone rapidly. I find beer helps ;)</p>

<p>So as I am quickly running out of words to type - and at the risk of rambling on… I guess this is good night.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
