<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Our last day in Greece</title>
	  <link>/our-last-day-in-greece</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-06-14T18:08:19+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/our-last-day-in-greece</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/greece.jpg" alt="" title="Greece" />]
Today is our last full day in Greece, as we fly out tomorrow at lunch time - meaning an early start to make sure we get to the airport on time.</p>

<p>Today was another reasonably relaxed and laid back day - we visited the National History Museum, and ate out for lunch in a lovely street side cafe adorned by fans and misting water to keep us cool.</p>

<p>Lunch started with a traditional glass of Ozzo (for me at least, Laura wasn’t too keen). We followed this with a seafood plater and a lamb souvlaki to share, both were fantastic.</p>

<p>The afternoon was then spent wandering the streets and the market - slowly heading back to the hotel.</p>

<p>We have spent a few hours relaxing in the hotel room, and are now gearing up to begin packing and getting ready for our departure tomorrow morning.</p>

<p>We are also attempting to plan ahead for some of our trip to come - the European and Italian guide books being flicked through rapidly trying to determine the ‘where, what, why, and when’ of the German and Italian stages of our journey - we want to try to be a little prepared from now on in.</p>

<p>We have also put up some more of our picture from our time here in Greece.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>A slow boat on the Aegean</title>
	  <link>/a-slow-boat-on-the-aegean</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-06-12T21:52:18+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/a-slow-boat-on-the-aegean</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/greece-cruise.jpg" alt="" title="Greece - Cruise" />
Today we headed out early to catch a cruise around three of the Greek islands closest to Athens.</p>

<p>Leaving port this morning at about 8.30am, the sun was up and had a fair sting in it - needless to say we took the opportunity to sit on the outer deck and soak up some of the fine rays.</p>

<p>The first thing that stuck us, once we had left the docks and headed out to sea, was the brilliant blue colour of the water - it was absolutely amazing. People have told us about the water over here, but its something you don’t really appreciate until you see it (and later swim in it :) .</p>

<p>The cruise was just what we both needed - some time to it and do nothing for a while!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/greek-island-swiming.jpg" alt="" title="Greek Island Swimming" />
We spent some time on each of the islands, and managed to fit a swim in on the last two - in that beautiful clear water.</p>

<p>Unfortunately Laura cut her foot while getting into the water at the second island - but we managed to find a local supermarket and add band aids and antiseptic spray to our current day pack first aid kit - oh and we patched her foot up in the process.</p>

<p>After a great day out, we have just been relating, and doing some washing in the hotel - and trying to plan what tomorrow will bring.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>A slow day in Athens</title>
	  <link>/a-slow-day-in-athens</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-06-11T20:34:59+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/a-slow-day-in-athens</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/athens.jpg" alt="" title="Athens" />
We got into Athens yesterday afternoon - great weather, we managed to escape the bad weather that has been forecast for the UK!</p>

<p>Yesterday basically involved getting from the airport to the hotel and checking in.</p>

<p>Today we decided to take an easy day - we have been on the go for so long you just need to recharge the batteries every now and then.</p>

<p>So a slow day involved heading into the Acropolis and seeing a number of the other sites that surround it. We then had a bite of lunch at a local cafe before heading back to the hotel for the afternoon - where we hav spent hours attempting to plan how to get from Finland to Germany without it costing a fortune. Unfortunately this is just not possible, so we booked the first flight out (which was the cheapest by far, but still relatively expensive :( ).</p>

<p>We have booked onto a 3 island tour for tomorrow - so this will be a long day, but we are looking forward to getting out and seeing some of the islands.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
