<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title></title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>The City of Angels</title>
	  <link>//the-city-of-angels</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-24T20:04:35+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//the-city-of-angels</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Earlier in the week (Monday 17th Aug) we left New York behind us (sad to leave but we have to move on), and flew across the country to Los Angeles.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/70530-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We weren’t actually staying in L.A. but just south in Anaheim as we planed to take Archie to Disneyland.</p>

<p>We arrived into our hotel in the early evening and checked in. We had a large suite on the top floor which was quite big compared to all the places we had stayed at on the trip - the only downside was, while being two rooms, it was actually only a single bed room with two queen sized beds - we got over that pretty quickly though.</p>

<p>After settling in for a bit we headed down to the restaurant in the hotel to get Archie fed. The restaurant wasn’t anything to write home about, but it provided a reasonable range of food and drinks and was adequate.</p>

<p>After dinner we booked our tickets to Disneyland and headed off to bed - tired after the long day and still operating on New York time.</p>

<h2 id="disneyland-park">Disneyland Park</h2>

<p>We woke early the next morning (Tuesday 18th Aug), as the plan was to get to the park at opening time (8am) to maximise our time inside.</p>

<p>We caught the local ART bus from the hotel ($5 for a day ticket) and in under 10 min we were pulling into the Disneyland bus hub.</p>

<p>Off the bus, we cleared security and then entered the park. Coincidentally it’s currently Disneyland’s 60th (Diamond) anniversary - and additional festivities were occurring to celebrate.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/f9a49-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We wandered through Disneyland main street and up toward the castle taking it all it.</p>

<p>Everything was perfect and clean - quite unbelievable considering the number of people they have through the gates on a daily basis.</p>

<p>We decided to take Archie on his first ride - the Snow White ride - it looked harmless enough. We waited in line and then boarded out 4-seater trolley car and off we went. About 10 seconds into the trip we quickly realised that the story of Snow White is actually quite dark - and this was well represented in the ride - very dark with lots of loud scary noises - witches and things jumping out at you… Archie was not a fan - in fact he was bloody terrified! Oops…</p>

<p>Luckily the ride wasn’t long - but the poor little guy was not very happy at the end of it. We took a breather and then decided to try our luck again - Pinocchio.</p>

<p>Oops… Another luck out… Much the same as Snow White, there is also a dark side to the Pinocchio story - which again was well emphasised in the ride. Archie was not a happy camper again!</p>

<p>Looking to recover from the past two terrifying experiences we had just submitted out son to - we saw the Dumbo ride - much like a carousel, but you can control the up and down motion - thankfully he loved this and all was good in the world once again.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/65915-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>From then on we selected Archie friendly rides - the animal train, Its A Small World, the Disneyland train, Whiney the Poo, etc.</p>

<p>We wandered our way through the park with no real plan. We manage to bump into Donald Duck, Mickey Mouse and Woody and snagged some happy snaps with these characters.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/a75a5-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/06c5d-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/bbf9b-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>By about 2pm we decided to head back to the hotel to put Archie down for a sleep. We all took some time out, either catching up on some sleep ourselves or having a dip in the pool.</p>

<p>We headed back to the park at about 4pm - just in time to watch the parade down Main Street - before continuing to explore the areas of the park we had yet to visit.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/39572-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/117b5-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Later in the evening we managed to find a ‘reasonable’ place to sit and watch the evening light show parade which was then followed by the fireworks show - a great end to a great (and very long) day.</p>

<p>At this time Archie was doing incredibly well to still be awake - so we headed home to hit the hay.</p>

<h2 id="the-outlets-at-orange">The Outlets at Orange</h2>

<p>Wednesday (19th Aug) we decided to head out shopping at the local Outlets in Orange. This turned out to be quite a big day out. While I don’t have anything else to compare it to - the outlets served out ‘needs’ well… We walked away all burdened down with bags containing new clothes, shoes and other bits and pieces. While the exchange rate isn’t as good as it was a few years ago - there were still some good bargains to be had - and we did!</p>

<h2 id="home-time">Home time</h2>

<p>Thursday (20th Aug) was our last day in Anaheim, and also the last day of our trip. We had a late flight back to Australia so didn’t need to be back to LAX until later in the evening - which meant we had pretty much a full day to do what we wanted.</p>

<p>Carmen decided to head out to do some more shopping and sightseeing on the ART buses. Laura, Jo, Archie and I decided to lay low and chill out at the hotel - although that lasted about an hour.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/79b67-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Laura and I decided to head out for a walk - and it was while walking that we discovered an alternate route to Disneyland… only 10 min walk away… oh well. We also discovered Downtown Disneyland - a restaurant and shopping precinct right next to the Disneyland Parks. Had we realised this was here we would likely have walked up each evening for a few drinks and dinner - there was a lot of choice, and while it was more expensive than the hotel (it is part of Disneyland after all), it would have provided a bit more atmosphere and variety. Oh-well… we know for next time.</p>

<p>Basically the remainder of our day ended up being spent at Disneyland Downtown. You would have thought that by now we would have had out fill of shopping… It appears there was room for a few additional items (like my new Collectors Edition Star Wars Lego Tie Fighter - which only just fit in my suit case).</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/90c73-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>In the early afternoon we all headed back to the hotel and met up before jumping into our transfer back to LAX.</p>

<p>We arrived fairly early to LAX - the freeway flowed fairly well - which allowed us to check in and pass through security fairly quickly.</p>

<p>We waited out time out in duty free shops and food outlets before boarding our Qantas flight back home.</p>

<p>The holiday was over - only 15hrs to go and we will be home - leaving behind the perfect Californian weather.</p>

<p>I wonder how long it will take for our tans to fade in the cooler Melbourne weather. I am looking forward to a great coffee however.</p>

<p>Once the dust settles, I will probably put together a bit of a retrospective of the trip to highlight our favourite parts - and any pictures which didn’t make it into the original posts.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/e8418-img_0101.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/f87fe-img_0116.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/d8e69-img_0121.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/e0bc0-img_0126.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/14b18-img_0128.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/1c9a7-img_9686.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/d8aa6-img_9761.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/86ee5-img_9765.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/8ca6a-img_9776.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/363ac-img_9790.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/bef95-img_9798.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/66285-img_9982.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/f31da-img_9985.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/ace5f-img_9995.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>On to Paris</title>
	  <link>//on-to-paris</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-03T09:37:59+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//on-to-paris</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>This morning we were up early - but not as early as previous travel days - 6:30am is manageable.</p>

<p>We have taxis booked to take us to the TGV train station so we can catch the TGV fast train to Paris - 1st class.</p>

<p>Aix-en-Provence has been great, and the 3 nights we have had here have been really relaxing - even Archie let us sleep in until 8am on on occasion, which was a welcome treat.</p>

<p>Our Taxi’s pull up to our apartment, and we divide into two groups to head for the TGV station - Laura, Archie and I in the BMW, the others in the Mercedes. The Taxi’s in France (at least in Aix) are significantly better than those back home in Melbourne.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/936f0-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The TVG ride was very pleasant. We were on the top deck which provided us we a slightly better view of the country side than earlier train rides where we had opted for the bottom deck on account of the numerous large and heavy suitcases. This time however, as our seats were pre-booked, we managed to lug the cases up the stairway to the top deck.</p>

<p>Being first on the train has advantages in being able to stow your bags with plenty of room. It also has disadvantages - as more people get on the train their bags pile on top of yours. Fortunately Paris is the end of the line - so there was no rush to dig through the pile of baggage to claim our bags and get of - we simply wait for everyone else to move out then simply follow.</p>

<p>Stepping off the train you immediately feel like you’re in Paris - something is just different. Walking out of the station confirms it. The typical Parisian architecture surrounds you. We have arrived in Paris.</p>

<p>We head for the Taxi rank and queue with everyone else. The Taxi rank attendant spots Laura pushing Archie in his pram and pulls us out of the line and arranges a special large Taxi for our group. There are definitely advantages to travelling with young children - I’m not sure we would get (or expect) this type of service back home in Australia - kid or no kid… you all line up and wait.</p>

<p>A brief taxi ride gets us to the reception office of the apartments where we will be staying. We drop our bags there, as the apartment is not quite available and head across the road for some lunch.</p>

<p>After lunch we head back to the reception office and go through the run-down of the apparent and the head off for the brief 500m walk around the corner and up the street to find where we will call home for the next 3 nights.</p>

<p>We arrive to a large solid door. Laura enters the code and we enter into a courtyard area. Here we wait to be met by one of the young ladies who manage the apartments. She takes us through a second security door and then up to the 3rd floor and shows us into the apartment.</p>

<p>There is a small elevator, which we will use for our bags. The elevator has a 2 person maximum - but I am confident it is almost impossible to exceed limit given the dimensions of the lift are only 1 meter deep by 50cm wide. The bags make it up safely.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/fedce-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The apartment is old but refurbished and contains a number of modern amenities - but not air-conditioning and minimum overnight temperatures of around 21-22c… only a single fan. I am sure we will survive - the windows are all open and there is a nice breeze flowing through.</p>

<p>The streets around our apartment are beautiful and typically Parisian (could they be anything else in Paris?). There are cafes and little eateries scattered all about our neighbourhood. We are all looking forward to the next few days.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/74eda-img_7972.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>This evening we took a short walk from the apartment out onto the nearby Rue de Rivoli - a very main street which leads up toward the Louvre. We then detoured in toward the Seine river, and across to see Notre Dame.</p>

<p>We didn’t make it to the Lourve tonight - it was too hot to be out walking too far (34c), and it was already 6:30pm, so time to find some dinner for Archie (and the rest of us).</p>

<p>We headed back toward our apartment and settled into La Favourite - a local cafe which had been recommended to us. The meals and drinks were all very nice - including my Whiskey Sour.</p>

<p>Anyway - we have a biggish day planned for tomorrow. Up early to try and get it all done before it gets too hot - and then back to the apartment and shade (or a local bar) to wait out the heat of the day. No wonder the Parisians all leave Paris at this time of year - its stinking hot.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/d11ac-img_7939.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/d12d4-img_7967.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/bbbcf-img_7971.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/be486-img_7972.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/f7b0c-img_7974.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/ad36d-img_7977.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/c3ede-img_7979.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Rome to Aix-en-Provence via Genoa (by train)</title>
	  <link>//1rome-to-aix-en-provence-via-genoa-by-train</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-30T04:02:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//1rome-to-aix-en-provence-via-genoa-by-train</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="back-in-rome">Back in Rome</h2>

<p>We arrived back into Rome on Wednesday evening (29th July) in reasonable time after having left San Lupo in the early afternoon - immediately after the main mass and precession of the statue of San Lupo through the streets.</p>

<p>It was good to have made it back to San Lupo again, although not a lot looks to have changed since our last visit in 2008 - but its beautiful during the festival with all the lights lining the streets at night.</p>

<p>The drive from San Lupo back to Rome was fairly straightforward and un-eventful - exactly how I like my drives in Italy to be. The auto strade makes for fairly good driving - especially on the tolled sections. It’s always the last 25-30min of navigation into your final destination that becomes stressful.</p>

<p>Once we got back to Rome, we unpacked and checked into our hotel. We decided it was best to return the rental cars that night instead of hanging onto them for the night and risking damage in the car park - or worse a 2.5hr wait to return the car like it took to pick it up.</p>

<p>The rental car return was as you would expect, and as we had hoped - simple and straightforward - and in under 20min we had returned both cars and were headed for the Fumancino taxi rank. We are now well acquainted with where the correct taxi rank is after our late and frustrating entry into Rome about a week and a bit ago.</p>

<p>After a brief walk we find the taxi rank with 2 taxi’s sitting waiting for us - what could be better? Well it could be better if one of the taxi drivers was actually interested in doing their job - but rather we find one taxi with 3 young people in it, 2 young ladies in the front and a young gentlemen in the back. The other taxi was empty.</p>

<p>Apparently the two young (and somewhat attractive) ladies in the front of the occupied taxi had gained the intrigue of the young male driver - and none of them were interested in us.</p>

<p>So we wait… We lean against the empty taxi making it very obvious that we would like to go somewhere… still nothing. Eventually a third taxi turns up with an older gentlemen who is willing to help us - however when he see’s two other taxi’s he decides to enquire why we didn’t get one of them. The problem became quickly obvious to him. A few rushed words of Italian and one of the girls jumps out of the front of her taxi and asks where we want to go.</p>

<p>The young guy in the back seat jumps out and we pile into the girls taxi and we are off - one of the young ladies at the wheel and her friend in the front passenger seat - apparently coming along for the ride.</p>

<p>The banter in the front seats was endless - and obviously very interesting based on the facial expressions of the friend. Her attention was fixated on what the driver had to say - and thanks to some interpretation from Albert (Laura’s dad) we were able to follow the general gist of the conversation.</p>

<p>Well… apparently the driver had just broken up with her boyfriend Francesco… and it went on… and on… and on…</p>

<p>We eventually got to the hotel and 20 Euro later we parted ways with the young ladies and left them to their less than interesting conversation about Francesco.</p>

<p>The rest of the evening was fairly laid back - and after dinner we all turned in for an early night as we wanted to check out of the hotel as early as possible to maximise our time in Rome in the morning.</p>

<h2 id="whirlwind-tour-of-rome">Whirlwind tour of Rome</h2>

<p>After an early breakfast the next morning we met our arranged shuttle van that was taking us, and our many bags, into Rome Termini train station. It was a long drive into Rome in the traffic, but we eventually made it. As it was still early we decided to check our bags in at the train station baggage holding area and head out for some brief sight seeing.</p>

<p>Given the limited time we had, we thought our whirlwind tour should hit some of the major attritions - St. Peters Basilica and the Spanish Steps - conveniently both located on train line ‘A’.</p>

<p>We got out to St. Peters Basilica in no time at all - and the air-conditioning in the Metro trains was a nice escape from the heat and humidity of the Roman streets.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/1fe0e-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Walking up and into St. Peter’s Basilica was quite a sight. It was only us, and 10,000 other people - quite tranquil really…</p>

<p>The line to get into the basilica wound its way right around the main piazza. We didn’t join the queue and were satisfied to observe from the outside and snap a few pics.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/900c1-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We then started to head back to the train and popped out at the Spanish Steps for a few pics before heading back to Rome Termini to pick up our bags and catch our train onto Genoa.</p>

<h2 id="train-to-genoa">Train to Genoa</h2>

<p>The train trip was great - although we managed to score the carriage with only partially working air conditioning - still it was better than none at all.</p>

<p>The train journey was relaxing. Put the mind in neutral for a while and enjoy the scenery passing by. A welcome change to being behind the steering wheel - and to be able to walk up to the bar carriage and have a few quite beers made it even better.</p>

<p>The train line follows the west coast of Italy - so there were a lot of brilliant views of the Mediterranean and the towns and cities along the way.</p>

<p>We arrived into Genoa in the early evening, and checked into our hotel, which was just a short walk across the piazza from the station. On this trip, Genoa is simply a stop over for us - so after a quick dinner (which was absolutely beautiful) we all headed off to bed to get up at 4:30am to catch our next train at 6am.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/bf391-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="the-early-train-to-aix-en-provence">The early train to Aix-en-Provence</h2>

<p>Friday morning we were all up early and met down stairs at 5:15am packed and ready to leave. We had arranged to check out the night before so just needed to drop our door keys with reception and leave. A short walk across the piazza got us back to the train station.</p>

<p>Today we had three trains to catch. The first was a regional train from Genoa (Italy) to Ventimiglia (Italy). The second was also a regional train from Ventimiglia (Italy) to Nice (France). The last was a fast TGV from Nice to our final destination Aix-en-Provence (France).</p>

<p>The challenges we had ahead were related to management of our baggage on and off the trains. Our bags at this point are quite heavy, and numerous. Getting on the first train was reasonably straight forward given the early hour - but as our journey moved on, more and more people joined the train making it more complicated to manage the placement of the bags.</p>

<p>The regional trains don’t stop for long at each station either - so we needed to be prepared - with out bags - ahead of time so we could quickly get everyone (and their bags) off before the train needed to move on.</p>

<p>The first stop was to be the most challenging with only 11 min to change trains - including locating the next train, its platform, and lugging all our bags down and back up the platform steps. Luckily we arrived in about 5 min ahead of schedule that gave us some more time. In the end, the change over was quite straightforward and we had plenty of time.</p>

<p>The next two legs of the journey were also straightforward - however we did notice an increased level of chaos at the French train stations as opposed to the Italian stations. Both Nice and the TGV station in Aix-en-Provence were packed and totally chaotic.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/481a6-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After arriving into the TGV station in Aix-en-Provence (about 20km out of the main city), we started looking for a taxi. Simply you would think - and in reality it was - unless you had two 30kg bags in tow plus a 10kg backpack, 4 other travellers and your 18-month-old son. Apparently we had arrived into platform 1. Taxis were at platform 3. This meant lugging bags up two flights of stairs onto the mezzanine level that allowed you to walk over the train line to platform 3. Most of the stations lifts were out of order. We found one that got us half way up, and reduced the stair climb by 50% - but we had to carry the bags the rest of the way.</p>

<p>The taxi was very easy - we needed two and in about 20min we arrived safely into Aix-en-Provence and at our accommodation - all very tired after the long day, and many stairs we had to carry bags up and down.</p>

<p>We did notice the much more comfortable temperature in Aix-en-Provence. Closer to 28c, and much cooler in the later evening when we ventured out for a walk up the nearby Cours Mir Abeau - a long and grand street which has night markets, cafes and restaurants all the way up. It made for a very nice and relaxed evening walk.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/3d18f-img_7660.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/ea41f-img_7661.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/7b590-img_7737.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/8ed35-img_7739.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/8a6c0-img_7759.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/99010-img_7768.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/e9736-img_7770.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/fe418-img_7772.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/db8db-img_7775.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/bf9aa-img_7778.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Dresden to Prague by train - the experience</title>
	  <link>//dresden-to-prague-by-train-the-experience</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-06-23T19:41:10+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//dresden-to-prague-by-train-the-experience</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/train-to-prauge.jpg" alt="" title="Train to Prague" />]
We laid awake this morning at about 4.50 am listening to the pouring rain, and claps of thunder didn’t put a positive spin on the day to come. After drifting back to sleep, we eventually go up and began to get ready for the day at about 6am - we had an early train to catch to Prague, at least the rain had stopped.</p>

<p>We got ourselves to the train station with plenty of time to spare for our 9am departure. As is our general experience with German public transport, the train pulled in exactly on time. We boarded and headed for our seats - we were in a 6 seater booth with only two other passengers.</p>

<p>The journey started - we were off to Prague, and the Czech republic, and whats more, the weather was great.</p>

<p>Leaving the station at 9.10am, the arrival time was just over 2 hours away. Traveling through some very beautiful country side made the journey very pleasurable - we basically followed the river from Dresden all the way.</p>

<p>About an hour into the journey we lost our cabin mates, and had the whole compartment to ourselves - this was great, we could stretch out and relax in the air conditioned comfort for the remainder of the trip.</p>

<p>As we drew closer to our destination we began to make some preparations - packing up our things so we could make a clean exit.</p>

<p>With only 30min until we reached Prague, we were now well over the Czech boarder and into Eastern Europe - it as at this point that the train slowed and pulled into a small station.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/broken-down-train-somewhere-in-eastern-eurpoe.jpg" alt="" title="Broken down train - somewhere in eastern Europe" />]
This station was, as we soon put together, an ‘un-scheduled’ stop. Apparently there was a major problem with the locomotive pulling our train and it had to be ‘swapped out’ for a new one before we could continue - or at least this is what we surmised after a conversation with the guard who could only speak Czech and German.</p>

<p>The locomotive was disconnected from the train - at which point so was our power - meaning no more air conditioning, or flushing toilets!</p>

<p>There is nothing quite like the feeling of being stranded on a broken train in Eastern Europe! Seeing our locomotive being towed away, not knowing when, or where the replacement would be coming from.</p>

<p>At this point there was a mass exodus from the train by ‘those in the know’, the locals, and anyone else who could successfully communicate with the guard.</p>

<p>The guard asked us our destination, to which we replied ‘Prague’. ‘You stay’ came the reply - it appears he know some English.</p>

<p>So we stayed… While everyone around us was getting off. It was an awkward feeling - do we get off an risk not catching another train, or do we stay and wait it out. We decided to take the guards advice and stay - after all, he should know whats best… shouldn’t he?</p>

<p>Meanwhile, with the lack of air conditioning, the temperature i the train started to raise to the point where it was no longer comfortable - and actually bloody hot. The guards had opened all the windows in the train that they could, but without movement it didn’t provide much relief.</p>

<p>At this point the tracks on either side of the train were strewn with passengers still making their way off the train - amongst the regularly scheduled trains that continued to fly past (another reason we though it best to remain on the train).</p>

<p>We quickly found that sitting in the open doorway of the train was the coolest - the cabins were becoming downright hot.</p>

<p>We sat on, in and around the train for the next 3.5 hours before excitement quickly spread through those that remained - a new locomotive was being connected to the train - it wouldn’t be long now!</p>

<p>With the news of this, many of those who left the train hoping to get another train quickly grabbed their bags, ventured back across the tracks and found their seats again on the train.</p>

<p>It was another 20 minutes before the train lurched to life - we were off again! Although it appeared that our carriage was still without power, and thus no air conditioning - the corridors again became a refuge, although at least the air was flowing now.</p>

<p>A short 30 minute ride had us in Prague, our final destination. We had been traveling for about 5 hours now - not bad for a journey that is meant to take just 2 hours.</p>

<p>We made it, and in one piece - and with a good story to tell. So tonight we are sitting in our hostel (actually an old two bedroom apartment) having dinner, and a few drinks relaxing - planning what we will do tomorrow.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
