<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>A slow boat on the Aegean</title>
	  <link>/a-slow-boat-on-the-aegean</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-06-13T07:52:18+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/a-slow-boat-on-the-aegean</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/greece-cruise.jpg" alt="" title="Greece - Cruise" />
Today we headed out early to catch a cruise around three of the Greek islands closest to Athens.</p>

<p>Leaving port this morning at about 8.30am, the sun was up and had a fair sting in it - needless to say we took the opportunity to sit on the outer deck and soak up some of the fine rays.</p>

<p>The first thing that stuck us, once we had left the docks and headed out to sea, was the brilliant blue colour of the water - it was absolutely amazing. People have told us about the water over here, but its something you don’t really appreciate until you see it (and later swim in it :) .</p>

<p>The cruise was just what we both needed - some time to it and do nothing for a while!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/greek-island-swiming.jpg" alt="" title="Greek Island Swimming" />
We spent some time on each of the islands, and managed to fit a swim in on the last two - in that beautiful clear water.</p>

<p>Unfortunately Laura cut her foot while getting into the water at the second island - but we managed to find a local supermarket and add band aids and antiseptic spray to our current day pack first aid kit - oh and we patched her foot up in the process.</p>

<p>After a great day out, we have just been relating, and doing some washing in the hotel - and trying to plan what tomorrow will bring.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
