<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Peru in review</title>
	  <link>//peru-in-review</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-05-22T22:42:01+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//peru-in-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Our time in Peru has come to an end - we are moving on and leaving behind some awesome memories and great new friends.</p>

<p>I thought it would be good to try and review and reflect on our time here in Peru, and ponder some of the highlights, and the lowlights of what we have seen (in some cases the highlights and lowlights run together).</p>

<p>Initially landing in Lima we were a little concerned about what we had got ourselves into - the airport, as with many big cities is surrounded by poorer districts. So our first impression of Peru was a wild taxi ride through the slum areas of Lima. We both looked at each other and said - ¨This is what we wanted!¨.</p>

<p>Where we stayed in Lima ended up not being so bad. Miraflores and Barranco were probably the nicer suburbs of Lima.</p>

<p>Our Intrepid travel group would have to be listed as a highlight, along with our leader Augusto. We made great friends with all in the group - and hope to catch up with many of them along the remainder of our trip, and also back in Australia when we return.</p>

<p>Pisco was probably the first lowlight (after the Hotel Espuranza in Lima). Unfortunately the place had been devastated by an earthquake months earlier, so there was really not much to do or see there. Lucky it was only a night. The place also smelt quite strongly of fish, a side affect of being a seaside community I guess.</p>

<p>The desert Oasis and Nazca were defiantly highlights. While the flight over the Nazca lines was a little scary, observing the lines from the air was defiantly worth every second in that small plane.</p>

<p>Another observation was that after Lima, the general quality of the Hotels improved. We were expecting Lima to be the best, and things to go down hill from there, however this was almost the opposite - the exceptions being the very small remote towns where we had on very basic hotels, but these even stacked up to the Lima accommodation in their own ways.</p>

<p>The overnight bus ride from Nazca to Arequipa was, while exciting and reasonably comfortable, probably a lowlight due to the scariness of driving at night through the Andes - feeling like the bus is going very fast around some of the sharp corners, or overtaking through corners was not a great experience, and it was better to be asleep so you just couldn’t´t see what was going on.</p>

<p>Arequipa was a lovely city, we all wished we had some more time there to explore. It was the first nice city we had been too. While it was at altitude (which had its way of affecting all of us), it was lovely.</p>

<p>On the topic of altitude, I think I could list this on my lowlights. I’m not certain if it was the altitude, the food, or the coca that made me ill, but I defiantly cannot face coca anymore.</p>

<p>Coca, Coca tea, and Coca lollies are meant to assist with the affects of altitude. So as the altitude increased, our consumption of coca products did as well. Initially it was great, but as I became ill, I think associated my sickness with the Coca (an I don´t doubt that in some small way it may have contributed). The mere smell of coca now makes me feel nauseous!</p>

<p>Seeing the Andes close up was defiantly a highlight - these mountains are so amazing, its an incredible experience.</p>

<p>The Colca Canyon was both a highlight and a lowlight for me. This is were I first became sick, putting a dull spin on everything I did. Shivay, the first small town we arrived to in the Colca Canyon was nice - simple but nice. I enjoyed the hot springs there as much as someone with an ill stomach and pounding head could.</p>

<p>Seeing condors flying in the canyon was defiantly on the highlight list. This was amazing. Personally we think that condors are rather ugly birds, but they defiantly make up for it when they are soaring through the canyon - very spectacular.</p>

<p>Sabyu, again is listed as both a highlight and a lowlight. For me, being ill while on the first home stay was difficult, and made it hard to enjoy the experience - although I did defiantly try. And in retrospect this home stay was nowhere near as well prepared or organized as our home stay near lake Titicaca.</p>

<p>Puno was alright. I would not list it as either a highlight or a lowlight - it was just part of the trip. Lake Titicaca, and the Uros islands was defiantly a highlight. This was amazing to see and experience. Our local guide ended up being a little bit of a dud and no one really liked him from our group. As I mentioned, the home stay near lake Titicaca was great. We all though that we could have probably done with only the one home stay - two home stays 1 day apart was a big ask especially for those of us who were not so well.</p>

<p>Cuzco was defiantly on the highlight list - we all loved the free time we had here, and the city it self was beautiful. We also found what I believe to be the best eatery in all of Peru - Peki´s. This was a tiny sandwich bar about 100m from our hotel in a narrow street on the way to the main square. We discovered this place early on and the news spread like wild fire through our group - great fresh sandwiches (actually toasted rolls), and burritos!. Pekis was a rest bite for us weary travelers from the continuous Peruvian food.</p>

<p>While i’m on the topic of food, I might as well cover off our favorites that we encountered on the way.</p>

<p>Yes we did try Guienne Pig - it was in small pieces and had been fried, so it was rather like eating small chicken wings. It wasn’t bad. Not really sure what it tasted like but I went back for seconds.</p>

<p>We also sampled Alpaca - although the Peruvian medium rare appears to be the same as all their other ways of cooking red meat - over done and a little tough. It was nice, but just tough.</p>

<p>Laura’s favorite, that she discovered early on was a dish called Lomo Saltado - basically a stir fry containing rice, beef strips, onion, red pepper, and chips.</p>

<p>Ceviche was another dish I attempted - raw fish prepared in vinegar and lemon juice. Not bad, but I only had it the once.</p>

<p>Out of everything on our time in Peru, Machu Picchu was what we were waiting to see - and we weren’t disappointed. It was fantastic - everything we had hoped it would be and more.</p>

<p>Our time in the Amazon was also brilliant - we both loved it and wished we had a little more time to spend there just to chill out and relax.</p>

<p>So all in all a fantastic trip that we will remember for ever.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Rum Night (Is there a theme forming?)</title>
	  <link>//rum-night-is-there-a-theme-forming</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-24T06:22:01+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//rum-night-is-there-a-theme-forming</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/peru-lima.jpg" alt="" title="Peru - Lima" />
Today we jumped onto a tour bus (Mira Tours) that took us for a 3 hour tour through Lima city and to the San Fransisco church and catacombs. This was a pretty cool tour. We got to see or first real glimpses of Lima city and the catacombs at the San Francisco church were pretty cool.</p>

<p>Getting back to the hostel tonight a lot of new people have checked in. In honor of their first night we have decided to have a few drinks to get to know each other. As we had a Pisco night the other night - and currently don’t have any expert Pisco Sour makers, or at least no one who could be bothered making it - we have decided to have a Rum &amp; Coke night.</p>

<p>One of the new arrivals, and myself volunteered to make the dash out after dark to the bottle shop to pick up the supplies required. This was only a 5 minute walk each way, but in that time we managed to be asked ‘Where you from mate?’ by at least two dodgy guys hanging about the street - this was followed by - ‘you want some smoke?, Where you from?’… Just the type of people we were hoping to avoid in our short trip up the street.</p>

<p>We got back in one peace, and with out too much hassle. The night so far has gone well. There are heaps of people in the hostel tonight. Mostly Americans, and funnily enough all from New York. These guys seem pretty cool.</p>

<p>We are looking forward to moving onto our Intrepid tour on Friday - will give us a chance to meet some new people, and start to really explore Peru.</p>

<p>We finalised our trip to Iguazu (Argentina) today. We hit the LAN Air office and booked our trip. We are only heading up there for one night, but the place looks great. We have booked into a hostel in Iguazu called the Hostel Inn - this place is a bloody resort, literally! They bought an old resort and turned it into a hostel. Its bloody huge and has a massive pool, etc. Everyone we have talked too said we will just want to stay because its so cheap and has everything - but one night will do us.</p>

<p>I do have heaps of pics from the tour we went on today, but as its late will not post them up until tomorrow sometime. Hopefully I will get a chance early, but with heaps of people here, the competition for the Internet is pretty fierce!</p>

<p>Love you all - Lucas &amp; Laura</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Pisco night</title>
	  <link>//pisco-night</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-22T04:30:14+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//pisco-night</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/peru-lima-sunset.jpg" alt="" title="Peru - Lima sunset" />
After the first good sleep we have had in the last week or so - I think the jet lag has finally left us - we got out and explored the local area a bit.</p>

<p>first off we caught one of the local buses into a neighbouring area called Mirafloures. This is almost like a small city in itself, with markets and shopping centers and parks.</p>

<p>Initially we were a little nervous about catching one of the local buses - 1 Soles - into town. We have seen many of these old, and often shabby looking mini buses ripping around the streets packed with locals. When your standing on the edge of the street seeing one of these tearing down the road towards you tooting its horn and a guy hanging out the window yelling the destinations, didn’t really evoke that ‘warm fuzzy feeling’.</p>

<p>Once on the bus however it was actually quite good - all considered. We got there reasonably quickly and with no problem - just goes to show, that sometimes you shouldn’t judge the book by its cover.</p>

<p>The weather over here is reasonably pleasant. Its cool in the morning, but by mid-afternoon it has been reasonably warm. The unfortunate thing about this time of the year is that the sea fog is setting in. Its thick and hangs about for most of the day. Apparently last week the skies were clear, and the fog has only just started to creep in over the last few days. In talking to people and reading about Lima, it appears that the fog is a normal part of life around here for about 8 months of the year - from about now through to December. Its unfortunate as the it really blocks what could be a beautiful view of the coast.</p>

<p>Tonight the skies had cleared a little. We sat at a bar and enjoyed a few of the local ales while watching the sun set over the Pacific - it was rather nice.</p>

<p>Back at the Hostel now, and sitting down with other backpackers. This hostel is great. There is a lot of other young people our age, and all with great stories. Its a great mix, we have some other Aussies, a Pom, an American, some Israel’s, and some Canadians - all great people.</p>

<p>Tonight were staying in and having a Pisco Sour night. Pisco, named after the city where the drink originated, is a distilled wine drink that that mix with lemon and ice to make Pisco sour - its also the national drink!</p>

<p>We sampled this in Chile, where it is also their national drink, however having read the customs forms on arrival to Peru, it appears that there may be some rivalry there - any beverages labeled ‘Pisco’ and not originating from Peru will be confiscated - something the duty free shops in Chile probably wouldn’t tell their customers.</p>

<p>So hopefully there wont be sore heads in the morning, but it looks like we should be in for a great night.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Touchdown in Lima</title>
	  <link>//touchdown-in-lima</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-21T01:45:02+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//touchdown-in-lima</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/peru-lima-dinner.jpg" alt="" title="Peru - Lima dinner" />
So we flew out of Santiago this morning (bright and early) into Lima, Peru.</p>

<p>I probably should have mentioned it earlier, but was only reminded about the fantastic view from the airplane window as you approach Santiago - floating through the clouds between the various snow capped mountains. It was an awesome experience. However, coming into Lima today topped it.</p>

<p>There was a lot of low clouds around Lima today and this made for a fantastic approach in the airplane, with the peaks of mountains breaking though into the clear air above the cloud. It was like a sea of white with little islands scattered around.</p>

<p>Once we landed in Lima, we negotiated immigration and customs - not quite the same experience you would get in Australia, quite simple, and not much too it, although it is Sunday!</p>

<p>We got into our arranged cab - a clapped out white Nissan wagon with big crack up through the windscreen - and headed for the Hostel (about a 30min ride) - what an experience… That imaginary third lane that exists somewhere between the lane that you expect to be in and the lane that the oncoming traffic is in was used by all, including our driver. Also in two lanes of one way traffic you can fit three cars! I think the lines on the road are more decorative than law.</p>

<p>This first experience made us a little nervous, but we arrived at our hostel in one piece.</p>

<p>We settled in and headed out to explore the neighbour hood. Our hostel is right on the cost, with the beach about a 5 min walk away. Unfortunately there is a heavy sea mist at the moment so visibility is minimal, but we expect a spectacular view and sunsets when it clears (hopefully in the next day or two).</p>

<p>The local neighbourhood has some nice places to get local food. We selected one about 2 min up the road and grabbed the Arroz con Mariscos (rice with seafood) - this was brilliant, very fresh and nice flavors.</p>

<p>Anyway, were back at the hostel now and will probably take it easy tonight and try to put together some idea of what we want to get up to here in Lima.</p>

<p>No photos yet - but hope to get some soon.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
