<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>A touch of Prague</title>
	  <link>//a-touch-of-prague</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-06-26T08:20:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//a-touch-of-prague</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/prauge.jpg" alt="" title="Prauge" />
Having arrived in Prague and settled in (after out exciting train ride) we decided to take a tour of Prague city – old, and new.</p>

<p>The tour started in the new Prague and worked its way through the streets to cross over into the old town. The old town is absolutely lovely – cobble stone streets that are easy to get lost in, and medieval buildings everywhere you look.</p>

<p>The tour was a mainly walking tour, although it also included a short boat ride up and down the river – giving a different perspective of the city.</p>

<p>Once off the boat we headed back into the city for the included traditional Czech lunch – this consisted of a very watery soup, a selection of either goulash (which Laura went with), or pork and sourcrout (which I went with). All mains were accompanied by 4 pieces of Czech dumpling – basically 4 slices of boiled bread. Desert was made up of something that resembled a donut (without a hole) covered in yogurt – overall rather bland, but I guess they make a tourist buck out of it.</p>

<p>After lunch we continued into the old city and to what are probably the highlights of Prague – Charles Bridge, and the Prague Castle. Both were amazing.</p>

<p>After the tour we slowly wandered home back over Charles Bridge (where we purchased a few souvenir photos), and finally home – to watch the Euro Cup quarter finals!</p>

<p>This pretty much wraps up our time in Prague – although we did have another day there, we dedicated this to planning for the rest of the trip, mainly the Italian leg (booking, etc is starting to get hard – and is becoming tedious).</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
