<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Peru in review</title>
	  <link>//peru-in-review</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-05-22T22:42:01+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//peru-in-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Our time in Peru has come to an end - we are moving on and leaving behind some awesome memories and great new friends.</p>

<p>I thought it would be good to try and review and reflect on our time here in Peru, and ponder some of the highlights, and the lowlights of what we have seen (in some cases the highlights and lowlights run together).</p>

<p>Initially landing in Lima we were a little concerned about what we had got ourselves into - the airport, as with many big cities is surrounded by poorer districts. So our first impression of Peru was a wild taxi ride through the slum areas of Lima. We both looked at each other and said - ¨This is what we wanted!¨.</p>

<p>Where we stayed in Lima ended up not being so bad. Miraflores and Barranco were probably the nicer suburbs of Lima.</p>

<p>Our Intrepid travel group would have to be listed as a highlight, along with our leader Augusto. We made great friends with all in the group - and hope to catch up with many of them along the remainder of our trip, and also back in Australia when we return.</p>

<p>Pisco was probably the first lowlight (after the Hotel Espuranza in Lima). Unfortunately the place had been devastated by an earthquake months earlier, so there was really not much to do or see there. Lucky it was only a night. The place also smelt quite strongly of fish, a side affect of being a seaside community I guess.</p>

<p>The desert Oasis and Nazca were defiantly highlights. While the flight over the Nazca lines was a little scary, observing the lines from the air was defiantly worth every second in that small plane.</p>

<p>Another observation was that after Lima, the general quality of the Hotels improved. We were expecting Lima to be the best, and things to go down hill from there, however this was almost the opposite - the exceptions being the very small remote towns where we had on very basic hotels, but these even stacked up to the Lima accommodation in their own ways.</p>

<p>The overnight bus ride from Nazca to Arequipa was, while exciting and reasonably comfortable, probably a lowlight due to the scariness of driving at night through the Andes - feeling like the bus is going very fast around some of the sharp corners, or overtaking through corners was not a great experience, and it was better to be asleep so you just couldn’t´t see what was going on.</p>

<p>Arequipa was a lovely city, we all wished we had some more time there to explore. It was the first nice city we had been too. While it was at altitude (which had its way of affecting all of us), it was lovely.</p>

<p>On the topic of altitude, I think I could list this on my lowlights. I’m not certain if it was the altitude, the food, or the coca that made me ill, but I defiantly cannot face coca anymore.</p>

<p>Coca, Coca tea, and Coca lollies are meant to assist with the affects of altitude. So as the altitude increased, our consumption of coca products did as well. Initially it was great, but as I became ill, I think associated my sickness with the Coca (an I don´t doubt that in some small way it may have contributed). The mere smell of coca now makes me feel nauseous!</p>

<p>Seeing the Andes close up was defiantly a highlight - these mountains are so amazing, its an incredible experience.</p>

<p>The Colca Canyon was both a highlight and a lowlight for me. This is were I first became sick, putting a dull spin on everything I did. Shivay, the first small town we arrived to in the Colca Canyon was nice - simple but nice. I enjoyed the hot springs there as much as someone with an ill stomach and pounding head could.</p>

<p>Seeing condors flying in the canyon was defiantly on the highlight list. This was amazing. Personally we think that condors are rather ugly birds, but they defiantly make up for it when they are soaring through the canyon - very spectacular.</p>

<p>Sabyu, again is listed as both a highlight and a lowlight. For me, being ill while on the first home stay was difficult, and made it hard to enjoy the experience - although I did defiantly try. And in retrospect this home stay was nowhere near as well prepared or organized as our home stay near lake Titicaca.</p>

<p>Puno was alright. I would not list it as either a highlight or a lowlight - it was just part of the trip. Lake Titicaca, and the Uros islands was defiantly a highlight. This was amazing to see and experience. Our local guide ended up being a little bit of a dud and no one really liked him from our group. As I mentioned, the home stay near lake Titicaca was great. We all though that we could have probably done with only the one home stay - two home stays 1 day apart was a big ask especially for those of us who were not so well.</p>

<p>Cuzco was defiantly on the highlight list - we all loved the free time we had here, and the city it self was beautiful. We also found what I believe to be the best eatery in all of Peru - Peki´s. This was a tiny sandwich bar about 100m from our hotel in a narrow street on the way to the main square. We discovered this place early on and the news spread like wild fire through our group - great fresh sandwiches (actually toasted rolls), and burritos!. Pekis was a rest bite for us weary travelers from the continuous Peruvian food.</p>

<p>While i’m on the topic of food, I might as well cover off our favorites that we encountered on the way.</p>

<p>Yes we did try Guienne Pig - it was in small pieces and had been fried, so it was rather like eating small chicken wings. It wasn’t bad. Not really sure what it tasted like but I went back for seconds.</p>

<p>We also sampled Alpaca - although the Peruvian medium rare appears to be the same as all their other ways of cooking red meat - over done and a little tough. It was nice, but just tough.</p>

<p>Laura’s favorite, that she discovered early on was a dish called Lomo Saltado - basically a stir fry containing rice, beef strips, onion, red pepper, and chips.</p>

<p>Ceviche was another dish I attempted - raw fish prepared in vinegar and lemon juice. Not bad, but I only had it the once.</p>

<p>Out of everything on our time in Peru, Machu Picchu was what we were waiting to see - and we weren’t disappointed. It was fantastic - everything we had hoped it would be and more.</p>

<p>Our time in the Amazon was also brilliant - we both loved it and wished we had a little more time to spend there just to chill out and relax.</p>

<p>So all in all a fantastic trip that we will remember for ever.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Peru here we come</title>
	  <link>//peru-here-we-come</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-29T03:58:53+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//peru-here-we-come</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/peru-nazca-lines.jpg" alt="" title="Peru - Nazca Lines" />
It’s been a few days since we have had a chance to grab a seat in front of a computer (probably a good thing), so I will try to fill you all in on what we have been up to in the last few days.</p>

<p>We started our Intrepid tour of Peru on Friday. We all met in a small hotel in Miraflores (a suburb of Lima). There are 13 of us in the group, and we all get along really well. The group is a really well balanced mix of people and ages - mostly Australians, and some Poms.</p>

<p>The first day comprised a short walking tour of Lima, which took us to the San Francisco church and the catacombs underneath. Laura and I had already seen the catacombs during our week in Lima, so passed and instead decided to check out the church, which was closed when we visited the first time.</p>

<p>One thing we noticed immediately (on attempting to make our local payment), was they hate, and will bluntly reject any US notes that are even slightly damaged. This is a real pain, as the banks and ATM’s dish them out freely. The result was we got stuck with a couple of spare US notes that are very difficult to pass off to anyone. Oh well… lessons learned. I’m sure the europeans won’t be as picky.</p>

<p>Anyway, we left Lima in the afternoon and headed south for Pisco. Pisco was recently (back in August) devastated by an earthquake, and around 600 people were killed. Unfortunately the city is still in ruin so there is not too much to take in here (from a tourists perspective).</p>

<p>Pisco is the city that gives its name to Peru’s national drink, the Pisco Sour (as you may have read, we have enjoyed a few of these). Pisco is made out of grapes grown in the Pisco region. Its essentially a distilled wine, and varies in potency from regular wine at about 12% to a very highly distilled alcohol at about 60-70%. Pisco sour is made with a form of Pisco that sits somewhere in the middle, and is mixed with lemon or lime juice, sugar syrup, and egg white, which is all blended together. The egg white gives it a frothy head. Its then topped with wither bitters, or more commonly cinnamon. Its rather refreshing on a warm day. Traditionally its intended as an aperitif, but is commonly drunk at any time (by us at least :))</p>

<p>From Pisco, we took a short bus ride down to the coast - passing a number of fish processing factories on the way (pin pointing the source of the strong fishy smell in the area). From a small coastal port we took a fast boat out to the Paracas islands. These are a set of small islands just off the coast which host heaps of bird life and sea lion colonies. On the larger of the islands was a huge candelabra figure etched into the side of the mountain face - this was pretty impressive to see, and gave us a taste for what we could expect later in Nazca.</p>

<p>From the coastal port we began heading inland for Nazca. The landscape in this area is essentially barron desert. Its very arid, and not many features except the odd tree, and mountains on either side.</p>

<p>We stopped in at a desert oasis on the way to Nazca for lunch. This was littery exactly how the cartoons picture them - it’s the middle of the desert, sand dunes for miles, then as you come over the top of one, you can see the other side, and instead of more sand, there is a small lake and some lush greenery with a hotel and some shops surrounding the lake.</p>

<p>We had the option to sand board here, but considering the head, and my previous experiences with large sand dunes I decided against it, considering we had a further 3 hours to Nazca. We didn’t really feel like sitting on the bus full of sand. It would have stuck to everything considering how hot it was.</p>

<p>So we settled for a light lunch, a few crevasses (beers), and a walk round the oasis instead.</p>

<p>We headed off to Nazca after lunch. Again more desert that was only broken up as we approached Nazca, and had to start going through some small mountains. This was pretty exciting after a few hours of desert. Coming into Nazca, we stopped at a roadside tower on the Nazca plains to observe some of the famous Nazca lines. Not a great view but gave us a taste.</p>

<p>Our hotel in Nazca was pretty nice - air con, pool, etc. It’s actually been the best so far.</p>

<p>Last night we headed out for a meal and a local Peruvian show, which featured some native dancing, as well as an Andean band, which was pretty great. I had the Ceveche - a Peruvian specialty of raw fish marinated in lemon/lime juice and vinegar (which sort of cooks the fish on the outside, and presumably kills any nasties?). It was quite nice - would defiantly have it again.</p>

<p>Today we took a (very small) plane (3 passengers) to fly out over the Nazca plains to see the lines from the air. This was great, a little nerve racking at times, and nauseating, but defiantly worth it. Just as we were about to head back, the lady in the front (also from our tour group) popped… projectile vomiting all over the side window and panel in front of her. The plane was defiantly too small for this. The smell nearly set us off in the back seat, but we managed to hold it together and got back in one piece - although our stomachs were a little stirred up.</p>

<p>Tonight were waiting for the overnight bus (about 11pm) to pick us up and take us to Araquipa. This is where we will start getting into the altitude, so light meals tonight and no grog…</p>

<p>Anyway, looking forward to whats to come.</p>

<p>Love you all</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
