<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>The Sound of Salzburg</title>
	  <link>//the-sound-of-salburg</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-07-01T10:00:34+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//the-sound-of-salburg</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/saltzberg-at-night.jpg" alt="" title="Salzburg at night" />
We pick-up here were our last post left off. We have arrived in Salzburg – and its the night of the Euro Cup 2008 final, Germany -v- Spain. With Austria being the hosts, we were in for a big night (it had already been a long day… whats a few more hours).</p>

<p>We headed out to the old city, about a 15min walk from where we were staying. A large Fan Zone had been set up in the city’s main square with two huge screens, a stage, and of course heaps of beer tents.</p>

<p>We decided to relax a little (after our huge day) before venturing back to the Fan Zone. We found a beer garden not far away from the center of town that was showing the game on plasma screens, grabbed a table and some dinner and relaxed with a few local Austrian beers for a few hours.</p>

<p>After half time we decided to head up to the main square and join in the other fans to watch the last half of the game. At this stage Spain was up 1-0 over Germany.</p>

<p>The main square was packed to capacity – there were people everywhere. The game was eventually won by Spain – to the delight of many in attendance. The crowd erupted in cheering and chanting. It has been over 20 years since Spain has won a title at the European level – so this was a big thing.</p>

<p>We vacated the square and began heading home – along with the majority of the German supporters.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/saltzberg-sound-of-music-tour-1.jpg" alt="" title="Salzberg - Sound of Music Tour 1" />
We were up early again the following morning as we had booked onto the 9am Sound of Music tour around Salzburg. The tour took us through much of Salzburg, and showed us many of the places that were used in the filming of the movie – Laura was in her element. The tour also took us out of town to the lakes district, and to some absolutely beautiful scenery. We had a short stop over in a small town with just enough time to have a coffee and sample some apple strudel, which was divine, before getting back on the bus and heading back to Salzburg to complete the tour.</p>

<p>We spent the afternoon exploring the Salzburg castle/fortress, which is the predominant feature in Salzburg, and can be seen from nearly anywhere in the city.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/saltzberg-beer-garden.jpg" alt="" title="Salzburg - Beer Garden" />
After this we headed to another beer garden – this one was run by monks, and was established in 1621. They had a pretty impressive setup. Walking in from the street the place doesn’t look like much – then you wander down some passage ways, and steps and come to a corridor with local food stalls. Further on you emerge into a massive beer garden.</p>

<p>We relaxed in the beer garden for the afternoon and sampled some of the monks beer, which is drawn straight from the barrel, and was, as with most beer over here, great.</p>

<p>Later we headed home to get some rest, as we were off early in the morning to Venice, Italy! The start of the Italian leg of our journey.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Madrid to Barcelona</title>
	  <link>//madrid-to-barcelona</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-05-26T16:54:40+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//madrid-to-barcelona</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So after a reasonably restful sleep overnight we got into exploring Madrid early – eager to use the remainder of the time available on our 24hr Madrid Vision card (we had until about 2pm) – first on the list was a coffee at one of the many local cafe’s, then onto the Royal Palace for a tour.</p>

<p>The Royal Palace was spectacular. We we allowed access to about 50 of the 2,800 rooms in the palace. We started in the royal armory where armor that had been worn by or gifted to the kings of Spain was housed. This was a very interesting exhibition – you could even see how some of the kings had grown around the waist over time by the re-sizing of their armor ;).</p>

<p>The palace has many tapestries on display as well as many various gold and silver wares. The tour took us about 2.5hrs in total, but was well worth seeing how the other side live (or at least how they used to).</p>

<p>The rest of the day was spent simply wandering the streets of Madrid – just getting lost so we could find new and interesting areas we hadn’t ventured to yet.</p>

<p>A recommendation to anyone going to Madrid who is traveling on a budget – get lunch at the Museo de Jamon (Museum of Ham) near the Plaza de Mayor. For 2 Euro’s you get a basic Ham (like prosciutto) roll, an apple or orange, and a can of drink, be it coke, beer, etc! Its the best value meal we have found in Spain yet.</p>

<p>Later in the afternoon we decided to fill in some time by attempting a dry run on the metro (subway) to the bus station where we had to get the overnight bus to Barcelona. As with our current experience of the public transport system in Madrid, this was very simple and quick. we got to the main bus station within about 15 minutes – however decided not to exit the train station to pass into the bus station as we would have to buy a return ticket if we exited – so we decided to head back to the hotel and wait around until 10.30pm to take off for the bus station (our bus was at 12:30 am).</p>

<p>10.30 came, and we navigated the metro system with ease, although after paying for a ticket to enter, we simply walked through an open gate and didn’t need to validate our ticket. Arriving at the bus station we queued for about 10min (with heavy packs on) just to be told we were at the wrong station! So much for a dry run.</p>

<p>Quickly trying to communicate with the Spanish only speaking clerk, we determined the metro station and line we need to be at – lucky we still had a valid ticket – some would call it fate!</p>

<p>Another 15min had us at the bus station we need to be at, and with an hour to spare.</p>

<p>We jumped on the night bus to Barcelona, and were surprised by the low number of fellow travelers. While we tried to sleep most of the way, we felt rather tired when we arrived at 8am.</p>

<p>We managed to get to our hostel using the Barcelona metro system – not quite as together as Madrid, but still reasonably good.</p>

<p>Unfortunately today has been raining on and off in Barcelona, so we tried to stick to inside activities, such as museums, churches, and pubs!</p>

<p>We will see what tomorrow brings, but we don’t expect the weather to improve greatly. Preparation for the UK I guess – the good weather couldn’t last for every.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Madrid - Spain</title>
	  <link>//madrid-spain</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-05-23T23:13:20+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//madrid-spain</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>We have now left South America behind us, and moved onto the European leg of our trip.</p>

<p>Our flight from Buenos Aires to Madrid was with the Spanish Iberia airline - an 11 hour flight that was probably our worst yet… lucky us to get the worst one on a long flight.</p>

<p>Based on our experience I would try to avoid flying with them again. The entertainment system was communal, no personal entertainment system that you seem to get on most other flights these days. The hostesses were not really interested, and the air conditioning was set to about 35c… even Laura was hot!</p>

<p>Anyway, we got here and easily navigated our way from the air port to the hostel. The pubic transport over here i great… makes Melbourne’s look like something from Peru!</p>

<p>The train terminal is in the airport. This then connects you to the main city lines. We did have to catch about 3 connecting trains, but the wait was a maximum of about 3 minutes at the most.</p>

<p>All the trains are underground as well, so we finally emerged about 100m from the hostel.</p>

<p>Initially we were both ready to go… we wanted to get out and hit the city as it was still pretty early (8am local time). This was fine for about the first half an hour until I sat in a big comfy chair in the local Starbucks and drifted off.</p>

<p>I think I had about an hour - and a cold coffee to boot - but I started feeling a little off as well (I think mainly due to tiredness). Anyway we continued on and did some basic exploring of the surrounding area before heading back to the hostel for some major siesta.</p>

<p>We eventually got going again at about 5pm - we though it was late, but this was pretty early on Madrid time. So we headed out once again, and were reasonably surprised at how light it still was - it seemed like 2 or 3 i the afternoon, but was approaching 6.</p>

<p>We continued exploring on foot, and eventually settled for a cafe in one of the main squares at about 9pm for dinner. Ordering a small plate of calamari and chips, we were a little surprised to receive a plate of calamari and  plate of chips from a packet (i.e. crisps)! Anyway we sorted it out and eventually got something closer to the mark.</p>

<p>Today, even though it was miserable and raining, we jumped on the local tourist bus and ventured around the city. our first stop was the Real Madrid stadium for a tour. This was pretty cool (even for someone not into soccer like myself).</p>

<p>Next we made a stop at the city cable car ride - you would think we would learn after out last experience, although this one turned out to be quite pleasant - European engineering at its finest, there was hardly a bump.<br />
With the rain setting in late this afternoon, we stopped off at the supermarket and bought some supplies for a good home cooked dinner - local salami, camembert, bread, wine and pasta - perfect for a night just like tonight.</p>

<p>So we are heading off to bed now. We catch an overnight bus to Barcelona tomorrow night, so will probably head out to see a few more sights tomorrow.</p>

<p>Hope to have pictures up in a new album soon.</p>

<p>Love Lucas &amp; Laura</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
