<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Our last day in Santiago</title>
	  <link>/our-last-day-in-santiago</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-20T00:57:33+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/our-last-day-in-santiago</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/chile-santiago-markets.jpg" alt="" title="Chile - Santiago Markets" />
So today is our last day in Santiago. We started out by heading to the post office to send off a few post cards to family back home. Right next to the post office in the Plaza de Armas is a huge old church where we went to mass.</p>

<p>From there we went onto the Marceto Centro (the central market) which is basically a cut down version of the Victoria Market in Melbourne.</p>

<p>Next onto the Museum of Pre-Colombian times. This was great - a lot of history and really interesting artifacts to view from the Aztec, Mays &amp; Inca times.</p>

<p>Tonight were off for our last meal in Santiago, and a few drinks before an early flight to Lima, Peru tomorrow morning.</p>

<p>Again, there are a few more pictures up in our Santiago gallery - enjoy :)</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>In and around Santiago</title>
	  <link>/in-and-around-santiago</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-19T02:39:35+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/in-and-around-santiago</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/chile-dusk-in-santiago.jpg" alt="" title="Chile - Dusk in Santiago" />
So we have settled our selves in and found our feet here in Santiago. We have managed to explore most of what the city has to offer (we think).</p>

<p>We have visited many of the beautiful old buildings (Churches, etc), as well as the various parks and gardens that are around the city.</p>

<p>For us, the big let down of Santiago is the smog! Its bad. No doubt there is worse, but it blocks what is one of Santiago’s best assets - the mountains. Santiago is surrounded by mountains. On one side the Andes, and on the other the costal mountain range. But unfortunately, you can barely make them out through the smog, and there is no hope for a good photo :(.</p>

<p>Yesterday we jumped on a tour out to Valparaso and Viña del Mar - two lovely cities basically on top of each other, about 2 hours bus ride to the north west of Santiago. These two cities are built on the Pacific Ocean, in fact some of Valparaso has actually been re-claimed from the ocean.</p>

<p>Today we toured the remainder of Santiago. Jumping on a Touris Tek double decker bus which takes you around the city, allowing you to get on/off at any of the 11 set stops. This worked pretty well for us, as we were able to skip the areas we had already seen and concentrate on the areas we hadn’t.</p>

<p>The main high light - and we do mean high - was the aerial cable car ride through the park at Cerro San Cristobal. This was 2km of hell for us, neither of us being great with hights - but provided a spectacular view of the smog covered mountains ;). The views were really spectacular.</p>

<p>Once at the top we visited the shrine to San Cristobal, and the small chapel as well. Getting down the mountain was less stressful. The Finacula (a cable tram up the side of the hill) was great.</p>

<p>So after a couple of long days we are pretty buggered, and hoping to get a good night sleep. Both of us have struggled a little with jet lag - sudden burst of being awake at 1am, 4am, etc… Trying to force ourselves into a regular sleep pattern, but its hard.</p>

<p>So what does tomorrow bring. We are hoping to go to a local mass at one of the many ancient churches. Mass in spanish should be different, and the atmosphere of the old churches is something to experience.</p>

<p>Oh… by the way, I have added a few more photos to the Santiago picture album - enjoy, we are :)</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Santiago pictures</title>
	  <link>/santiago-pictures</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-16T23:49:03+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/santiago-pictures</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/chile-santiago-streets.jpg" alt="" title="Chile - Santiago streets" /></p>

<p>I have managed to post some of our pictures from around the neighbourhood where we are staying. There are not too many up there yet, but I hope to be able to get more up soon. Its difficult due to the size of my image files, and not being able to resize them easily in internet cafe’s… oh well.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Hola! The trip begins.</title>
	  <link>/hola-the-trip-begins</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-15T15:47:24+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/hola-the-trip-begins</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Hi all,</p>

<p>After a reasonable, but long flight we touched down in Santiago yesterday afternoon (14th). After some sleep, we had our first dinner here, which consisted of a packet of Corn chips &amp; a bottle of local red wine called ´Carmen´ - made the choice easy.</p>

<p>After some more sleep last night we had a light breakfast where we are staying, and have headed out to try and get a feel for the place. Hope to do some tours during the week to see the sights, etc.</p>

<p>The city is reasonably nice. We are staying in the european area, which has nice buildings and cobble stone streets. The rest of the city is basically like any other - very busy. The smog here is noticeable, although not too bad.</p>

<p>We hope to have some photos up here shortly.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
