<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title></title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Turkey - The Wrap Up</title>
	  <link>/blog//turkey-the-wrap-up</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-05-27T06:41:51+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blog//turkey-the-wrap-up</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>We still have a day and a half left in Istanbul. Other than our last minute shopping and revisiting the Bazaar’s we are winding down and getting ready to come home.</p>

<p>We thought this was a good time to reflect on what we have done, and wanted to provide a brief wrap up of everything we have done while in Turkey.</p>

<p><strong>Gallipoli</strong><br />
Gallipoli was probably on top of our list. It was absolutely beautiful, and the historical significance almost meant it was a must do for us - and we weren’t disappointed.</p>

<p><strong>Istanbul (general)</strong><br />
Istanbul is great. Depending on how adventurous you are, will depend on how much you get out of Istanbul. Delving deep into the streets and alleys to uncover hidden, off the beaten track gems is great. But even we haven’t had time to explore everything. The tourist sights (Blue Mosque, Aya Sophia, Grand Bazaar, Spice Bazaar, Taksim Square) are always a must see for first time visitors such as myself - but I’m sure Laura is starting to get sick of them by now.</p>

<p><strong>Troy</strong><br />
Troy was interesting - probably more so from the Myth and Legend perspective than anything. To be able to say I have stood in Troy is quite amazing. Overall it’s not the most exciting of places however, and the tour is only an hour or so long. Defiantly worthwhile given we were in the area, but not something I would be making the 12 hour round bus trip for on it’s own.</p>

<p><strong>The Princes Island</strong><br />
The Princes Island is one of those curious sites. While you want to make sure you see it - and don’t get me wrong it was a nice place - there isn’t actually that much to do. Possibly this was one of the places we were least prepared for, and didn’t have much time to dig too deeply… So we could quite easily have missed the good stuff?</p>

<p>So what was our favourite? Basically the order in which they appear above is reflective of how highly each ranked.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Mythical Troy</title>
	  <link>/blog//mythical-troy</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-05-24T13:45:33+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blog//mythical-troy</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So after out day in Gallipoli, our tour takes us across the narrows of the Dardanelles to Canakkale which is in the Asian side of Turkey, an where we spend the night before heading of to nearby Troy (Troya) in the morning.</p>

<p>Troy is about a 30 minute bus ride out of Canakkle. We arrive to an overcast drizzling morning - its about now we wished we had packed our rain coats!</p>

<p>Walking through the archeological site that is Troy was very interesting, and our local guide again provided lots of details and background about the site.</p>

<p>One interesting fact relates to the site of Troy itself. Troy of legend and myth was a sea port - the actual location is somewhat inland (although the Dardanelles are visible from the high vantage point).</p>

<p>The belief is that thousands of years ago when Troy was prospering it was actually a sea port as described in the legends and myths. It is thought that heavy silting bought on by earth quakes in the region over time forced the narrowing of the mouth of the Dardanelles which in turn caused the sea to subside and form solid land - which is now in use as extremely fertile cropping country.</p>

<p>As with many other cities within Turkey, Troy saw its fair share of occupying rulers - the Trojans, the Greeks, and the Romans. Each new occupation saw dramatic reshaping of the earlier Troy - either because it had been raised to the ground from the conflict, or the new rulers wanting to inject their own cultural influences on the region.</p>

<p>This resulted in 9 different levels of Troy - all built on top of the ruins of the previous, and clearly visible as you walk through the archeological site.</p>

<p>All in all it was a very interesting tour. The only downside is the 6 hour bus ride back to Istanbul, which included the obligatory stop at the purpose built tourist trap buffet and shopping complex - glad we ate before we left 5TL for 2 Kebabs in Canakkale or 13TL each for crappy buffet in the middle of nowhere).</p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/20120525-112106.jpg" alt="20120525-112106.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/20120525-112120.jpg" alt="20120525-112120.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/20120525-112131.jpg" alt="20120525-112131.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/20120525-112157.jpg" alt="20120525-112157.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/20120525-112028.jpg" alt="20120525-112028.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Preparing the Turkey - The lead up to our Istanbul trip</title>
	  <link>/blog//preparing-the-turkey-lead-up-to-istanbul-trip</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2012-05-06T05:44:04+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blog//preparing-the-turkey-lead-up-to-istanbul-trip</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So Laura and I will be heading off to Turkey in a few weeks.  While Laura has been to Turkey twice previously, this will put a tick in the “done” column on my travel bucket list.</p>

<p>The more people we talk to about Turkey, the better it sounds - I haven’t met anyone yet with a bad story, and actually all the stories I have heard sound fantastic.</p>

<p>It will be a reasonably whirlwind trip this time, about 11 days in total made up of 2 days in Kuala Lumpur on the way over, then the rest of our time in Turkey being mainly concentrated in Istanbul with an overnight trip to Gallipoli (to see the ANZAC war memorials and battle fields) and historic Troy.</p>

<p>So as our preparations continue, the excitement is building - and the clock is ticking until we leave.  While in Istanbul I am planning on taking a lot of photos - what is there not to like about a city so full of vibrant colours, culture and postcard like scenes such as  the Blue Mosque, the Grand Bazaar, the Spice Bazaar, and the Ayasofya.</p>

<p>With luck we will have internet access during our trip, so I will be able to sit back in the evenings enjoying a refreshing local beverage or two, possibly smoking on a Shisha Pipe, and reflect on the events of the day to distil the essence of our day into a blog post.</p>

<p>Until then… elveda  (goodbye in Turkish - according to Google translate at least :) )</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
