<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Peru in review</title>
	  <link>/peru-in-review</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-05-23T08:42:01+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/peru-in-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Our time in Peru has come to an end - we are moving on and leaving behind some awesome memories and great new friends.</p>

<p>I thought it would be good to try and review and reflect on our time here in Peru, and ponder some of the highlights, and the lowlights of what we have seen (in some cases the highlights and lowlights run together).</p>

<p>Initially landing in Lima we were a little concerned about what we had got ourselves into - the airport, as with many big cities is surrounded by poorer districts. So our first impression of Peru was a wild taxi ride through the slum areas of Lima. We both looked at each other and said - ¨This is what we wanted!¨.</p>

<p>Where we stayed in Lima ended up not being so bad. Miraflores and Barranco were probably the nicer suburbs of Lima.</p>

<p>Our Intrepid travel group would have to be listed as a highlight, along with our leader Augusto. We made great friends with all in the group - and hope to catch up with many of them along the remainder of our trip, and also back in Australia when we return.</p>

<p>Pisco was probably the first lowlight (after the Hotel Espuranza in Lima). Unfortunately the place had been devastated by an earthquake months earlier, so there was really not much to do or see there. Lucky it was only a night. The place also smelt quite strongly of fish, a side affect of being a seaside community I guess.</p>

<p>The desert Oasis and Nazca were defiantly highlights. While the flight over the Nazca lines was a little scary, observing the lines from the air was defiantly worth every second in that small plane.</p>

<p>Another observation was that after Lima, the general quality of the Hotels improved. We were expecting Lima to be the best, and things to go down hill from there, however this was almost the opposite - the exceptions being the very small remote towns where we had on very basic hotels, but these even stacked up to the Lima accommodation in their own ways.</p>

<p>The overnight bus ride from Nazca to Arequipa was, while exciting and reasonably comfortable, probably a lowlight due to the scariness of driving at night through the Andes - feeling like the bus is going very fast around some of the sharp corners, or overtaking through corners was not a great experience, and it was better to be asleep so you just couldn’t´t see what was going on.</p>

<p>Arequipa was a lovely city, we all wished we had some more time there to explore. It was the first nice city we had been too. While it was at altitude (which had its way of affecting all of us), it was lovely.</p>

<p>On the topic of altitude, I think I could list this on my lowlights. I’m not certain if it was the altitude, the food, or the coca that made me ill, but I defiantly cannot face coca anymore.</p>

<p>Coca, Coca tea, and Coca lollies are meant to assist with the affects of altitude. So as the altitude increased, our consumption of coca products did as well. Initially it was great, but as I became ill, I think associated my sickness with the Coca (an I don´t doubt that in some small way it may have contributed). The mere smell of coca now makes me feel nauseous!</p>

<p>Seeing the Andes close up was defiantly a highlight - these mountains are so amazing, its an incredible experience.</p>

<p>The Colca Canyon was both a highlight and a lowlight for me. This is were I first became sick, putting a dull spin on everything I did. Shivay, the first small town we arrived to in the Colca Canyon was nice - simple but nice. I enjoyed the hot springs there as much as someone with an ill stomach and pounding head could.</p>

<p>Seeing condors flying in the canyon was defiantly on the highlight list. This was amazing. Personally we think that condors are rather ugly birds, but they defiantly make up for it when they are soaring through the canyon - very spectacular.</p>

<p>Sabyu, again is listed as both a highlight and a lowlight. For me, being ill while on the first home stay was difficult, and made it hard to enjoy the experience - although I did defiantly try. And in retrospect this home stay was nowhere near as well prepared or organized as our home stay near lake Titicaca.</p>

<p>Puno was alright. I would not list it as either a highlight or a lowlight - it was just part of the trip. Lake Titicaca, and the Uros islands was defiantly a highlight. This was amazing to see and experience. Our local guide ended up being a little bit of a dud and no one really liked him from our group. As I mentioned, the home stay near lake Titicaca was great. We all though that we could have probably done with only the one home stay - two home stays 1 day apart was a big ask especially for those of us who were not so well.</p>

<p>Cuzco was defiantly on the highlight list - we all loved the free time we had here, and the city it self was beautiful. We also found what I believe to be the best eatery in all of Peru - Peki´s. This was a tiny sandwich bar about 100m from our hotel in a narrow street on the way to the main square. We discovered this place early on and the news spread like wild fire through our group - great fresh sandwiches (actually toasted rolls), and burritos!. Pekis was a rest bite for us weary travelers from the continuous Peruvian food.</p>

<p>While i’m on the topic of food, I might as well cover off our favorites that we encountered on the way.</p>

<p>Yes we did try Guienne Pig - it was in small pieces and had been fried, so it was rather like eating small chicken wings. It wasn’t bad. Not really sure what it tasted like but I went back for seconds.</p>

<p>We also sampled Alpaca - although the Peruvian medium rare appears to be the same as all their other ways of cooking red meat - over done and a little tough. It was nice, but just tough.</p>

<p>Laura’s favorite, that she discovered early on was a dish called Lomo Saltado - basically a stir fry containing rice, beef strips, onion, red pepper, and chips.</p>

<p>Ceviche was another dish I attempted - raw fish prepared in vinegar and lemon juice. Not bad, but I only had it the once.</p>

<p>Out of everything on our time in Peru, Machu Picchu was what we were waiting to see - and we weren’t disappointed. It was fantastic - everything we had hoped it would be and more.</p>

<p>Our time in the Amazon was also brilliant - we both loved it and wished we had a little more time to spend there just to chill out and relax.</p>

<p>So all in all a fantastic trip that we will remember for ever.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Welcome to the Jungle</title>
	  <link>/welcome-to-the-jungle</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-05-15T10:27:35+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/welcome-to-the-jungle</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/peru-amazon-from-the-air.jpg" alt="" title="Peru - Amazon from the air" />
From the comfort of Cuzco, we headed our on an AreoCondor flight to Puerto Maldonado in the Amazon Jungle.</p>

<p>While being back close to sea level was a relief, the temperature had also increased considerably along with the humidity, and the number of mosquitoes - although, none of these were quite as bad as we had expected.</p>

<p>After leaving the airport at Puerto Maldonado we were picked up by our Jungle Lodge transfer service - a Mercedes Benz bus without windows, and wooden seats with Jungle themes painted down the sides. The bus took us into Puerto Maldonado - a bit of a slum really, with not much there, and very dirty. Apparently the main mode of transport is the motorbike, with hundreds of these packing the dirty streets. While helmets did appear to be quite common, this was only the case for the drivers, with the passengers (often another 2 or 3 people) never seen to be wearing them.</p>

<p>We had a quick tour of the local market in Puerto Maldonado, which showed us some of the local Jungle produce, and one of the specialties of the area, the Brazil nut - which were quite nice.</p>

<p>From Puerto Maldonado we caught a slim boat down the river 2 hours to eventually arrive at the Ecoamazonia Lodge - our accommodation for the next two nights.</p>

<p>The lodge was very well set out and very comfortable - two hammocks in every room. The rooms were very open to the outside but sealed well with fly-screens - not a single mosquito bite the whole time :).</p>

<p>They also had a very nice bar, which offered beer and cocktails till 10pm, when all power was turned off to the lodge - literally lights out.</p>

<p>During the first afternoon, we had a short trek around Monkey Island - so called due to the local inhabitants. Our guide took a ruck sack full of banana’s and oranges to entice the locals down from the trees, which worked a treat. Very shortly after emptying his bag onto a bench the monkeys swarmed in for the feed - allowing us to observe them at very close proximity.</p>

<p>It was a pretty cool experience, although I think Laura would have preferred them to be on the other side of a fence or similar - a little too close for her comfort.</p>

<p>One of our group ended up with a monkey on his back - and after a few photos the monkey was finally lead off to a nearby tree - quite funny for those of us without the monkey on our backs!</p>

<p>Later that evening we took a small boat out onto the river in search of cayman (local alligators). We spotted only a few small ones - again something I think that made Laura happy - she was not too fond of the small boats, and didn’t really enjoy the idea of looking for alligators in the dark.</p>

<p>The next day we had a very early start to begin a 7.5km trek through a patch of local jungle - this was made a little more difficult by the fact that we had to wear gumboots due to the mud in certain sections.</p>

<p>At the half way mark there was an ‘observation tower’ - actually a huge tree with steps built into it. Not being fond of heights, I though I would just go a little way up, but ended up at the top - with nothing to see but the tops of trees swaying in the wind!</p>

<p>The return trip entailed a 3km boat paddle which was pretty tough in the heat of the day. By the time we go back to the lodge we were all pretty hungry and ready for a siesta!</p>

<p>Last night was completed in the bar enjoying a few cocktails and beers.</p>

<p>Today we left the lodge and headed back to Puerto Maldonado to catch a flight back to Lima. We arrived in Lima this afternoon - completing our Peruvian Experience!</p>

<p>So one to the next part of our journey.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Machu Picchu</title>
	  <link>/machu-picchu</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-05-11T14:24:20+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/machu-picchu</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/peru-machu-picchu.jpg" alt="" title="Peru - Machu Picchu" />
We got off to a very early start this morning - 4.30am, breakfast at 5, and on the bus up to Machu Picchu at 5.30.</p>

<p>The bus departs from the bus station in Aquas Calientes and heads down a narrow road into the jungle before crossing the river to begin the step and windy assent up the Machu Picchu mountain. Both Laura and I are not the best with heights, and buses driving along shear cliff faces is one thing we both battle for the isle seat on. Laura scored the window seat on the way up - were not certain if the partial daylight made the trip better or worse, but we made it to the top in one piece, although a there were a few nifty manuevers on the way up as two buses passed each other on the often very narrow track.</p>

<p>We were at the top at about 6am, and there was already a queue to get into the park. After entering, we walked/climbed our way to one of the higher areas on the southern side of the city where we could look down over the ruins.</p>

<p>Reaching the top you are immediately struck by the awesome site of the Machu Picchu city ruins - its pretty much all you expect it to be, but being there is just so much more exciting.</p>

<p>After many photos - post card perfect - we began our tour with our leader through the Machu Picchu ruins - this lasted for probably a good hour and a half to two hours and was very interesting.</p>

<p>The lawns of Machu Picchu are continually manicured by the Alpaca’s that roam freely there - apparently they are the owners of the site now and have completely free rain.</p>

<p>We took heaps of photos - although im sure these will not do the place justice - its something that simply has to be seen to fully appreciate.</p>

<p>Anyway, I have added some of the photos I took on my mobile to the gallery, so it should give you a small taste until I can upload more.</p>

<p>After our tour we had the option of climbing Wayna Picchu - the small, but very steep mountain that is on the northern side of the Machu Picchu site (Machu Picchu is actually the name of the mountain on the southern side of the site) - although this looked a little too dicey for us, so we decided to grab something to eat (a mistake as a chicken sandwich cost 20 soles, the equivalent of a decent 3 course dinner in most Peruvian cities!). Anyway, after a small snack we decided to just sit on one of the terraces and absorb the surroundings for a while (and pluck up the courage to take the bus back down in full daylight - I scored the window seat this time!).</p>

<p>This afternoon was pretty much consumed by the train ride back to Ollantaytambo, and then a bus ride back to Cuzco and civilisation again.</p>

<p>I must say, Cuzco is an absolutely lovely city - possibly one our favorite of the tour so far - and its great to be back. We have another free day here in Cuzco tomorrow, and then we head off for the Jungle after that for two nights, and that will conclude out tour.</p>

<p>We are looking forward to the Jungle, and have had a very small taste of it travelling to Machu Picchu today.</p>

<p>The country side here is amazing. In the Jungle (about 2,000m) its warm and humid, yet the tops of the mountains (some of which go over 5,000m) have snow caps. Its weird to be in the warmth of the Jungle and look up and see snow on top of the mountains.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>On the road to Machu Picchu</title>
	  <link>/on-the-road-to-machu-picchu</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-05-10T09:27:17+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/on-the-road-to-machu-picchu</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/peru-inca-ruins.jpg" alt="" title="Peru - Inca Ruins" />]
So we left Cuzco yesterday afternoon headed for Ollantaytambo, a small rural town which is part of Cuzco province, and a couple of hours out of Cuzco city.</p>

<p>On the way we passed through the sacred valley and visited the large markets in Pisac - again buying a few souvenirs. We then continued on to another small rural town where we had some local interaction. We were met at the local petrol station by a local (guide) on a push bike. We followed him through a number of back streets in our bus and eventually arrived at a local pottery factory.</p>

<p>One of the local families worked at the pottery factory and made various types of pottery - from cups, tea pots, plates, etc. All vary nice but probably little fragile to transport!</p>

<p>After the pottery factory, we had lunch with a local family - this consisted of an Andean grain soup with potatoes, which was very nice, and was followed by salad and a dish made of a different type of potato and mince (they love their potato’s over here, and have over 1000 varieties!).</p>

<p>After the meal we went to what was probably the highlight of the day - the local chocolate factory. Here we watched a demonstration of how the locals make chocolate, starting with the dried coco beans, then roasting them, then simply combining the roasted coco beans with equal measure of raw sugar and passing it through a grinder! Fantastic! Needless to say we purchased a sample - it was great, and you couldn’t get fresher :).</p>

<p>On the way out of town - heading for Ollantaytambo - we stopped at a local pub/bar where we saw how the locals make Chicha (corn beer). The process was interesting, the result not so great. We sampled two varieties, essentially both the same base, but one was mixed with strawberries which changed it from a yellow colour to a mild pink. I think I will stick to the local lagers, which are surprisingly good!</p>

<p>Arriving in Ollantaytambo you can’t help but notice the massive mountains on either side. These are so high the clouds often cover their peaks. Embedded in the side of some of the mountains were some Inca ruins.</p>

<p>This morning we spent a couple of hours exploring these ruins - a preparation for Machu Picchu tommorrow.</p>

<p>So this afternoon we caught the train from Ollantaytambo to Aquas Calientes (literally translated it means hot waters). Aquas Calientes is not that exciting… Its essentially a town that has been built as a staging point for tourists on their way to and from Machu Picchu. It is cute in its own way, but as the only way to get here is by train (or walk the Inca Trail), everything is expensive!</p>

<p>So tomorrow we will be getting up early (5am) to have breakfast and leave by 5.30am. We will be up at Machu Picchu by about 7am, apparently in time to see the last of the sun rise (if the clouds keep away… not too promising at the moment!). We are then pretty much free to spend about 4 or 5 hours exploring Machu Picchu before getting back on the bus to Aquas Calientes, then getting the train and bus back to Cuzco, where we will spend the night, and have another free day before heading for the Jungle!</p>

<p>Once in Cuzco, I really hope to be able to get some more of our pictures posted up, as we have heaps.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Cuzco here we come</title>
	  <link>/cuzco-here-we-come</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-05-06T23:32:29+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cuzco-here-we-come</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/peru-in-the-andies.jpg" alt="" title="Peru - In the Andies" />
So after another long bus ride across the Andean country side we arrived in Cuzco yesterday afternoon - and what a relief this was. The 7 hour bus ride across Peruvian highways that at times were as smooth as a bad gravel road was wearing thin - plus our butts were sore from sitting for so long ;).</p>

<p>Cuzco really is the oasis we have been waiting for - its downtown region is really old and beautiful with a definite European feel. The icing on the cake for us is that we are sort of starting to feel better!</p>

<p>We have a couple of free days here to explore and get to know the city - which we are both looking forward to.</p>

<p>Last night consisted of locating an old English style pub, consuming a few lagers, and then heading up the road for a bowl of creamed tomato soup (all the soup over here seems to be creamed - its hard to get a simple chicken broth, etc).</p>

<p>Today we are going to head out to the local produce markets, which should be very interesting and present a few good photo opportunities I hope.</p>

<p>If I get some free time later this afternoon, I will try to work on getting some of the other photos put up, but this will take time as I need to re-size, etc.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Lake Titicaca home stay</title>
	  <link>/lake-titicaca-home-stay</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-05-05T10:29:30+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/lake-titicaca-home-stay</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/peru-lake-titi-caca.jpg" alt="" title="Peru - Lake Titi Caca" />
So we are back in Puno now (which is located on the shores of lake Titicaca) after leaving yesterday morning for our home-stay. We are both felling 100% on what we have been and hopefully the worst is behind us. We still need to be a little careful with our stomachs as they are still a little tender, but generally much better than they have been over the past 3-4 days.</p>

<p>Leaving the hotel yesterday we caught the local limo service - bicycle taxi’s. This was quite a ride with a dozen of us heading of in these peddle powered vehicles, and our drivers all competing to get us to the port first.</p>

<p>At the port we all jumped onto a local ferry which had been hired for us. The ferry left the port of Puno and headed out into Lake Titicaca. Close to Puno the water is covered in heaps of green algae, apparently caused from the pollution of Puno city. Lucky, the area is encircled by reids which trap most of the polluted water and keep the rest of Lake Titicaca fresh and clean.</p>

<p>Our first stop was about 40mins from Puno on one of the floating read islands of the Uros. We stopped at one of the smaller islands, which hosts around 5 families. There we had time to look around and take a pleasant ride on one of the reid boats with the children of the island, who sung us songs, and showed us how to eat the reid’s (basically you pull the reid out, take the bottom stork which is which, strip the skin off it, and begin chewing - it had no real flavour, but I wasn’t too keen on swallowing it as it had just come out of the lake!).</p>

<p>From the Uros island we continued on the ferry for about another hour until we got to our home-stay community in Llachon (pronounced yachon). This was a lovely little community and very friendly people. Our host family, Jesus and Candelara where great. They had three children, one girl 10, and two boys 9 and 7.</p>

<p>The children were a little shy to begin with, but soon came out of their shells and entertained us for the afternoon.</p>

<p>On arriving we went with our host families for lunch, which consisted of a lovely vegitable broth (containing potato, broad beans, onion, and carrot). This was followed by some fried home made cheese, boiled potatoes, broad beans, and yams. While it was all very delicious, our stomachs could only handle so much - so the soup was the highlight, being very simple.</p>

<p>In the late afternoon we helped the families put nets out in lake titicaca to catch fish for breakfast. After fishing, we returned to our homes and were provided with traditional clothes to dress up in for dinner.</p>

<p>For dinner, we all met in the community house (in full traditional dress) and were treated to corn soup (which was good), followed by some pasta and rice (which was too heavy for us so we passed it up). After dinner a local music group performed - these guys were just learning, and this was somewhat obvious, but they put on a reasonable show anyway.</p>

<p>Breakfast this morning consisted of two types of bread rolls - the hollow type we seem to be encountering everywhere, and one that was a little sweeter and resembled a fried scone. This was then followed by a pancake, and finally fried fish (resembling white bait) and boiled potatos. I think Laura was happy to see the pancake, and the fried white bait was quite tasty.</p>

<p>We left our home-stay families straight after breakfast and got back on the ferry to head to Taquile island, where we climbed the steep path to the top to see the awesome view - you could see the snow capped mountains in Bolivia from here (Peru and Bolivia share lake titicaca 60-40).</p>

<p>Finally a slow trip home back to Puno, where we are staying for tonight. Tomorrow we are off to Cuzco, which I think most of us are looking forward to - although it will be a 7-8 hour bus ride!</p>

<p>I think we are looking forward to Cuzco for number of reasons - it at a lower altitude, so things should be a little simpler, we are there for 3 days, so we can relax a little, and its meant to be a very beautiful city - so we cant wait.</p>

<p>We have tons of photos from the last week, but unfortunately haven’t had access to a computer that will easily allow us to upload them. I might try to find another place later tonight, or perhaps in Cuzco.</p>

<p>Also please forgive the bad spelling. The keyboards over here are setup for european languages, and often the letters on the keys have been rubbed out, etc, making the job all that more difficult.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Colca Canyon and Home Stay</title>
	  <link>/colca-canyon-and-home-stay</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-05-03T12:53:29+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/colca-canyon-and-home-stay</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/peru-colca-canyon.jpg" alt="" title="Peru - Colca Canyon" />
From Arequipa we headed to the Colca Canyon - passing through altitudes of almost 5,000m on the way.</p>

<p>When you get off the bus at these altitudes, you have to take it very slowly! Even very slow walking causes your head to spin and heart to thump. I thought it was convenient that they had roadside markets in places like this. Unknowing tourists such as ourselves jump off the bus in the high altitude, dizzy due to lack of oxygen, and purchase anything that is going before making it back to the bus to recover.</p>

<p>I only ended up with a Peruvian style beanie - which has come to great use as its bloody cold up here at night.</p>

<p>We stayed in a small little town - the name evades me now - and ventured out to the local hot springs. These were great, but unfortunately not sure they were the best idea for me, with a head ache and crock guts. I spent the rest of the night in bed, while the others ventured out to a local restaurant with a dance show.</p>

<p>Yesterday, we set of early to see Andean Condors in the mid section of the Colca Canyon. This was amazing. There were about ten to twelve condors soaring around in the canyon - defiantly well worth the hour long bumpy bus ride.</p>

<p>After this we headed to a small village in the top end of the Colca Canyon for our first home stay. This was fun - or could have been except I was still pretty sick. Laura and I both enjoyed spending time with the family we were billeted out to. Our room was small, simple, but nice - a dirt floor, and hard beds. It was really interesting trying to communicate with our families who knew virtually no english, just spanish, and a local language (cant remember its name at the moment).</p>

<p>After an extremely cold night, and poor sleep due to my need to use the wañu (bathroom) excessively, we left our families for our next stop - Puno.</p>

<p>We arrived in Puno this after noon, and have been out getting some simple supplies for our families at the next home stay (tomorrow night) on the shaws of lake titicaca. I imagine this will be another very cold night, but we are looking forward to it, and making the most of the comfortable hotel we are in tonight.</p>

<p>Its a pity we are both a little on the sick side - while im worse than Laura, we are both feeling it. Hopefully it will all disappear once we come down from the altitude a little.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>We made it to Arequipa</title>
	  <link>/we-made-it-to-arequipa</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-30T14:09:30+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/we-made-it-to-arequipa</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/peru-arequipa.jpg" alt="" title="Peru - Arequipa" />]
So we caught the overnight bus from Nazca last night. We were not expecting too much, but we were pretty surprised when we boarded the bus to find it was equipped with recliner seats - i’m not just talking about being able to recline the back of the seat, but a leg rest as well. It was pretty well equipped - not that is really any exchange for a real bed and pillow. While we did sleep, I was pretty restless but probably the best you could expect on a bus.</p>

<p>I get the feeling that the idea of having an overnight bus is mainly to combat the potential for car sickness. Nazca is about 500m above sea level, while Arequipa is over 2,500m - so there is a lot of mountain climbing involved, and this involves many many windy and often hairpin turns.</p>

<p>I think the best option was sleeping. It was a little nerve racking at times with the bus driver pumping ‘Black Betty’ from his sealed off compartment while driving (often faster than I think a bus should have been) through the mountain bends.</p>

<p>This was the first bus service we have been on where the in service movies were in english, so this was a little novelty. They also served a light breakfast of mini hot-dogs and highly sweetened black coffee on the bus - we found this a little weird but hunger got the better of us.</p>

<p>So today we ventured out into the streets of Arequipa and did a tour of a local monastery - which was pretty cool. Arequipa has a fantastic view of some nearby snow capped mountains, and an active volcano nearby. Great scenery.</p>

<p>We have noticed that the higher we are going the cooler it is getting. We will be going over 4,500m tomorrow - our highest point, and have been warned that the next three days could be quite cool.</p>

<p>For me the altitude has been a little noticeable. I think Laura is coping with it much better at the moment, but the next week or so will tell. We have been told to drink coca tea or eat coca sweats to help with the affects of altitude. The coca tea is not that different from green tea. We will also get the opportunity to get some coca leaves to brew our own tea while on the home stay.</p>

<p>We have our first (of two) home stays in two days time, so we are looking forward to that.</p>

<p>Anyway, probably wont be near internet for the next few days, so will try to write more once we get back into civilisation :)</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Peru here we come</title>
	  <link>/peru-here-we-come</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-29T13:58:53+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/peru-here-we-come</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/peru-nazca-lines.jpg" alt="" title="Peru - Nazca Lines" />
It’s been a few days since we have had a chance to grab a seat in front of a computer (probably a good thing), so I will try to fill you all in on what we have been up to in the last few days.</p>

<p>We started our Intrepid tour of Peru on Friday. We all met in a small hotel in Miraflores (a suburb of Lima). There are 13 of us in the group, and we all get along really well. The group is a really well balanced mix of people and ages - mostly Australians, and some Poms.</p>

<p>The first day comprised a short walking tour of Lima, which took us to the San Francisco church and the catacombs underneath. Laura and I had already seen the catacombs during our week in Lima, so passed and instead decided to check out the church, which was closed when we visited the first time.</p>

<p>One thing we noticed immediately (on attempting to make our local payment), was they hate, and will bluntly reject any US notes that are even slightly damaged. This is a real pain, as the banks and ATM’s dish them out freely. The result was we got stuck with a couple of spare US notes that are very difficult to pass off to anyone. Oh well… lessons learned. I’m sure the europeans won’t be as picky.</p>

<p>Anyway, we left Lima in the afternoon and headed south for Pisco. Pisco was recently (back in August) devastated by an earthquake, and around 600 people were killed. Unfortunately the city is still in ruin so there is not too much to take in here (from a tourists perspective).</p>

<p>Pisco is the city that gives its name to Peru’s national drink, the Pisco Sour (as you may have read, we have enjoyed a few of these). Pisco is made out of grapes grown in the Pisco region. Its essentially a distilled wine, and varies in potency from regular wine at about 12% to a very highly distilled alcohol at about 60-70%. Pisco sour is made with a form of Pisco that sits somewhere in the middle, and is mixed with lemon or lime juice, sugar syrup, and egg white, which is all blended together. The egg white gives it a frothy head. Its then topped with wither bitters, or more commonly cinnamon. Its rather refreshing on a warm day. Traditionally its intended as an aperitif, but is commonly drunk at any time (by us at least :))</p>

<p>From Pisco, we took a short bus ride down to the coast - passing a number of fish processing factories on the way (pin pointing the source of the strong fishy smell in the area). From a small coastal port we took a fast boat out to the Paracas islands. These are a set of small islands just off the coast which host heaps of bird life and sea lion colonies. On the larger of the islands was a huge candelabra figure etched into the side of the mountain face - this was pretty impressive to see, and gave us a taste for what we could expect later in Nazca.</p>

<p>From the coastal port we began heading inland for Nazca. The landscape in this area is essentially barron desert. Its very arid, and not many features except the odd tree, and mountains on either side.</p>

<p>We stopped in at a desert oasis on the way to Nazca for lunch. This was littery exactly how the cartoons picture them - it’s the middle of the desert, sand dunes for miles, then as you come over the top of one, you can see the other side, and instead of more sand, there is a small lake and some lush greenery with a hotel and some shops surrounding the lake.</p>

<p>We had the option to sand board here, but considering the head, and my previous experiences with large sand dunes I decided against it, considering we had a further 3 hours to Nazca. We didn’t really feel like sitting on the bus full of sand. It would have stuck to everything considering how hot it was.</p>

<p>So we settled for a light lunch, a few crevasses (beers), and a walk round the oasis instead.</p>

<p>We headed off to Nazca after lunch. Again more desert that was only broken up as we approached Nazca, and had to start going through some small mountains. This was pretty exciting after a few hours of desert. Coming into Nazca, we stopped at a roadside tower on the Nazca plains to observe some of the famous Nazca lines. Not a great view but gave us a taste.</p>

<p>Our hotel in Nazca was pretty nice - air con, pool, etc. It’s actually been the best so far.</p>

<p>Last night we headed out for a meal and a local Peruvian show, which featured some native dancing, as well as an Andean band, which was pretty great. I had the Ceveche - a Peruvian specialty of raw fish marinated in lemon/lime juice and vinegar (which sort of cooks the fish on the outside, and presumably kills any nasties?). It was quite nice - would defiantly have it again.</p>

<p>Today we took a (very small) plane (3 passengers) to fly out over the Nazca plains to see the lines from the air. This was great, a little nerve racking at times, and nauseating, but defiantly worth it. Just as we were about to head back, the lady in the front (also from our tour group) popped… projectile vomiting all over the side window and panel in front of her. The plane was defiantly too small for this. The smell nearly set us off in the back seat, but we managed to hold it together and got back in one piece - although our stomachs were a little stirred up.</p>

<p>Tonight were waiting for the overnight bus (about 11pm) to pick us up and take us to Araquipa. This is where we will start getting into the altitude, so light meals tonight and no grog…</p>

<p>Anyway, looking forward to whats to come.</p>

<p>Love you all</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Peruvian Highlights Tour Begins</title>
	  <link>/peruvian-highlights-tour-begins</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-04-27T10:31:01+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/peruvian-highlights-tour-begins</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>We meet up with our tour group last night in Miraflores (just out of Lima) in the hotel we were staying in for the night.</p>

<p>Our tour group is pretty good - a mix of both young and older people, but all lovely.</p>

<p>We left Lima this afternoon and after a 3-4 hour bus ride we have arrived in Pisco - the city where the national drink gets its name from.</p>

<p>The earthquake in Peru last year has hit this place pretty hard, and a lot of places have been flattened - luckily our hotel wasn’t one of them.</p>

<p>The first impressions of Pisco - you step off the bus and the distinct aroma of fish is in the air - I would describe it more of a fish flavoured cat food smell… well its only for a night.</p>

<p>Anyway, hope to be able to post some pics soon as we get access to a USB port.</p>

<p>Till then - Love you all</p>

<p>Lucas &amp; Laura</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
