<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Heathrow, Terminal 4, BA Lounge</title>
	  <link>/heathrow-terminal-4-ba-lounge</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-07-31T21:26:41+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/heathrow-terminal-4-ba-lounge</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Let me start by saying - This place is ace!</p>

<p>We landed into Gatwick from Naples, almost a 3 hour flight, and had to make our way to Heathrow Terminal 4 - which nothing seems to go to directly!</p>

<p>We converted our left over Euro’s into Pounds which was almost exactly enough to buy our bus ticket from Gatwick to Heathrow - luckily its a free ride for BA travellers from Terminal 5 to Terminal 4 on the bus.</p>

<p>We got here in reasonable time, and cleared security reasonably quickly. On the other side I suggested to Laura that we ‘try’ our Qantas Frequent Flyer card at the BA Lounge - we could only be turned away and have to sit in the public lounge for just over 2 hours.</p>

<p>Laura was a little hesitant initially, and took some convincing. I was not even sure we would get in. We approached the entry desk, presented our cards and boarding passes and we let in immediately!</p>

<p>We walked in and we were a little overwhelmed - what to do first? Use the free internet, go to the serve yourself anything you can dream of bar, the cafe, use the showers… All of it is free!</p>

<p>First up we grabbed some food - if we hadn’t been allowed in we were looking at a £10 McDonald’s meal. We enjoyed dinner with a lovely 2001 red wine, followed by a tall Gin &amp; Tonic. We then had some more salad and bread, and finished with cheese and crackers.</p>

<p>After a few more free pour Gin &amp; Tonics we decided to have a shower - it was rather hot in Italy, and we have an 11 hour trip ahead of us. We were given our beeper to be alerted when the private shower facilities were free - this gave us time for another Gin &amp; Tonic (for me) and a Bailies on ice (for Laura).</p>

<p>After showering and freshening up we went to the lower level to use the internet - where I am now. Laura indulged in another glass of fine red wine, and I helped my self to a few more Gin &amp; Tonics.</p>

<p>Let me assure you - this place is much better than McDonald’s - but I’m sure we have already paid for it all (and more) in our ticket prices somewhere along the line. It’s just a pity we only discovered it now. Let me assure you we will be checking in early in Bangkok!</p>

<p>Anyway, must away… My Gin &amp; Tonic is empty.</p>

<p>See you all soon.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
