<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Exploring more of Paris</title>
	  <link>/exploring-more-of-paris</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-05T19:26:53+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/exploring-more-of-paris</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Today has been much hotter than yesterday - about 34c - and after the big day we had yesterday we decided to take it a little easier and just hit a few of the sights - with the Eiffel Tower the first on the list.</p>

<p>We headed off reasonably early from the apartment (while it was still cool) and headed across the river, past Notre Dame, and then onto the train station we thought would take us straight to the Eiffel Tower - unfortunately that part of the line (and the station) are closed for works… there go those plans and our early start.</p>

<p>After a brief chat with some helpful tourist information staff we were on our way again - however we ‘re-interpreted’ their instructions removing a change of train line and swapping it for a small walk - which ended up being quite pleasant.</p>

<p>It wasn’t long before the Eiffel Tower appeared from behind the many other tall buildings along the street - at least we were on track. A pleasant walk through some gardens brings us to the base of the tower - and its only 9:15am… We made it in pretty good time - only 20 busloads of people in front of us.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e24c6-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After a brief group conference at the base of the tower - and based on the size of the line for the elevator, we decided to walk up the stairs - how bad could 669 stairs be after all?</p>

<p>The thighs were burning for the first few flights - carrying an 18 month old added to the burn - but in the end we made it up to the first level.</p>

<p>A well-earned coffee while we looked out over Paris was that much more enjoyable having earned it by walking the stairs.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/5eeea-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Not being an enthusiast of heights (in fact I hate them), level one of the tower was actually pretty easy - except for the glass flooring in the centre - which Archie seemed to be attracted to.</p>

<p>The first time Archie ventured out onto the glass flooring he didn’t realise and then froze stiff once he looked down - but quickly realised he was ok and kept going. From then on it was a game - and I suspect he realised both mum and dad didn’t like going near it. He would quickly get himself just out of arms reach - just to taunt us I am sure.</p>

<p>We ventured up the next set of stairs and made it to level 2 - for an even better view of the city. A good number of photos later we made the journey back down the 669 stairs to the ground - and were glad for the early start, as the queues were much longer now.</p>

<p>From here our group went in two different directions. Mum and Jo jumped on one of the hop-on-hop-off buses to get a better look around the city while Laura, Maddie and I took Archie back to the apartment for a sleep - 2 minutes later he was asleep in the pram.</p>

<p>We arrived back at the apartment just as the little man was waking up - a good hour of sleep under his belt, and just in time for lunch. For lunch, we decided to check out the Falafel bar about 5 doors down from the apartment - it was awesome. For 6.50 Euro we got a falafels, salads, cooked eggplant, hummus and yoghurt in a nice fresh pocket bread - it was absolutely beautiful… and for desert… 2 doors up… we sampled decadent éclairs from <a href="http://leclairdegenie.com">L’Eclair de Genie</a> - which as the name suggests - were magical. We had Chocolate, Strawberry and Pistachio, and Salted Caramel.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/39845-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ab853-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After lunch we headed out to the Jardin du Tuileries. Laura and Maddie headed to the Museum at the end of the gardens; while Archie and I sat in a restaurant beer garden under the trees and watched the people flow by. It was here I discovered Hoegaarden Rosee (regular Hoegaarden wasn’t available) - it’s a lighter version of Hoegaarden (3%) that is mixed with a red berry juice. I wasn’t quite sure what to expect - but it was actually quite refreshing on a warm afternoon.</p>

<p>The girls got back from the museum and joined me (and Archie) for a few drinks at the restaurant in the park under the trees. It wasn’t long and the entire group was re-united when Mum and Jo came walking across the park and found us. From here we headed back home - we were done for the day.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/c65e9-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Back at the apartment we let Archie run around and play for a before heading out for dinner. The girls had found a nice secluded square a few streets down from where we were staying that was enclosed by 5 or 6 nice little restaurants. We sat down and ordered - tonight we had the dry sausage (two types of salami and prosciutto) as well as 3 types of cheese to start and then the girls all had a mixed grill, and I had the confit d’oie (goose) - which was delightful. It was my first time eating goose, and I will be back!</p>

<p>We are now all sitting around the little table in the apartment. The girls are playing cards, and eating gelato - while I punch out another blog post and sip away at the last of the limoncello we were still carrying with us from Tuscany.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ea179-img_8127.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2c3b8-img_8129.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/25c66-img_8142.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/af6ed-img_8222.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/887d6-img_8230.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fd1ca-img_8232.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>A big day in Paris</title>
	  <link>/a-big-day-in-paris</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-04T17:59:07+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/a-big-day-in-paris</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Today has been a very BIG day or us in and around Paris - and we are all knackered.</p>

<p>I’m sitting at the small kitchen table in our apartment - my back to the open window to catch the breeze. Today has been substantially cooler than any day we have encountered on our trip so far - about 28c max with most of the morning and afternoon around 18-25c - which made it actually quite pleasant for the amount of walking we ended up doing. It just wouldn’t have been possible on a hotter day.</p>

<p>After leaving the apartment at about 8:30am this morning we arrived back home at about 5:30pm - knackered and armed with groceries for a quick dinner. We suspect we have stretched Archie to his limit - he only had an hour sleep in the pram while we were out, and as we arrived home he was well and truly into his extremely tired and silly state.</p>

<p>The little man is down now and the house is peaceful - a very different situation only 30min ago - when he was fighting the need to sleep. But all is calm and the little guy is off with an early night - and I expect him to sleep through after the day we have had.</p>

<p>So… back to today…</p>

<p>The plan was to head to Versailles to see the palace and walk the gardens, an then try to get to Monet’s garden before coming back into Paris to fill out the rest of the afternoon with other sights. As it turned out things went about 50% right. It appears something went wrong in our planning and research - Monet’s garden is nowhere near Versailles (as we had thought it was). Oops. Unfortunately this meant mum wasn’t able to see one of the main things she had really come to Paris to see - but it’s a great excuse to come back.</p>

<p>Getting to Versailles was pretty simple on the Paris train system - with a short walk up to the Palace. We never wanted or expected to go inside the Palace - we just wanted to walk through the garden. When we arrived at the Palace (around 10am) the queue for the Palace tour was massive. There were almost as many people here as were in St. Peters square in Rome. It was crazy. Luckily the lines for the gardens were not nearly as long - quite small actually.</p>

<p>The gardens were what you would expect - immense, immaculate, and impressive. We wandered for hours.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/c4f94-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/4bf71-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After leaving the Palace we decided to head back into town where we had passed a produce market to pick up some lunch before continuing back to the train station to figure out how to get to Monet’s garden. All a little wiry from the morning walking we decided maybe it would be best to get a Taxi - we expected was only about 10km away.</p>

<p>After waiting (about 30min) for the Taxi drivers to come back to their cars from their lunch breaks, we asked to go to Monet’s garden. The Taxi driver looked at us oddly. Luckily we asked for an estimate of how much it would cost. $150 Euro came the reply.</p>

<p>Shit - something was wrong here. Either we are being ripped off or we have miscalculated. Either way we are not getting in the Taxi. We decided to ask the staff at the train station - who were very helpful and told us it was two trains and then a bus. Based on their directions we used the GPS on our phone and figured out we were about 60km away - the Taxi driver probably wasn’t trying to rip us off… It would probably cost $150 Euro to go that distance in a Taxi in Paris.</p>

<p>We abandoned our effort to see Monet’s garden at this point.</p>

<p>We decided to catch the train back into Paris and see some more of the sights. We got off at the Louvre station and walked around - only to discover the Louvre is closed on Tuesdays… another false start.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/d7c03-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>From the Louvre we walked up to the Champs Elysee, and then onto the Arch De Triumph - which was a fair walk in the late afternoon after having already spent much of the morning walking through Versailles.</p>

<p>All now a little wiry, we decided to catch the train back to Saint Paul station which is right near our apartment, grab some groceries and have dinner in tonight.</p>

<p>So, after a bottle of white wine and a few Hoegaarden beer the wiriness of the day has moved on to a more subtle comfortable tiredness.</p>

<p>I expect we will all sleep well tonight.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/94891-img_8041.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/15f4b-img_8045.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/4a5c8-img_8050.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8f48c-img_8053.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/33def-img_8058.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/3c1fa-img_8061.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/23cc8-img_8068.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ae758-img_8079.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f6040-img_8080.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/a586c-img_8110.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>On to Paris</title>
	  <link>/on-to-paris</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-03T19:37:59+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/on-to-paris</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>This morning we were up early - but not as early as previous travel days - 6:30am is manageable.</p>

<p>We have taxis booked to take us to the TGV train station so we can catch the TGV fast train to Paris - 1st class.</p>

<p>Aix-en-Provence has been great, and the 3 nights we have had here have been really relaxing - even Archie let us sleep in until 8am on on occasion, which was a welcome treat.</p>

<p>Our Taxi’s pull up to our apartment, and we divide into two groups to head for the TGV station - Laura, Archie and I in the BMW, the others in the Mercedes. The Taxi’s in France (at least in Aix) are significantly better than those back home in Melbourne.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/936f0-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The TVG ride was very pleasant. We were on the top deck which provided us we a slightly better view of the country side than earlier train rides where we had opted for the bottom deck on account of the numerous large and heavy suitcases. This time however, as our seats were pre-booked, we managed to lug the cases up the stairway to the top deck.</p>

<p>Being first on the train has advantages in being able to stow your bags with plenty of room. It also has disadvantages - as more people get on the train their bags pile on top of yours. Fortunately Paris is the end of the line - so there was no rush to dig through the pile of baggage to claim our bags and get of - we simply wait for everyone else to move out then simply follow.</p>

<p>Stepping off the train you immediately feel like you’re in Paris - something is just different. Walking out of the station confirms it. The typical Parisian architecture surrounds you. We have arrived in Paris.</p>

<p>We head for the Taxi rank and queue with everyone else. The Taxi rank attendant spots Laura pushing Archie in his pram and pulls us out of the line and arranges a special large Taxi for our group. There are definitely advantages to travelling with young children - I’m not sure we would get (or expect) this type of service back home in Australia - kid or no kid… you all line up and wait.</p>

<p>A brief taxi ride gets us to the reception office of the apartments where we will be staying. We drop our bags there, as the apartment is not quite available and head across the road for some lunch.</p>

<p>After lunch we head back to the reception office and go through the run-down of the apparent and the head off for the brief 500m walk around the corner and up the street to find where we will call home for the next 3 nights.</p>

<p>We arrive to a large solid door. Laura enters the code and we enter into a courtyard area. Here we wait to be met by one of the young ladies who manage the apartments. She takes us through a second security door and then up to the 3rd floor and shows us into the apartment.</p>

<p>There is a small elevator, which we will use for our bags. The elevator has a 2 person maximum - but I am confident it is almost impossible to exceed limit given the dimensions of the lift are only 1 meter deep by 50cm wide. The bags make it up safely.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fedce-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The apartment is old but refurbished and contains a number of modern amenities - but not air-conditioning and minimum overnight temperatures of around 21-22c… only a single fan. I am sure we will survive - the windows are all open and there is a nice breeze flowing through.</p>

<p>The streets around our apartment are beautiful and typically Parisian (could they be anything else in Paris?). There are cafes and little eateries scattered all about our neighbourhood. We are all looking forward to the next few days.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/74eda-img_7972.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>This evening we took a short walk from the apartment out onto the nearby Rue de Rivoli - a very main street which leads up toward the Louvre. We then detoured in toward the Seine river, and across to see Notre Dame.</p>

<p>We didn’t make it to the Lourve tonight - it was too hot to be out walking too far (34c), and it was already 6:30pm, so time to find some dinner for Archie (and the rest of us).</p>

<p>We headed back toward our apartment and settled into La Favourite - a local cafe which had been recommended to us. The meals and drinks were all very nice - including my Whiskey Sour.</p>

<p>Anyway - we have a biggish day planned for tomorrow. Up early to try and get it all done before it gets too hot - and then back to the apartment and shade (or a local bar) to wait out the heat of the day. No wonder the Parisians all leave Paris at this time of year - its stinking hot.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/d11ac-img_7939.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/d12d4-img_7967.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/bbbcf-img_7971.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/be486-img_7972.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f7b0c-img_7974.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ad36d-img_7977.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/c3ede-img_7979.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>In and around Aix-en-Provence</title>
	  <link>/in-and-around-aix-en-provence</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-02T07:56:57+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/in-and-around-aix-en-provence</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>It’s been good to be back in one place for a few days. It’s still warm, but a lot cooler than where we have been in Italy - which makes getting out during the day a lot more manageable - especially for Archie our 18-month-old.</p>

<p>Aix-en-Provence is a beautiful old city - two main grand carriage ways (streets) with many, many cobble stone lined streets leading off them in all directions. It’s very easy to get tangled - but also easy to get your way back to the main streets if you need to.</p>

<p>Yesterday started with Mum and I heading out to a local patisserie to by breakfast for everyone - fresh croissants (literally straight out of the oven), and a mixed assortment of other nice French pastries. Unfortunately the coffee we bought from the same place wasn’t exactly the great coffee experience we were looking for. Appears they may be either great at making pastries or great at making coffee - and few are great at both. We survived and the freshly made pastries were absolutely delicious.</p>

<p>The remainder of the day was spent basically exploring the city. We just wondered through the streets seeing what we could see. We hopped on the local street explorer shuttle and took the 45 min audio tour of the city, which helped to give us some of the history of the city as well as some general reference points for us to head back to.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/dfea2-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/608bd-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>In the late afternoon our wanderings lead us back to the Cours Mirabeau - where the markets were just being set up. Walking through the markets I couldn’t resist trying some of the freshly baked artisanal madeleines, and ended up buying one of each flavour (almond, citrus, orange, chocolate, and plain) us for afternoon tea - they were delicious, and possibly repeatable tomorrow afternoon.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ee443-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>In the late evening the temperature had cooled even further which made it very pleasant for an evening walk before dinner. We settled on what looked to be a nice little place in a side street a few streets back from the main streets. It was quieter and fortunately less smokers were here (actually none which is very rare in France).</p>

<p>Something about the French - they love smoking, and they love dogs. Dogs in restaurants. Dog in department stores. Dogs in the streets. Dogs at the airport. Dogs on the trains. Dogs everywhere. It seems that your dog literally has the same access privileges you do - so if you can go, so can the dog. Just makes me wonder how a department store like H&amp;M deal with a dog incident in women’s wear?</p>

<p>The restaurant we had selected for dinner was a good mix of traditional French food (which I was after), as well as more ‘recognisable’ foods - which fit the balance of our group well.</p>

<p>Our small group ordered a wide variety of dishes - Foie gras, roasted Camembert with Jamon and salad, chicken milanese and lasagne. I had the escargot and magret de canard (duck) done medium rare - so it was still a very blushing pink. It was all very delicious.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fd1c3-img_7887.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/d096f-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8e3f9-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>For desert I had a shot of black coffee and the 3 desert tasting plate which consisted of a small slice of lemon meringue tart, a small panacotta with red berry coulis and a small creme brulee - absolutely delicious.</p>

<p>Unfortunately we timed dinner a little late tonight. After a big day walking Archie didn’t last the distance - so Laura took him back to our apartment to put him to bed while we finished up. Dinner might need to be a little earlier tomorrow night.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/5c648-img_7779.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/332fc-img_7780.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/80963-img_7788.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/19d91-img_7806.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1bb05-img_7816.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/6d61f-img_7819.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/0ffe1-img_7829.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e7780-img_7834.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fc41b-img_7836.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/121ad-img_7839.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f0938-img_7843.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/00934-img_7885.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1b31b-img_7886.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/3c8ef-img_7889.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1ee58-img_7890.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/123d1-img_7891.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Rome to Aix-en-Provence via Genoa (by train)</title>
	  <link>/1rome-to-aix-en-provence-via-genoa-by-train</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-30T14:02:00+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/1rome-to-aix-en-provence-via-genoa-by-train</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="back-in-rome">Back in Rome</h2>

<p>We arrived back into Rome on Wednesday evening (29th July) in reasonable time after having left San Lupo in the early afternoon - immediately after the main mass and precession of the statue of San Lupo through the streets.</p>

<p>It was good to have made it back to San Lupo again, although not a lot looks to have changed since our last visit in 2008 - but its beautiful during the festival with all the lights lining the streets at night.</p>

<p>The drive from San Lupo back to Rome was fairly straightforward and un-eventful - exactly how I like my drives in Italy to be. The auto strade makes for fairly good driving - especially on the tolled sections. It’s always the last 25-30min of navigation into your final destination that becomes stressful.</p>

<p>Once we got back to Rome, we unpacked and checked into our hotel. We decided it was best to return the rental cars that night instead of hanging onto them for the night and risking damage in the car park - or worse a 2.5hr wait to return the car like it took to pick it up.</p>

<p>The rental car return was as you would expect, and as we had hoped - simple and straightforward - and in under 20min we had returned both cars and were headed for the Fumancino taxi rank. We are now well acquainted with where the correct taxi rank is after our late and frustrating entry into Rome about a week and a bit ago.</p>

<p>After a brief walk we find the taxi rank with 2 taxi’s sitting waiting for us - what could be better? Well it could be better if one of the taxi drivers was actually interested in doing their job - but rather we find one taxi with 3 young people in it, 2 young ladies in the front and a young gentlemen in the back. The other taxi was empty.</p>

<p>Apparently the two young (and somewhat attractive) ladies in the front of the occupied taxi had gained the intrigue of the young male driver - and none of them were interested in us.</p>

<p>So we wait… We lean against the empty taxi making it very obvious that we would like to go somewhere… still nothing. Eventually a third taxi turns up with an older gentlemen who is willing to help us - however when he see’s two other taxi’s he decides to enquire why we didn’t get one of them. The problem became quickly obvious to him. A few rushed words of Italian and one of the girls jumps out of the front of her taxi and asks where we want to go.</p>

<p>The young guy in the back seat jumps out and we pile into the girls taxi and we are off - one of the young ladies at the wheel and her friend in the front passenger seat - apparently coming along for the ride.</p>

<p>The banter in the front seats was endless - and obviously very interesting based on the facial expressions of the friend. Her attention was fixated on what the driver had to say - and thanks to some interpretation from Albert (Laura’s dad) we were able to follow the general gist of the conversation.</p>

<p>Well… apparently the driver had just broken up with her boyfriend Francesco… and it went on… and on… and on…</p>

<p>We eventually got to the hotel and 20 Euro later we parted ways with the young ladies and left them to their less than interesting conversation about Francesco.</p>

<p>The rest of the evening was fairly laid back - and after dinner we all turned in for an early night as we wanted to check out of the hotel as early as possible to maximise our time in Rome in the morning.</p>

<h2 id="whirlwind-tour-of-rome">Whirlwind tour of Rome</h2>

<p>After an early breakfast the next morning we met our arranged shuttle van that was taking us, and our many bags, into Rome Termini train station. It was a long drive into Rome in the traffic, but we eventually made it. As it was still early we decided to check our bags in at the train station baggage holding area and head out for some brief sight seeing.</p>

<p>Given the limited time we had, we thought our whirlwind tour should hit some of the major attritions - St. Peters Basilica and the Spanish Steps - conveniently both located on train line ‘A’.</p>

<p>We got out to St. Peters Basilica in no time at all - and the air-conditioning in the Metro trains was a nice escape from the heat and humidity of the Roman streets.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1fe0e-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Walking up and into St. Peter’s Basilica was quite a sight. It was only us, and 10,000 other people - quite tranquil really…</p>

<p>The line to get into the basilica wound its way right around the main piazza. We didn’t join the queue and were satisfied to observe from the outside and snap a few pics.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/900c1-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We then started to head back to the train and popped out at the Spanish Steps for a few pics before heading back to Rome Termini to pick up our bags and catch our train onto Genoa.</p>

<h2 id="train-to-genoa">Train to Genoa</h2>

<p>The train trip was great - although we managed to score the carriage with only partially working air conditioning - still it was better than none at all.</p>

<p>The train journey was relaxing. Put the mind in neutral for a while and enjoy the scenery passing by. A welcome change to being behind the steering wheel - and to be able to walk up to the bar carriage and have a few quite beers made it even better.</p>

<p>The train line follows the west coast of Italy - so there were a lot of brilliant views of the Mediterranean and the towns and cities along the way.</p>

<p>We arrived into Genoa in the early evening, and checked into our hotel, which was just a short walk across the piazza from the station. On this trip, Genoa is simply a stop over for us - so after a quick dinner (which was absolutely beautiful) we all headed off to bed to get up at 4:30am to catch our next train at 6am.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/bf391-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="the-early-train-to-aix-en-provence">The early train to Aix-en-Provence</h2>

<p>Friday morning we were all up early and met down stairs at 5:15am packed and ready to leave. We had arranged to check out the night before so just needed to drop our door keys with reception and leave. A short walk across the piazza got us back to the train station.</p>

<p>Today we had three trains to catch. The first was a regional train from Genoa (Italy) to Ventimiglia (Italy). The second was also a regional train from Ventimiglia (Italy) to Nice (France). The last was a fast TGV from Nice to our final destination Aix-en-Provence (France).</p>

<p>The challenges we had ahead were related to management of our baggage on and off the trains. Our bags at this point are quite heavy, and numerous. Getting on the first train was reasonably straight forward given the early hour - but as our journey moved on, more and more people joined the train making it more complicated to manage the placement of the bags.</p>

<p>The regional trains don’t stop for long at each station either - so we needed to be prepared - with out bags - ahead of time so we could quickly get everyone (and their bags) off before the train needed to move on.</p>

<p>The first stop was to be the most challenging with only 11 min to change trains - including locating the next train, its platform, and lugging all our bags down and back up the platform steps. Luckily we arrived in about 5 min ahead of schedule that gave us some more time. In the end, the change over was quite straightforward and we had plenty of time.</p>

<p>The next two legs of the journey were also straightforward - however we did notice an increased level of chaos at the French train stations as opposed to the Italian stations. Both Nice and the TGV station in Aix-en-Provence were packed and totally chaotic.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/481a6-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After arriving into the TGV station in Aix-en-Provence (about 20km out of the main city), we started looking for a taxi. Simply you would think - and in reality it was - unless you had two 30kg bags in tow plus a 10kg backpack, 4 other travellers and your 18-month-old son. Apparently we had arrived into platform 1. Taxis were at platform 3. This meant lugging bags up two flights of stairs onto the mezzanine level that allowed you to walk over the train line to platform 3. Most of the stations lifts were out of order. We found one that got us half way up, and reduced the stair climb by 50% - but we had to carry the bags the rest of the way.</p>

<p>The taxi was very easy - we needed two and in about 20min we arrived safely into Aix-en-Provence and at our accommodation - all very tired after the long day, and many stairs we had to carry bags up and down.</p>

<p>We did notice the much more comfortable temperature in Aix-en-Provence. Closer to 28c, and much cooler in the later evening when we ventured out for a walk up the nearby Cours Mir Abeau - a long and grand street which has night markets, cafes and restaurants all the way up. It made for a very nice and relaxed evening walk.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/3d18f-img_7660.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ea41f-img_7661.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/7b590-img_7737.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8ed35-img_7739.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8a6c0-img_7759.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/99010-img_7768.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e9736-img_7770.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fe418-img_7772.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/db8db-img_7775.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/bf9aa-img_7778.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Only days away</title>
	  <link>/only-days-away</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-11T03:19:25+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/only-days-away</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>After almost 18 months of planning, we are now quickly approaching our departure date. Our bags are packed (well mostly), and we are ready to go.</p>

<p>In the past Laura and I have either travelled solo or more typically together as a couple - not this time however…</p>

<p>Since we last had the opportunity to travel abroad, a few things have changed… mainly the arrival of our son (now 18 months old) who will be heading off with us to experience the wonders of the big wide world.</p>

<p>Not only will our son be travelling with us, but a fair part of our immediate families are also joining - some 17 people at last count.</p>

<h2 id="so-where-exactly-are-we-all-headed">So where exactly are we all headed?</h2>

<p>The large (main) group are all set to converge on a villa we have booked in Tuscany - somewhere near Sienna. There we plan to enjoy each others company as we soak in the warmth of the Tuscan sun, and feast on delicious hearty Italian food and wine.</p>

<p>Most of us will also continue on travelling to the south of Italy to arrive in San Lupo - the small town where Laura’s family are originally from.</p>

<p>Following our time in Italy, most of the group will head back home, while we continue on heading into the north of Italy then spending some time in France before heading across to the U.K. where the European leg of our journey will end.</p>

<p>Finally we will head across the pond and spend some time in the U.S. before heading for home.</p>

<p>So so really exciting time ahead of us. The hardest part now is watching the clock slowly tick down to our departure date…</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
