<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title></title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>London Gin Club in Soho</title>
	  <link>/london-gin-club-in-soho</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-09T11:09:27+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/london-gin-club-in-soho</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Last night was our final night in London. Laura and I left Archie with Mum and Jo and then headed out to Soho to find the London Gin Club - something Laura had kindly tracked down for me and thought it would be a great way to spend our last night in London.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f64df-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The club is in an old small pub - pretty casual and unpretentious - which was exactly what we were looking for.</p>

<p>We were greeted at the door and asked if we had a reservation - the place was packed.</p>

<p>“No… Sorry we don’t” we replied.</p>

<p>“Ok - let me see what we can do. Follow me” the waitress said.</p>

<p>We followed down a narrow spiral staircase into the Gin Cellar below and were seated at a small two seater table amongst other Gin drinkers.</p>

<p>The Gin menu was extensive. I settled on one of the tasting boards, while Laura had a Gin cocktail.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/de3aa-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The tasting board arrived - 4 vials of selected Gins and accompanying garnishes for each. Two large ice filled glasses then arrived - each Gin deserves its own fresh glass.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/6de7a-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The waitress then guided me through the tasting process - first pour the vial of Gin directly over the ice and then taste. Next add some of the premium tonic water that had been provided and taste. Finally add the paired garnish and taste again - then enjoy the rest of the drink. This process was repeated for each of the 4 Gins.</p>

<p>The night went quickly as we both enjoyed sitting in the balmy room down stairs sipping Gin. Later the waitress offered to move us upstairs where it was much cooler - so up we went - and enjoyed more Gin.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/7efb0-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/93cea-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Given we were flying he next day we wanted to avoid completely writing ourselves off. Not a good idea with an 18 month in tow - so after a few more drinks we called it a night and headed home - very happy with our evening out.</p>

<p>I would really recommend anyone who enjoys the odd Gin to look this place up next time they are in Soho - well worth it.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/51c44-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/035de-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
