<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Dresden - The old and the new</title>
	  <link>/dresden-the-old-and-the-new</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-06-23T19:37:24+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/dresden-the-old-and-the-new</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>We arrived into Dresden on the ICE train from Berlin and immediately fell in love with the city - despite it being a Sunday, and (almost) everything being shut.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/dresden-palace.jpg" alt="" title="Dresden - Palace" /></p>

<p>If we had realised how cute Dresden was we would defiantly penciled it in for a few more nights than just one - it defiantly deserves more!</p>

<p>Our hostel was about a 20 minute walk from the old town, but was situated in a new funky part of town with bars, cafe’s and restaurants.</p>

<p>We weren’t able to check into our hostel until mid-afternoon, so we dumped our bags (because they are getting heavier), and headed over to the old city.</p>

<p>The old city is situated on the northern side of the river Elbe, and is made up of beautiful cobble stone streets that wind their way between centuries old buildings, churches, and palaces - with the occasional modern upper class hotel thrown into the mix.</p>

<p>We headed to the Dresden Zwinger Palace and toured around there for the afternoon - in the heat (it was about 30c, and muggy). The palace was amazing, although we didn’t venture inside (as each separate section seems to require a different ticket!), we did walk through the court yard and around the roof terraces.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/dresden-ballet.jpg" alt="" title="Dresden - Ballet" />
We then wandered back through the main part of town on our way to the hostel - and after checking in, and a quick refreshing shower, we headed back to the Zwinger Palace to take in an evening of the local ballet companies production of “Casanova” - which was a nice relaxing way to finish off the afternoon and early evening.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/dresden-sunset.jpg" alt="" title="Dresden - Sunset" />
Heading back home, we decided to watch the sun go down in one of the beer gardens that was located right on the banks of the river and looked back over the old city - a few local drafts (and a fresh pretzel) really helped to close out what turned out to be a really great day.</p>

<p>We both think that Dresden is a place we will need to come back and see again. Its the type of place that you feel you could live in, and appears to nicely strike a balance between the old and new.</p>

<p>While we only experienced Dresden on a Sunday (and a very sunny one at that), the city had a very relaxed feel to it - and so many beautiful old buildings!</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
