<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>London Gin Club in Soho</title>
	  <link>/london-gin-club-in-soho</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-09T01:09:27+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/london-gin-club-in-soho</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Last night was our final night in London. Laura and I left Archie with Mum and Jo and then headed out to Soho to find the London Gin Club - something Laura had kindly tracked down for me and thought it would be a great way to spend our last night in London.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f64df-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The club is in an old small pub - pretty casual and unpretentious - which was exactly what we were looking for.</p>

<p>We were greeted at the door and asked if we had a reservation - the place was packed.</p>

<p>“No… Sorry we don’t” we replied.</p>

<p>“Ok - let me see what we can do. Follow me” the waitress said.</p>

<p>We followed down a narrow spiral staircase into the Gin Cellar below and were seated at a small two seater table amongst other Gin drinkers.</p>

<p>The Gin menu was extensive. I settled on one of the tasting boards, while Laura had a Gin cocktail.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/de3aa-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The tasting board arrived - 4 vials of selected Gins and accompanying garnishes for each. Two large ice filled glasses then arrived - each Gin deserves its own fresh glass.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/6de7a-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The waitress then guided me through the tasting process - first pour the vial of Gin directly over the ice and then taste. Next add some of the premium tonic water that had been provided and taste. Finally add the paired garnish and taste again - then enjoy the rest of the drink. This process was repeated for each of the 4 Gins.</p>

<p>The night went quickly as we both enjoyed sitting in the balmy room down stairs sipping Gin. Later the waitress offered to move us upstairs where it was much cooler - so up we went - and enjoyed more Gin.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/7efb0-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/93cea-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Given we were flying he next day we wanted to avoid completely writing ourselves off. Not a good idea with an 18 month in tow - so after a few more drinks we called it a night and headed home - very happy with our evening out.</p>

<p>I would really recommend anyone who enjoys the odd Gin to look this place up next time they are in Soho - well worth it.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/51c44-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/035de-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>London and Bath</title>
	  <link>/london-and-bath</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-08T07:32:57+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/london-and-bath</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So we arrived into London on Thursday afternoon (6th August) from Paris after catching the EuroStar train across the channel.</p>

<p>We were expecting a little more from the EuroStar – the name builds up a certain expectation – and we were left wanting. It probably didn’t help that the air conditioning in our carriage was on the blink either – making for quite a warm journey indeed. Thankfully one of the staff members was extremely helpful and did everything he could to make our journey more comfortable. He initially started handing out bottles of water, but seeing the sweat pumping out of Archie he decided to try and move us. After a little exercise in seat logistics he eventually found us two sets of two seats – we wouldn’t all be sitting together, but at least we would all be a little more comfortable in an better air conditioned carriage. The journey would have been horrible without this – as Archie was really getting quite irritable in the heat.</p>

<p>The train journey from Paris to London was around 2 hours, with barley 20min of that spent in the channel tunnel. Emerging on the English side of the tunnel you immediately notice grey sky… We are definitely in England.</p>

<p>Coming from the dry and often dusty 34-36c daily temperatures of Paris, the lower 25-27c temperatures that were forecast for the next few days in London would be very welcome.</p>

<p>After arriving into our station we discover that there is a tube strike on today – meaning no trains running at all in the Underground. This was going to be interesting. The queue for taxi’s was long, and after getting in one, the roads were quite clogged. Thankfully we got a nice driver who got us to our new home as fast as he could – and 20 Pound later we had arrived.</p>

<p>Our new neighbourhood is a bit rough – I suspect the local riff-raff live directly across the road – and fully expect to be kept up to all hours with dogs barking and kids screaming. People seem to park their cars wherever they want and on whatever side of the road suit them.</p>

<p>I feel like walking across the road to that house and setting a few things straight before we get started – Kensington Palace… who do they think they are…</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/de664-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Well so it seems William and Kate are our neighbours – literally a misguided drop-punt would have your footy over their fence – I suspect Will would be a pretty good sport and kick it back however.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ee14b-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>So it appears we are not in a scrubby neighbourhood at all, but rather the Royal Borough of Kensington and Chelsea – the X-Trail would look rather ‘out-of-place’ here I can tell you. Most car bonnets seem to be emblazon with either a three-point-star, four joined hoops, a horse, a big B or R. I think you get my drift – not to many Toyota’s or Nissan’s.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/97d0f-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Most of the cars are pitch black, with drivers at the ready. Our street (Prince of Wales Terrace) seems to be some sort of a waiting bay – drivers come and sit in their expensive luxury cars, some get out and polish the duco back to an immaculate shine – all waiting for whoever they work for to call.</p>

<p>Anyway, Will and Kate have been pretty good neighbours so far – not a peep – I’m not even sure if they are at home. I was hoping Will might sneak across the road for a quite pint at the end of the day (once the kids are in bed) – but we haven’t seen him in the Goat (our closest pub).</p>

<p>On the last two evenings we have enjoyed having a picnic dinner in Kensington Gardens, right at the back of the Palace – Archie has become quite fond of the ducks at the big pond.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/0466a-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Yesterday (Friday), Laura, Jo, Archie and I all jumped on a regional train and headed for Bath. Mum had been there recently so she did her own thing in and around London for the day.</p>

<p>The trip up to Bath took around 2hrs, but the journey was well worth the wait – Bath is beautiful… and I think next time we might have to stay there for a few days.</p>

<p>Big old streets, white sandstone buildings, big blossoming gardens and all immaculately clean. We spent the whole day wandering around Bath – there is just so much to take in.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/47615-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Laura and Jo went to the Jane Austin house, while Archie and I went to check out the smallest pub in Bath and have a local pint. Small was right – no room to swing a cat, let along a pram. The pram got folded up and Archie and I sat on the remaining 2-seater table next to the bar (there were only 4 in total inside).</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/0e2bc-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After our (my) pint of local ale, we headed back to meet up with the girls and headed down to the river for some lunch.</p>

<p>We continued to drift around Bath for the remainder of the day before catching the train back to London in the late afternoon.</p>

<p>Today we set out reasonably early and caught the train to the Tower of London. Getting there early was a great plan – there was no queue and we went straight in. Laura and I missed the Tower of London last time we were here (2008), so had it on the list to see this time round. We spend a good hour or so wandering around the grounds, and Archie seemed to enjoy himself – entertaining the Beefeaters.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/3aee6-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Laura, Archie and I left Jo and Mum at the tower (not literally) – they had booked a show in the afternoon and we wanted to see a few more sights before heading home to get Archie off to bed for the afternoon.</p>

<p>We caught the train up to Westminster – Saturdays in London in summer are full on. Tourists everywhere. Coming out of Westminster station we could hardly move. I think it took as about 25 min to get from the station, across the road to see Big Ben, across to Westminster itself before heading back toward St. James Garden – it was packed.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/d4841-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The walk up through St. James garden was beautiful, and London turned on an incredible day for us to be out walking. We wandered up through the gardens to Buckingham Palace then continued on to Hyde Park Corner before diverting off to see Harrods.</p>

<p>After a walk through Harrods, and some lunch, we headed back to the train station and home.</p>

<p>We are not waiting for Jo and Mum to get home from their show so we can ‘change the guards’ and leave Archie with Mum and Jo for the evening while Laura and I head out for dinner and a few drinks – Soho is the plan… but we will see what eventuates.</p>

<p>Tomorrow we fly to New York!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/49a2f-img_8275.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8e890-img_8292.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/b30e8-img_8312.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/74d52-img_8317.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/9b774-img_8369.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/109cc-img_8442.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/3e849-img_845628129.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/aa85a-img_8456.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/c28f3-img_8482.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Only days away</title>
	  <link>/only-days-away</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-10T17:19:25+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/only-days-away</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>After almost 18 months of planning, we are now quickly approaching our departure date. Our bags are packed (well mostly), and we are ready to go.</p>

<p>In the past Laura and I have either travelled solo or more typically together as a couple - not this time however…</p>

<p>Since we last had the opportunity to travel abroad, a few things have changed… mainly the arrival of our son (now 18 months old) who will be heading off with us to experience the wonders of the big wide world.</p>

<p>Not only will our son be travelling with us, but a fair part of our immediate families are also joining - some 17 people at last count.</p>

<h2 id="so-where-exactly-are-we-all-headed">So where exactly are we all headed?</h2>

<p>The large (main) group are all set to converge on a villa we have booked in Tuscany - somewhere near Sienna. There we plan to enjoy each others company as we soak in the warmth of the Tuscan sun, and feast on delicious hearty Italian food and wine.</p>

<p>Most of us will also continue on travelling to the south of Italy to arrive in San Lupo - the small town where Laura’s family are originally from.</p>

<p>Following our time in Italy, most of the group will head back home, while we continue on heading into the north of Italy then spending some time in France before heading across to the U.K. where the European leg of our journey will end.</p>

<p>Finally we will head across the pond and spend some time in the U.S. before heading for home.</p>

<p>So so really exciting time ahead of us. The hardest part now is watching the clock slowly tick down to our departure date…</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>London calling</title>
	  <link>/london-calling</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-05-28T09:30:49+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/london-calling</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>We have now left the Spanish speaking countries behind us after about 7 weeks of traveling. We find it hard to stop saying ‘Gracias’ to people - but I’m sure we will get over it.</p>

<p>Our flight out of Barcelona was delayed by about 30min, but we managed to touch down on British soil fine. We were dreading hitting Heathrow a little - you never seem to hear a good story about that place - but we were very surprised when we only queued for about 5min in immigration and waled straight through customs. Literally took us about 10min! We spent longer in the duty free grog shop buying gifts for our hosts here in London.</p>

<p>We caught the train from the airport to Paddington station, where we dumped our bags and started walking.</p>

<p>The very first thing that hit us ws the smell of fried food - the train station was full of it. I was an unfortunately familiar smell - one that we haven’t come across for the last 7 weeks.</p>

<p>We had no idea where we were and where things were in relation to us (no, we hadn’t done our homework again!). Wandering the streets we stumbled on a sign pointing to Hyde Park - where we managed to spend th rest of the afternoon.</p>

<p>We found our way back to Paddington station (and saw Princess Ann getting into a huge Bentley), grabbed our packs (and quickly remembered how heavy they were), and caught th train to Elouise’s place in Fulham - a reasonably easy experience.</p>

<p>Last night we ducked down to the local for a few pints and some dinner - its funny how comforting it was to have dinner in an English pub. Reminded us of home - at least the closest we have come so far.</p>

<p>This morning we were pleasantly surprised to have a Skype call with Laura’s parents - it was great to chat and touch base at home again.</p>

<p>Today we are planing to head into London and try to pick up a bike tour - which should be great providing the rain holds off!</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
