<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title></title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Italian transport strike</title>
	  <link>/blog//italian-transport-strike</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-07-07T09:05:32+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blog//italian-transport-strike</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Despite all efforts to plan and schedule the Italian leg of our trip, there is nothing we can do about a public transport strike.</p>

<p>The strike incorporates buses, trains, and planes - so we aren’t going anywhere! We were meant to leave Bologna today for San Gimiamo, but this will have to wait until tomorrow.</p>

<p>So today is a forced day of relaxation in the Bolognese country side - we can’t even get into town as we rely on the local bus service.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Bologna country side</title>
	  <link>/blog//the-bologna-country-side</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-07-05T09:38:06+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blog//the-bologna-country-side</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/blog//assets/images/bolonga.jpg" alt="" title="Bologna" />]
We arrived in Bologna yesterday afternoon, after a short train trip from Venice (2 hours). We managed to navigate the local bus system with the help of a local and shortly after arrived at our B&amp;B which is located in the country side hills overlooking farmland and the city - about 15 minutes drive out of town.</p>

<p>Its absolutely beautiful here. The relaxing surroundings, the peacefulness of the Italian country side… Its just what we needed - a change from staying in city’s.</p>

<p>After a relaxed afternoon of sitting on our balcony overlooking the country side, and having a few refreshing beers… and a nap… it was time for dinner out on the patio where we could watch the sun setting over Bologna.</p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/bolonga-feast.jpg" alt="" title="Bologna - Feast" />
We selected the local traditional plater and a salad to share for dinner, which was made up of all local produce including; salami, prosciutto, mortadela (which originated here in Bologna), dips and sauces, pickled peppers, pickled onions, pork fat, parmesan, and two types of bread - one a fried flat bread, and the other a small hard bread (resembling a hard flat scone). Our meal was accompanied by a glass or two of wine, and some conversation with the owner.</p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/bolongna-sunset.jpg" alt="" title="Bologna - Sunset" />
It really topped of a very relaxing afternoon - it was beautiful sitting outside, eating dinner, watching the sun go down.</p>

<p>Today we have plans to catch the bus into town and look around. Bologna - what we saw briefly of it yesterday - appears to be a lovely city with lots to see, and it has a reputation for amazing local food (Parma - where Parma ham is from, and Modena - where the fine Balsamic is from, are both just up the road).</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
