<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title></title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>The Sound of Salzburg</title>
	  <link>/the-sound-of-salburg</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-07-01T20:00:34+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/the-sound-of-salburg</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/saltzberg-at-night.jpg" alt="" title="Salzburg at night" />
We pick-up here were our last post left off. We have arrived in Salzburg – and its the night of the Euro Cup 2008 final, Germany -v- Spain. With Austria being the hosts, we were in for a big night (it had already been a long day… whats a few more hours).</p>

<p>We headed out to the old city, about a 15min walk from where we were staying. A large Fan Zone had been set up in the city’s main square with two huge screens, a stage, and of course heaps of beer tents.</p>

<p>We decided to relax a little (after our huge day) before venturing back to the Fan Zone. We found a beer garden not far away from the center of town that was showing the game on plasma screens, grabbed a table and some dinner and relaxed with a few local Austrian beers for a few hours.</p>

<p>After half time we decided to head up to the main square and join in the other fans to watch the last half of the game. At this stage Spain was up 1-0 over Germany.</p>

<p>The main square was packed to capacity – there were people everywhere. The game was eventually won by Spain – to the delight of many in attendance. The crowd erupted in cheering and chanting. It has been over 20 years since Spain has won a title at the European level – so this was a big thing.</p>

<p>We vacated the square and began heading home – along with the majority of the German supporters.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/saltzberg-sound-of-music-tour-1.jpg" alt="" title="Salzberg - Sound of Music Tour 1" />
We were up early again the following morning as we had booked onto the 9am Sound of Music tour around Salzburg. The tour took us through much of Salzburg, and showed us many of the places that were used in the filming of the movie – Laura was in her element. The tour also took us out of town to the lakes district, and to some absolutely beautiful scenery. We had a short stop over in a small town with just enough time to have a coffee and sample some apple strudel, which was divine, before getting back on the bus and heading back to Salzburg to complete the tour.</p>

<p>We spent the afternoon exploring the Salzburg castle/fortress, which is the predominant feature in Salzburg, and can be seen from nearly anywhere in the city.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/saltzberg-beer-garden.jpg" alt="" title="Salzburg - Beer Garden" />
After this we headed to another beer garden – this one was run by monks, and was established in 1621. They had a pretty impressive setup. Walking in from the street the place doesn’t look like much – then you wander down some passage ways, and steps and come to a corridor with local food stalls. Further on you emerge into a massive beer garden.</p>

<p>We relaxed in the beer garden for the afternoon and sampled some of the monks beer, which is drawn straight from the barrel, and was, as with most beer over here, great.</p>

<p>Later we headed home to get some rest, as we were off early in the morning to Venice, Italy! The start of the Italian leg of our journey.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Guten tag! Willkommen in Deuchland</title>
	  <link>/guten-tag-willkommen-in-deuchland</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-06-19T05:23:05+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/guten-tag-willkommen-in-deuchland</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/bremen-becks.jpg" alt="" title="Bremen - Becks" />
So we are in Germany now – having arrived from Tampere, Finland into Bremen the other day. We have been in Bremen for the last few days, staying with friends (Suzanne &amp; Richard) in their lovely apartment which is just a short ride from the heart of Bremen.</p>

<p>We quickly realised that the Euro 2008 Cup (soccer) is in progress – and on the night we arrived Germany were facing off with Austria (the hosts), and it was a must win type of situation for Germany to allow them to progress through.</p>

<p>Suzanne and Richards apartment is conveniently located above a nice little bar – so we headed down stairs with some of their work friends for meal and a few drinks to watch the game – ending with Germany winning 2-0… needless to say the Germans were rather pleased!</p>

<p>The next day we headed out into Bremen on bikes we borrowed from Suzanne &amp; Richard. This was th best way to get around town – everyone here rides, and the place is so flat its perfect (it also lets you cover more ground).</p>

<p>Coming into Bremen we new little about the city – we quickly discovered that its the home of the Beck’s Brewery (and this stuff is cheaper than water over here – 4 Euros for 3 liters at the supermarket!). Its also the home of the Traveling Musicians from the Brothers Grimm fairy tail (a donkey, dog, cat and a rooster).</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/bremen-city.jpg" alt="" title="Bremen - City" />
The old town has some classically beautiful German architecture – Churches, and other lovely old style buildings.</p>

<p>Riding into Bremen, we hit the Market Platz – basically the center of town, with lovely cafe’s, buildings, and markets all skirting the main plaza.</p>

<p>After a quick coffee, we continued riding in search of the Beck’s brewery. This was a little way up the river – unfortunately tours are only made on Thursday’s and Fridays.</p>

<p>We road back towards town down the side of the river – heading past the many Bier Gartens (Beer Gardens) that are on the riverside. This got the better of us (well me), and we decided to take 5 in one of the Bier Gartens and sample some of the local beers – oh and a freshly cooked pretzel or two.</p>

<p>The following day we were lucky enough to have a local guide, Suzanne, to show us around. As it happened, Suzanne was actually meant to be heading out of town for a few days on business, but the night before she was dew to fly out she had a minor dental emergency with one of her teeth cracking – needless to say this put a halt to her business trip.</p>

<p>So while it worked out fairly we for us, it wasn’t so good for Suzanne – but a quick trip to the dentist the next morning she returned minus a tooth, and with a rather numb mouth.</p>

<p>Suzanne took us out to the Burgerpark – a huge area of park land in Bremen – which was great. We pulled up at a little cafe in the middle of the park for some lunch, and a chance to sample some more of the local beer – Green Lemon (basically lime) Becks, Weissbier and Banana Juice (which was actually reasonably good), and the local favorite Haake Becks.</p>

<p>Later we walked back into town and sampled some of the local torte (cake) – my favorite being the German baked cheese cake!</p>

<p>We then toured through some of the small cute side streets in Bremen before heading home.</p>

<p>Today we have jumped on the ICE (Inter City Express) train from Bremen to Berlin (about 3 hours). These trains are awesome – traveling at over 250km on a smooth as silk line it barely any noise from outside – there is defiantly something to be said for good German engineering!</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
