<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title></title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>The Sound of Salzburg</title>
	  <link>/blog//the-sound-of-salburg</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-07-01T10:00:34+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blog//the-sound-of-salburg</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/blog//assets/images/saltzberg-at-night.jpg" alt="" title="Salzburg at night" />
We pick-up here were our last post left off. We have arrived in Salzburg – and its the night of the Euro Cup 2008 final, Germany -v- Spain. With Austria being the hosts, we were in for a big night (it had already been a long day… whats a few more hours).</p>

<p>We headed out to the old city, about a 15min walk from where we were staying. A large Fan Zone had been set up in the city’s main square with two huge screens, a stage, and of course heaps of beer tents.</p>

<p>We decided to relax a little (after our huge day) before venturing back to the Fan Zone. We found a beer garden not far away from the center of town that was showing the game on plasma screens, grabbed a table and some dinner and relaxed with a few local Austrian beers for a few hours.</p>

<p>After half time we decided to head up to the main square and join in the other fans to watch the last half of the game. At this stage Spain was up 1-0 over Germany.</p>

<p>The main square was packed to capacity – there were people everywhere. The game was eventually won by Spain – to the delight of many in attendance. The crowd erupted in cheering and chanting. It has been over 20 years since Spain has won a title at the European level – so this was a big thing.</p>

<p>We vacated the square and began heading home – along with the majority of the German supporters.</p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/saltzberg-sound-of-music-tour-1.jpg" alt="" title="Salzberg - Sound of Music Tour 1" />
We were up early again the following morning as we had booked onto the 9am Sound of Music tour around Salzburg. The tour took us through much of Salzburg, and showed us many of the places that were used in the filming of the movie – Laura was in her element. The tour also took us out of town to the lakes district, and to some absolutely beautiful scenery. We had a short stop over in a small town with just enough time to have a coffee and sample some apple strudel, which was divine, before getting back on the bus and heading back to Salzburg to complete the tour.</p>

<p>We spent the afternoon exploring the Salzburg castle/fortress, which is the predominant feature in Salzburg, and can be seen from nearly anywhere in the city.</p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/saltzberg-beer-garden.jpg" alt="" title="Salzburg - Beer Garden" />
After this we headed to another beer garden – this one was run by monks, and was established in 1621. They had a pretty impressive setup. Walking in from the street the place doesn’t look like much – then you wander down some passage ways, and steps and come to a corridor with local food stalls. Further on you emerge into a massive beer garden.</p>

<p>We relaxed in the beer garden for the afternoon and sampled some of the monks beer, which is drawn straight from the barrel, and was, as with most beer over here, great.</p>

<p>Later we headed home to get some rest, as we were off early in the morning to Venice, Italy! The start of the Italian leg of our journey.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Munich...Beer halls, beer halls, beer halls... Oh and tripod!</title>
	  <link>/blog//munich-beer-halls-beer-halls-beer-halls-oh-and-tripod</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-06-29T10:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blog//munich-beer-halls-beer-halls-beer-halls-oh-and-tripod</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/blog//assets/images/munich-beer-halls.jpg" alt="" title="Munich - Beer Halls" />
So we left Prague, and the Czech Republic behind us (and the train made it this time!) for the spoils of Munich (passing back through Dresden, to minimize our ticket cost, and maximize our use of the Eurail pass).</p>

<p>Straight out, Munich is a lovely city – beer halls, parks &amp; gardens, old buildings, and lovely people (well almost all of them – we will get to this later).</p>

<p>Our first night in Munich consisted of us checking into our accommodation, about 5 min walk from the station, then heading out for a bite to eat and something to drink. Walking the streets for the first time, not knowing were we were going it wasn’t long, literally 2 minutes, before we stumbled on our first Munich beer hall… We need look no further.</p>

<p>So dinner consisted of a shared plate of mozzarella and tomato salad, and a few beers, followed by a shared plate of farm style chicken and pommies (chips) and the ultimate Munich style beer – 1 Mass – the 1 liter stein.</p>

<p>The beer hall had the obligatory screening of the Euro Cup (Russia v Spain) which made for a great atmosphere.</p>

<p>The following day (yes, we didn’t drink too much!) we jumped on a free bike tour of Munich. This took us around many of the sights, including… yes a beer garden.</p>

<p>At the start of the tour, the guide was looking for a volunteer – and then I got that feeling… he’s going to pick me! And he did. I was the lucky ‘volunteer’. I was given the job of ‘bringing up the rear’. I had to make sure that we left no one behind, and that the group didn’t straggle – as they often can with people taking photos, etc. I was given authority – although this was somewhat diminished by my new name, ‘Ass Man’.</p>

<p>On the tour we ventured through the main park area of Munich, which is loved and adored by the locals – and by none more than the local nudists (yes it is legal to be nude in the middle of Munich!).</p>

<p>The park featured as one of our stops, and being a warm day, there were plenty of people about – and one in particular (a nudist), who our guide dubbed ‘Tripod’, and we soon found out why! He was not shy of tourists, and actually appeared to enjoy the tourist presence, in amongst his odd 10m jog (for no apparent reason), or throw of the frisbee (to himself). Needless to say we quickly moved on before he became any more friendly.</p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/munich-river-surfing.jpg" alt="" title="Munich - River Surfing" />
The park is also the home to the Munich river surfers. The river that flows through the park was altered artificially by US solders after the war to entertain themselves. The river was temporarily stopped, and a large piece of concrete put in place to cause a large pressure wave in the river – which provides quite good surfing. It was pretty amazing to see people jumping in on the wave one after another surfing it, and bailing to let the next on.</p>

<p>Once the tour finished, I relinquished my authority (and my nick name), and we headed out to explore more of Munich on our own – first stop the market to pick up some local food for lunch (bread, dip, pickled octopus, olives, tomato and mozzarella salad, and strawberries). We managed to entertain ourselves for the rest of the day – ending up at the famous Hofbrauhaus beer hall, where we indulged in a few beers to end the day.</p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/dachau.jpg" alt="" title="Dachau" />]
The following day was a somewhat more sombre affair – we took a tour out to Dachau where the first Nazi concentration camp was located. The tour was a pretty sobering experience, and really told a strong story. While Dachau was not an actual ‘death camp’, in the same sense that Auschwitz was, many thousands of people did die there – mainly through disease, undernourishment, overwork, suicide, or a combination of many other factors.</p>

<p>One of the most amazing pieces of information we were told on the tour that helped to cement how bad conditions would have been was in regard to the camp population size. The camp was originally built and designed to hold 2,500 people – however when it was liberated at the end of the war, over 30,000 people were found in the camp.</p>

<p>Dachau was the first concentration camp – it was the model for all others. It was located just out of Munich, as Munich was the center of all things Nazi – it was where the Nazi party began, and where Hitler first started his political (for want of a better word) career.</p>

<p>Dachau has now been converted into a museum and memorial ground to both survivors and those who died.</p>

<p>Later that afternoon we began planing for our exit from Munich, and Germany the following day – we were headed for Salzburg, Austria, although there was a dilemma… We had just realised that the Neuschwanstein castle (the one Disney modeled their snow white castle on) was in German, and just over 2 hours from Munich!</p>

<p>What to do… We were pretty exhausted after a couple of big days on the run. If we were to get to Neuschwanstein it would mean we would have a very long and tight schedule for the next day in order to see the castle and get to Salzburg (the complete opposite direction).</p>

<p>After much deliberation, we eventually came to the decision not to go – we were too exhausted… 10min later though… we though ‘were here now. Lets get some value out of this Eurail ticket’. So we were off – the decision was final, and the following schedule locked in:</p>

<ul>
  <li>05.50: leave Munich by train to Fussen (the closest train station to the castle)</li>
  <li>08.00: Arrive in Fussen and catch a bus to the town at the base of the hill where the castles were</li>
  <li>08:30: Buy tickets to the castle tour (start 9.45am). Wander around the town and other castle for a while</li>
  <li>09.00: Catch a horse drawn carriage up the hill to the Neuschwanstein castle</li>
  <li>09.45: Start the castle tour</li>
  <li>10.30: Rip round the remainder of the castle quickly, before quickly trying to get back down the mountain to catch the bus back to Fussen – which we missed, and through our original schedule out!</li>
  <li>11.15: Catch the next bus back to Fussen</li>
  <li>12.05: Catch the train from Fussen back to Munich</li>
  <li>14.17: Arrive in Munich. Sprint to our lockers and get our packs. We had 5 minutes to catch the next train to Salzburg</li>
  <li>14.22: The train to Salzburg pulls out of Munich Hbf – with us aboard!</li>
  <li>16:45: Arrive in Salzburg!</li>
</ul>

<p>We had made it. While it was a bloody long day, we had managed to cram a lot in, and it was defiantly worth making the effort to see the castles – they look like they are straight out of a fairy tail!</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Guten tag! Willkommen in Deuchland</title>
	  <link>/blog//guten-tag-willkommen-in-deuchland</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-06-18T19:23:05+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/blog//guten-tag-willkommen-in-deuchland</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/blog//assets/images/bremen-becks.jpg" alt="" title="Bremen - Becks" />
So we are in Germany now – having arrived from Tampere, Finland into Bremen the other day. We have been in Bremen for the last few days, staying with friends (Suzanne &amp; Richard) in their lovely apartment which is just a short ride from the heart of Bremen.</p>

<p>We quickly realised that the Euro 2008 Cup (soccer) is in progress – and on the night we arrived Germany were facing off with Austria (the hosts), and it was a must win type of situation for Germany to allow them to progress through.</p>

<p>Suzanne and Richards apartment is conveniently located above a nice little bar – so we headed down stairs with some of their work friends for meal and a few drinks to watch the game – ending with Germany winning 2-0… needless to say the Germans were rather pleased!</p>

<p>The next day we headed out into Bremen on bikes we borrowed from Suzanne &amp; Richard. This was th best way to get around town – everyone here rides, and the place is so flat its perfect (it also lets you cover more ground).</p>

<p>Coming into Bremen we new little about the city – we quickly discovered that its the home of the Beck’s Brewery (and this stuff is cheaper than water over here – 4 Euros for 3 liters at the supermarket!). Its also the home of the Traveling Musicians from the Brothers Grimm fairy tail (a donkey, dog, cat and a rooster).</p>

<p><img src="/blog//assets/images/bremen-city.jpg" alt="" title="Bremen - City" />
The old town has some classically beautiful German architecture – Churches, and other lovely old style buildings.</p>

<p>Riding into Bremen, we hit the Market Platz – basically the center of town, with lovely cafe’s, buildings, and markets all skirting the main plaza.</p>

<p>After a quick coffee, we continued riding in search of the Beck’s brewery. This was a little way up the river – unfortunately tours are only made on Thursday’s and Fridays.</p>

<p>We road back towards town down the side of the river – heading past the many Bier Gartens (Beer Gardens) that are on the riverside. This got the better of us (well me), and we decided to take 5 in one of the Bier Gartens and sample some of the local beers – oh and a freshly cooked pretzel or two.</p>

<p>The following day we were lucky enough to have a local guide, Suzanne, to show us around. As it happened, Suzanne was actually meant to be heading out of town for a few days on business, but the night before she was dew to fly out she had a minor dental emergency with one of her teeth cracking – needless to say this put a halt to her business trip.</p>

<p>So while it worked out fairly we for us, it wasn’t so good for Suzanne – but a quick trip to the dentist the next morning she returned minus a tooth, and with a rather numb mouth.</p>

<p>Suzanne took us out to the Burgerpark – a huge area of park land in Bremen – which was great. We pulled up at a little cafe in the middle of the park for some lunch, and a chance to sample some more of the local beer – Green Lemon (basically lime) Becks, Weissbier and Banana Juice (which was actually reasonably good), and the local favorite Haake Becks.</p>

<p>Later we walked back into town and sampled some of the local torte (cake) – my favorite being the German baked cheese cake!</p>

<p>We then toured through some of the small cute side streets in Bremen before heading home.</p>

<p>Today we have jumped on the ICE (Inter City Express) train from Bremen to Berlin (about 3 hours). These trains are awesome – traveling at over 250km on a smooth as silk line it barely any noise from outside – there is defiantly something to be said for good German engineering!</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
