<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title></title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Rome to Aix-en-Provence via Genoa (by train)</title>
	  <link>//1rome-to-aix-en-provence-via-genoa-by-train</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-30T04:02:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//1rome-to-aix-en-provence-via-genoa-by-train</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="back-in-rome">Back in Rome</h2>

<p>We arrived back into Rome on Wednesday evening (29th July) in reasonable time after having left San Lupo in the early afternoon - immediately after the main mass and precession of the statue of San Lupo through the streets.</p>

<p>It was good to have made it back to San Lupo again, although not a lot looks to have changed since our last visit in 2008 - but its beautiful during the festival with all the lights lining the streets at night.</p>

<p>The drive from San Lupo back to Rome was fairly straightforward and un-eventful - exactly how I like my drives in Italy to be. The auto strade makes for fairly good driving - especially on the tolled sections. It’s always the last 25-30min of navigation into your final destination that becomes stressful.</p>

<p>Once we got back to Rome, we unpacked and checked into our hotel. We decided it was best to return the rental cars that night instead of hanging onto them for the night and risking damage in the car park - or worse a 2.5hr wait to return the car like it took to pick it up.</p>

<p>The rental car return was as you would expect, and as we had hoped - simple and straightforward - and in under 20min we had returned both cars and were headed for the Fumancino taxi rank. We are now well acquainted with where the correct taxi rank is after our late and frustrating entry into Rome about a week and a bit ago.</p>

<p>After a brief walk we find the taxi rank with 2 taxi’s sitting waiting for us - what could be better? Well it could be better if one of the taxi drivers was actually interested in doing their job - but rather we find one taxi with 3 young people in it, 2 young ladies in the front and a young gentlemen in the back. The other taxi was empty.</p>

<p>Apparently the two young (and somewhat attractive) ladies in the front of the occupied taxi had gained the intrigue of the young male driver - and none of them were interested in us.</p>

<p>So we wait… We lean against the empty taxi making it very obvious that we would like to go somewhere… still nothing. Eventually a third taxi turns up with an older gentlemen who is willing to help us - however when he see’s two other taxi’s he decides to enquire why we didn’t get one of them. The problem became quickly obvious to him. A few rushed words of Italian and one of the girls jumps out of the front of her taxi and asks where we want to go.</p>

<p>The young guy in the back seat jumps out and we pile into the girls taxi and we are off - one of the young ladies at the wheel and her friend in the front passenger seat - apparently coming along for the ride.</p>

<p>The banter in the front seats was endless - and obviously very interesting based on the facial expressions of the friend. Her attention was fixated on what the driver had to say - and thanks to some interpretation from Albert (Laura’s dad) we were able to follow the general gist of the conversation.</p>

<p>Well… apparently the driver had just broken up with her boyfriend Francesco… and it went on… and on… and on…</p>

<p>We eventually got to the hotel and 20 Euro later we parted ways with the young ladies and left them to their less than interesting conversation about Francesco.</p>

<p>The rest of the evening was fairly laid back - and after dinner we all turned in for an early night as we wanted to check out of the hotel as early as possible to maximise our time in Rome in the morning.</p>

<h2 id="whirlwind-tour-of-rome">Whirlwind tour of Rome</h2>

<p>After an early breakfast the next morning we met our arranged shuttle van that was taking us, and our many bags, into Rome Termini train station. It was a long drive into Rome in the traffic, but we eventually made it. As it was still early we decided to check our bags in at the train station baggage holding area and head out for some brief sight seeing.</p>

<p>Given the limited time we had, we thought our whirlwind tour should hit some of the major attritions - St. Peters Basilica and the Spanish Steps - conveniently both located on train line ‘A’.</p>

<p>We got out to St. Peters Basilica in no time at all - and the air-conditioning in the Metro trains was a nice escape from the heat and humidity of the Roman streets.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/1fe0e-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Walking up and into St. Peter’s Basilica was quite a sight. It was only us, and 10,000 other people - quite tranquil really…</p>

<p>The line to get into the basilica wound its way right around the main piazza. We didn’t join the queue and were satisfied to observe from the outside and snap a few pics.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/900c1-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We then started to head back to the train and popped out at the Spanish Steps for a few pics before heading back to Rome Termini to pick up our bags and catch our train onto Genoa.</p>

<h2 id="train-to-genoa">Train to Genoa</h2>

<p>The train trip was great - although we managed to score the carriage with only partially working air conditioning - still it was better than none at all.</p>

<p>The train journey was relaxing. Put the mind in neutral for a while and enjoy the scenery passing by. A welcome change to being behind the steering wheel - and to be able to walk up to the bar carriage and have a few quite beers made it even better.</p>

<p>The train line follows the west coast of Italy - so there were a lot of brilliant views of the Mediterranean and the towns and cities along the way.</p>

<p>We arrived into Genoa in the early evening, and checked into our hotel, which was just a short walk across the piazza from the station. On this trip, Genoa is simply a stop over for us - so after a quick dinner (which was absolutely beautiful) we all headed off to bed to get up at 4:30am to catch our next train at 6am.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/bf391-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="the-early-train-to-aix-en-provence">The early train to Aix-en-Provence</h2>

<p>Friday morning we were all up early and met down stairs at 5:15am packed and ready to leave. We had arranged to check out the night before so just needed to drop our door keys with reception and leave. A short walk across the piazza got us back to the train station.</p>

<p>Today we had three trains to catch. The first was a regional train from Genoa (Italy) to Ventimiglia (Italy). The second was also a regional train from Ventimiglia (Italy) to Nice (France). The last was a fast TGV from Nice to our final destination Aix-en-Provence (France).</p>

<p>The challenges we had ahead were related to management of our baggage on and off the trains. Our bags at this point are quite heavy, and numerous. Getting on the first train was reasonably straight forward given the early hour - but as our journey moved on, more and more people joined the train making it more complicated to manage the placement of the bags.</p>

<p>The regional trains don’t stop for long at each station either - so we needed to be prepared - with out bags - ahead of time so we could quickly get everyone (and their bags) off before the train needed to move on.</p>

<p>The first stop was to be the most challenging with only 11 min to change trains - including locating the next train, its platform, and lugging all our bags down and back up the platform steps. Luckily we arrived in about 5 min ahead of schedule that gave us some more time. In the end, the change over was quite straightforward and we had plenty of time.</p>

<p>The next two legs of the journey were also straightforward - however we did notice an increased level of chaos at the French train stations as opposed to the Italian stations. Both Nice and the TGV station in Aix-en-Provence were packed and totally chaotic.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/481a6-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After arriving into the TGV station in Aix-en-Provence (about 20km out of the main city), we started looking for a taxi. Simply you would think - and in reality it was - unless you had two 30kg bags in tow plus a 10kg backpack, 4 other travellers and your 18-month-old son. Apparently we had arrived into platform 1. Taxis were at platform 3. This meant lugging bags up two flights of stairs onto the mezzanine level that allowed you to walk over the train line to platform 3. Most of the stations lifts were out of order. We found one that got us half way up, and reduced the stair climb by 50% - but we had to carry the bags the rest of the way.</p>

<p>The taxi was very easy - we needed two and in about 20min we arrived safely into Aix-en-Provence and at our accommodation - all very tired after the long day, and many stairs we had to carry bags up and down.</p>

<p>We did notice the much more comfortable temperature in Aix-en-Provence. Closer to 28c, and much cooler in the later evening when we ventured out for a walk up the nearby Cours Mir Abeau - a long and grand street which has night markets, cafes and restaurants all the way up. It made for a very nice and relaxed evening walk.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/3d18f-img_7660.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/ea41f-img_7661.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/7b590-img_7737.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/8ed35-img_7739.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/8a6c0-img_7759.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/99010-img_7768.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/e9736-img_7770.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/fe418-img_7772.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/db8db-img_7775.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/bf9aa-img_7778.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Alberobello</title>
	  <link>//alberobello</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-25T09:52:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//alberobello</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Saturday we packed up and checked out of the villa. It was sad to leave as its been an absolutely great time and very relaxing, but everything must come to an end and we must move on to our next destination - Alberobello.</p>

<p>Alberobello is in the south east of Italy, not far from Bari - but it’s roughly 750km from where we currently are in Siena, which will make for a long days driving. Furthermore we need to swing by Rome airport to pickup Maddie (Laura’s sister) who will be joining the travelling group for a few weeks.</p>

<p>Also while we are at Rome airport we will continue to try and track down our lost baggage - one small backpack and Archie’s pram. Franco - our host at the villa - was fantastic in assisting us dealing with the lost baggage people at Rome airport via phone - although even he could only do so much. In the end we had settled for the baggage (once it was finally located) to be sent to Rome airport where we would collect it.</p>

<p>We jumped into the cars and headed south toward Rome - a 2.5hr drive. We arrived with plenty of time to meet Maddie’s plane - so while the others waited for its arrival, Laura and I headed off to lost baggage.</p>

<p>Collecting lost baggage requires you to first pass through security - which luckily we had navigated the week prior and were now well prepared for what was ahead. We made it through security quickly and headed for the lost baggage desk - essentially a small makeshift trestle table in the back corner of the arrivals and baggage collection area of the airport.</p>

<p>It appears lost luggage at Rome airport is common - 3 of our group alone lost luggage. While Laura waited in line to be served (by the one person manning the desk), I decided to do a ‘walk-through’ of the mountains of luggage that were setup in makeshift racks and piles surrounding the desk. There would literally be enough ‘lost luggage’ here to fill an entire plane.</p>

<p>Somehow I managed to very quickly stumble across our backpack. Done. After a quick inspection to verify it was ours, the pack was securely on my back and I was off again in search for the pram. Given our experiences at Rome airport to date, I wasn’t overly surprised about the lack of security around the lost luggage. Its surprising really that anything is every returned to its rightful owners under this system (and I hesitate to call it a system).</p>

<p>After some good searching I still could not locate the pram - although there was a mountain of other ‘lost or unclaimed’ prams. For a brief moment, I pondered - should I just grab one and get out of here? I thought better of it. I would hate to be responsible for another family not being able to find their pram - although I really doubt anyone would have stopped me if I had decided to go through with it.</p>

<p>Heading back to Laura (who was still in the queue), I diverted to the bathrooms. It was here I quickly realised what must have been the ultimate downfall of the great Roman empire - water, marble floors and thongs (or sandals back in the day) DO NOT MIX. The simple act of placing a thong bearing foot onto a small puddle of water on highly polished marble tile in the men’s bathrooms resulted in a torrent of blood streaming from my shin as it slammed into the underneath of the sinks.</p>

<p>Being as eco-friendly as they are, Rome airport do not have paper hand towels in the bathrooms, only hand dryers. This left me with a scrap of napkin I was fortunate enough to have left in my pocket to mop up the blood. The napkin was soon soaked, so I headed back to Laura to see if she had something to assist. Another scrap of napkin - however this time it helped to reduce the flow of blood to a trickle… a trickle that in the heat continued for the next hour until I returned to the car - shin still aching.</p>

<p>Maddie’s plane arrived in late, which set our already tight schedule and long drive to Alberobello back further. We eventually hit the road and onto the auto strade - only 5.5hrs to go.</p>

<p>Before we set out we agreed to stop along the way to stretch our legs and for a toilet break - however as we got further and further into the drive I suspect we all just wanted to be there and the thought of stopping was not on anyone’s minds. Eventually we did stop about an hour out of Alberobello - our bladders could not take it any longer and the two drivers (Albert and I) really needed to get out from behind the wheel for a stretch and refresh. Our pit stop lasted about 30min, and we were back on the road again. Our ETA had now pushed out form 8:30pm to just after 9pm… we were going to be arriving in the dark once again. This meant handing full control of navigation over to our TomTom - who at this point we had nicknamed Slip’n Jimmy (a Better Call Saul reference) - because of all the dodgy routes he had taken us on to this point.</p>

<p>Laura decided to call ahead and let the accommodation know we would be arriving late - they were fine with this but told us to call them as we arrived into town as their was a festival on and half of the roads were closed off - this was really going to put Slip’n Jimmy (and the rest of us) to the test.</p>

<p>We were guided into town by the TomTom (Slip’n Jimmy), and to its credit we got a fair way in - but the closed roads were the end of us. It was a little stressful to say the least - in the dark, in a strange town, with no idea of where we were meant to be. Turn left, turn right, or continue on? Did it matter?</p>

<p>We eventually found ourselves parked in front of the main church in town - fortunately out of the way enough to allow all the other traffic to move through without us interrupting them. We called the accommodation again and they walked up to meet us and guided us in.</p>

<p>We eventually made it to our accommodation - some of the UNESCO heritage listed Trulli’s which Alberobello and the region are well known for.</p>

<p>After a long and somewhat stressful drive, we turned in for the night - it was now almost 11pm.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/6f559-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The next morning we all regrouped and headed down to the main town piazza to a restaurant where our breakfast had been arranged. In the light of day the town, and the Trulli houses were amazing - unlike anything we had seen before.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/0a641-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The remainder of the day was spent exploring Alberobello, the various districts of Trullis, the Trulli church, and the largest Trulli in town.<br />
That night the town filled up again and the roads closed - the festival that had stopped us driving into town the night before was still running. We sat on the edge of the main piazza, enjoyed dinner and watched the people flow through.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/a7781-img_7208.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/6cb1d-img_7212.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/bdd4d-img_7218.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/b1265-img_7220.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/42bb8-img_7233.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/cd596-img_7243.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/c144a-img_7238.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/da6bd-img_7243.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/0d7e9-img_7256.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/cb19d-img_7268.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/f085f-img_7281.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/4e1d9-img_7297.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/937af-img_7299.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/e26f1-img_7282.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/d2ac2-img_7283.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/b8217-img_7305.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/7a7c7-img_7283.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/7e73f-img_7328.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Family Vacation - Let's Begin</title>
	  <link>//the-family-vacation-lets-begin</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-18T22:20:25+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//the-family-vacation-lets-begin</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So… The last few day have been hectic and somewhat full-on to say the least.</p>

<p>I was wanting to sit down at the end of each day, with a beer or a glass of wine, and take some time out to update the blog - however given the events of the past few days, this was not possible.</p>

<p>I now find myself sitting in a villa in Tuscany on morning one, a cup of tea and a piece of toast at my side, looking out across an open field towards some bushland, writing about the events leading to this point.</p>

<h2 id="prepare-for-departure">Prepare for Departure</h2>

<p>Early Wednesday evening we find ourselves arriving at Melbourne Airport to catch our flight from Melbourne to Dubai later that night.</p>

<p>At this point spirits are high, although there is some nervousness amongst the traveling group - especially those of us who are travelling with little ones for the first time - however we are well ahead of schedule so nothing can stop us now… Well except maybe a 1.5 hour wait to check in!!</p>

<p>Granted we are not ‘regular’ international travellers, but in the occasional adventures we have never encountered a check-in queue like this one before.</p>

<p>Rapidly we go from being ‘comfortably on-time’ to dancing ridiculously close to the line that results in missing a flight. Needless to say the significantly longer than expected check-in process upped the anxiety levels amongst the travelling group - and we still had to clear customs and get to the gate.</p>

<p>Luckily things flowed somewhat more ‘smoothly’ from that point. We got to the gate with (some) time to spare (they had started calling for us) and promptly took our seats.</p>

<p>The next 14hrs hours of flight is made up of brief naps, resettling our little ones - who were incredibly good throughout the flight - and putting the Wiggles on high repetition on the in-flight entertainment system when the little ones became unsettled.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/560b3-img_0600.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Needless to say we all arrived safely in Dubai just slightly ahead of schedule.</p>

<p>Having come from the ‘Antarctic vortex’ that saw Melbourne temperatures average around 12c, Dubai was defiantly a contrast with its 38c heat.</p>

<h2 id="dubai">Dubai</h2>

<p>Arriving in at Dubai airport, we disembarked the plane and made our way to the arrivals hall - it was here we realised we had forgotten Tiger - Archie’s little teddy bear. We headed back to the plane where the staff were very helpful and assisted us in reuniting Archie with his little Tiger teddy.</p>

<p>This brief interlude had allowed the rest of the passengers to clear customs - meaning a very quick passage through customs ourselves.</p>

<p>A brief (air-conditioned) drive from the airport takes us to our hotel where we settled, had some breakfast and set out to explore the local area. We hired a driver from the hotel who helped to show us around more of Dubai. This was great until our (very tired) son decided he wanted to run to find mum - at which point he tripped on his own feet and face planted into the stone pavers.</p>

<p>A blood nose and a bloody mouth and a lot of tears meant this was the end of our excursions for the afternoon. We were initially fearful Archie may have broken his front teeth - the blood made it very difficult to see what ws actually going on. By the time we arrived back at our hotel, the little guy was laughing and eating again - so we were confident that his teeth were ok.</p>

<p>The swimming pool was the next destination - and a welcome relief from the heat of the Dubai streets.</p>

<p>We all settled in for an early night as we were flying out early in the morning.</p>

<h2 id="dubai-to-rome-via-london">Dubai to Rome via London</h2>

<p>Dubai is where our travelling group split up. Most of our family were travelling with Emerites and were able to fly direct from Dubai to Rome. Unfortunately our ticket required us to transit via London - which was going to make for a very long day.</p>

<p>The flight to London was fairly uneventful, and again Archie was amazing - we were now getting comments from nearby passengers about how good he had been.</p>

<p>London’s Heathrow airport was busy to say the least - and a place I would like to avoid in future with an 18 month old (unfortunately we will be back there before the trip is complete).</p>

<p>4 hours of doing nothing in Heathrow airport is truly about as exciting as it sounds. It makes the long haul plane ride look great in comparison.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/aaee0-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>10 minutes before our boarding gate was to be announced all of the airport departure screens went out. This made for a more lively time - with everyone suddenly rushing the information desks in panic trying to find out what departure gate they needed to get to. We joined in the chaos and eventually found out what our next move was to be - Gate B32.</p>

<p>So off we went, and made it to the gate well ahead of time - given the flight was delayed… more waiting.</p>

<p>We eventually boarded our flight to Rome - with Archie sound asleep on my shoulder… this is where tired little ones in an airport has it advantages - straight to the front of the line and first to board.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/e7d32-img_0603.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="when-in-rome---wait">When in Rome - Wait</h2>

<p>Archie slept the whole flight to Rome, and Laura had a few cat-naps. We arrived into Rome after 11pm. Our plane pulled up to the air bridge and there we waited a further 30min, as the tug had misaligned the plane with the aero-bridge and no one was able to get off - and the tug had to be recalled to realign the plan.</p>

<p>After getting off the plane we cleared passport control easily and headed for the baggage area. Here we waited further. We collected most of our bags, but after further waiting, we soon realised we were not getting all of them. Our pram was missing, and so was a small backpack. Both were more comfort items rather than essential - but their loss was painful none the less. It was well after midnight by this time.</p>

<p>We headed for the lost baggage desk - only to find out that they could not help us and that we needed to speak directly with the airline desk… unfortunate no-one was able to tell us where that was.</p>

<p>So at 12:30am we find ourselves walking through the various terminals of Rome international airport in search of either someone who could help, or the airlines desk. We found neither - and after a very long day of travel and not much sleep we decided to just head for the hotel.</p>

<p>Our hotel was only a short drive from the airport - it should be simple to walk out the front of the airport and hail a cab - at least you would think… After a further 45min of walking between the various cab ranks, we eventually found where we were meant to be - unfortunately there were no cabs around.</p>

<p>At this point it seemed nothing was going our way - including a call to the hotel for assistance. Apparently there is a ‘local law’ that prohibits the hotel from calling some very tired travellers with an 18 month old in tow, a cab at 1am.</p>

<p>Eventually, after some more waiting, a cab did appear and we made it to the hotel. Check-in was simple but at 2am - to discover that we didn’t have a cot in the room (as requested in our booking) was pretty much the not-so-perfect end to a not-so-perfect day.</p>

<p>Grumpy, hot and tired we started to work on settling in for the evening to get some sleep. We stripped Archie off to get him ready to settle in for sleep - turning our back for a minute we hear a barely audible ‘thud’ - turning back around we see Archie has dropped a big poo in the middle of the floor. We looked at each other and all we could do was laugh. In one small action, our 18 month old had littery summed up our day - SHIT.</p>

<p>We cleaned up both Archie and the floor and headed to bed. 4 hours later we were re-united with our travelling group over breakfast.</p>

<p>Venturing out of the hotel a brave few of us headed back to the airport to try and track down our lost baggage. We received an email from the airline overnight indicating the pram had made it to London but thats where it stayed. Our backpack was still in Dubai.</p>

<p>Tracking down the airline lost baggage desk was no easier in the light of day than it was at midnight. We eventually found it and joined the queue at the makeshift trestle table in the back of the arrivals hall.</p>

<p>We decided to split up and start multi-tasking. Laura stayed at the lost property desk while I headed for the rental car office.</p>

<p>I could dedicate a whole blog post to the experience of renting a car at Rome airport. Not an experience I would like to repeat and would recommend against for anyone else travelling to Rome. It can only be described as pure chaos and I will keep it breif.</p>

<p>Getting to the car rental office at around 10:30am, I print a ticket which give me my place in the queue… Number 64 - they were currently serving 32. Not long to wait… like buggery!</p>

<p>I actually struggle to understand how it would even be possible to make the process of renting a car to take so long. People may not believe me if I say I did not leave the rental car office with key in hand until 1pm. It was truly insanity - and I really get the feeling this is ‘normal’.</p>

<h2 id="the-road-to-tuscany">The Road to Tuscany</h2>

<p>Arriving back to the hotel with our rental car, we met up with the rest of our family group and headed off toward Siena.</p>

<p>Driving in Italy for the first time was interesting to say the least - but we adapted pretty quickly, and the drive was actually reasonably straight forward down the auto strata.</p>

<p>We made it into Siena and picked up Mum from the train station. She piled into the other car (a 9 seater mini-van) and we headed out of Siena toward the Villa near Sovicille.</p>

<p>Pulling up at the Villa was exciting - and very picturesque - it was everything we had imagined it would be (pictures coming).</p>

<p>We unpacked and settled in for the evening - a brief swim helped relieve the heat of the afternoon. We dinned outside on a big long table with the family.</p>

<p>Let the holiday begin! Compared to the events of the past few days, the relaxing tranquility of the villa and surrounds is very enjoyable.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>When in Rome...</title>
	  <link>//when-in-rome</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-07-17T23:11:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//when-in-rome</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/rome.jpg" alt="" title="Rome" />
We made it to Rome after a pleasant few days in the Cinque Terre. Almost immediately we noticed that it was a little warmer here in Rome, away from the cooler comfort of the coast that Cinque Terre offered.</p>

<p>We are staying in a simple B&amp;B - its not quite what you would classify as a B&amp;B in Australia, but I guess it meets the necessities, we get a bed, and we get breakfast. To be honest, its actually quite nice. The room is huge, and while there are no cooking facilities we do have access to a fridge.</p>

<p>For out first full day in Rome we ventured out to the Colosseum, a short walk from where we are staying. We also wondered around and through many of the surrounding sights, including the Palatine, the Roman Forums, the Trevi Fountain and the Spanish Steps.</p>

<p>On our second day we ventured out to the Vatican city - not that the Pope is there… he’s in Australia at the moment! Anyway, we took in most of the Vatican’s sights, including the huge St. Peters Basilica, the Sistine Chapel, and St. Peters square.</p>

<p>The Vatican has so much to offer, and many beautiful works of art - it was well worth a day there.</p>

<p>Today we wandered down the road to the Basilica di San Giovanni- which was the first Christian Basilica built in Rome. The Basilica also serves as Rome’s cathedral, and is also the Pope’s seat as the Bishop of Rome. The Basilica is also the home to many ancient and religious relics, including the heads of both St. Peter and St. Paul.</p>

<p>Rome has been fascinating, and well worth the time.<br />
We continue our trek south tomorrow as we move onto Naples for a few days.</p>

<p>We have now put up some of our photos from Rome - however, as we left our iPod cable in Rome, we may not be putting too many more photos up in the near future! Have to wait until we get home - lucky its not long now.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
