<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title></title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>An evening in Siena</title>
	  <link>//an-evening-in-siena</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-20T03:48:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//an-evening-in-siena</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Today we decided to venture out to nearby Siena for the evening - its too hot (38-40c) to be out and about with the kids during the heat of the day, and for us the time is much better spent cooling off and relaxing by the pool.</p>

<p>From our villa, Siena is roughly a 20km drive - initially through scenic hills which make for some exciting driving with blind hair-pin corners, narrow stone wall lined roads and stretches of tree lined avenues. Winding down from the hills takes us through a number of small townships and into a valley with paddocks full of sunflowers and others with freshly cut hay.</p>

<p>Driving into Siena was fairly straightforward and we followed our instincts and headed toward the train station and shopping centre to find car parking. Once in Siena the driving became a little more hectic but still manageable.</p>

<p>After missing the turn for the shopping centre car park there was a decision to be made - pull a u-turn right here right now or keep going and find a roundabout. We decided to find a roundabout - considering we were travelling in convoy with a 9-seater van. Unfortunately however for some other travellers, they did not make the same decision. As we rounded the round-about we saw their car pull a u-turn right in front of another oncoming car. The outcome was inevitable - and fortunately for us we were far enough away to avoid any involvement.</p>

<p>Entering the underground car park was a breeze in our small Fiat 500L, but a little more technical for those in the larger 9 seater van - we made it in however without a hitch.</p>

<p>From the shopping centre we headed up (and up, and up, and up) the length of escalators and travelators that take you up to the walled city of Siena.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/cc20f-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We headed in toward the centre of the city to find the Piazza del Campo. We found a nice restaurant on the edge of the Piazza and settled in for a refreshing few glasses of wine and a lovely dinner. By this time the heat of the day had passed and a lovely light breeze was moving through the Piazza - making for a wonderfully enjoyable evening.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/09864-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/bdf31-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After dinner we continued to explore the streets of Siena. The cooler air of the evening made this much more enjoyable, and the streets looked lovely in the light of dusk.</p>

<p>We wandered up to the Siena Cathedral (the Duomo), a spectacular black and white marble cathedral right in the middle of Siena. Unfortunately it was closed at night so we couldn’t go inside, but the architecture of the building from the outside was exceptional.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/ab054-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/eaed9-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>By this time the kids were ready for home, so we walked back through Siena and headed for the shopping centre that would lead us back to the card.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/2df6b-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/c953d-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Heading home from Siena was a challenge to say the least. Navigating in near pitch darkness for 20km in the Tuscan countryside means you need total confidence in your TomTom - something we didn’t have.</p>

<p>We started out well and the road seemed familiar, although only having travelled it once it was difficult to tell - although when the lines on the road disappeared and the TomTom started recommending washed out goat tracks with a 45 degree incline as ‘the best route’ we started to have our concerns.</p>

<p>Trusting to our own instincts we decided against the recommendations of the TomTom and doubled back to a main road. From here we were able to find our way back to more familiar areas before we resumed use of the not-so-trusted TomTom. While I am sure the TomTom would have got us to where we needed to go, I think it failed to recognise the Fiat 500L wasn’t equipped with a 4x4 pack.</p>

<p>Now travelling confidently through familiar areas we were well on the way to home - then TomTom recommended a right hand turn. Moments after taking the turn we recalled we had avoided this turn on a previous occasion in preference for a better road - however in the pitch dark of night this decision was not so simple to make. We travelled along the road, and while rough we eventually guessed where it would lead us to and were confident we were still on the right track (and it was a track).</p>

<p>Eventually we re-joined the main road again and continued confidently on - until we rounded a hairpin corner and a cat darted across the road and… thud… went under the car before any of us realised what had happened. We continued on and eventually made it safely home - over an hour after we had left Siena…</p>

<p>Needless to say a few beers were required to settle the stress levels from the drive home. We all decided that maybe we should impose the ‘Cinderella Policy’ and make sure we are home before dark next time - although where would the fun be in that…</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/59019-img_6524.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/c1929-img_6528.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/77fec-img_6536.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/bebdb-img_6572.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/a92c3-img_6575.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/9df29-img_6579.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>San Lupo</title>
	  <link>//san-lupo</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-07-31T09:37:19+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//san-lupo</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="//assets/images/sanlupo-poster.jpg" alt="" title="San Lupo - Poster" />
We arrived into Benevento by train from Naples, and were greeted warmly by Laura’s relations Sandra and Lorenzo Ciaglia. We then drove for about 30min up into the hills to our destination, the small town of San Lupo.</p>

<p>We arrived right at the beginning of the three day festa, where the town honors its patron saint - San Lupo.</p>

<p>During the festa the town comes alive, and is dressed up with lights all up and down the main street and through the main piazza in front of the church.</p>

<p>The three days of the festa include various religious and civic events, including various mass’s honoring San Lupo, public concerts of classical music in the piazza, fireworks, processions through the town and the obligatory markets and food stalls.</p>

<p>Of course, it wouldn’t be an Italian fiesta without food - and there was defiantly no lack of that - Laura and myself generally returned to our accommodation most afternoons(for siesta), and again at night, stuffed to the brim with traditional Italian foods including, various pasta, pepperoni (stuffed peppers), breads, prosciutto, cheeses, parmigiana, vino, and beautiful home made limoncello - to mention just a few.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/san-lupo-village.jpg" alt="" title="San Lupo - Village" />
The town of San Lupo was absolutely beautiful. The main part of the town is essentially a medieval village with tiny cobble stone streets that wind up and down the side of a mountain.</p>

<p>Now days the town sprawls out a little with more modern, free standing houses surrounding the original village - but we were surprised at how modern the interiors of the older houses in the village actually were.</p>

<p>The piazza is the main focal point of the town (as with most European towns and villages) with a church at one end, a bar at the other and houses all around.</p>

<p>The first two nights we stayed about 1km out of town (an easy walk), in a newly opened B&amp;B which was great. On our last night (the festa night) we stayed in town with some family friends, Alex &amp; Berel, who were a lovely older, English speaking, couple.</p>

<p>We participated in most of the events of the festa, including two of the main mass’s, and all three of the town processions - 1 to commemorate the beheading of a bandit who used to raid the town a few centuries ago, the next to bless the local oil and grain, and the final one which was the longest and wound its way through almost every street in the town was to honor San Lupo.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/san-lupo-festa1.jpg" alt="" title="San Lupo - Festa" />
The final procession follows immediately after a large mass given by the Bishop. The procession is made up of a marching band at the front, who are followed by many candle holders (who have made offerings to San Lupo). They are followed by another marching band and a group of men who carry the statue of San Lupo on their shoulders. Finally, anyone else who wishes to participate in the procession (this included us) walk behind.</p>

<p>This final procession took about an hour - on quite a warm day - and wound its way through almost every street in San Lupo (all of the main ones at least). It starts and ends at the church.</p>

<p>Many of the candle bearers walk the entire procession in bare feet.</p>

<p>Once the procession has completed (about 2.30pm), everyone retires to their houses for the festa lunch. Sandra had prepared an absolute feast for us - antipasto, lasagna, scallopini, pepperoni, parmigiana, fruit, and cake.</p>

<p>The festa night included continuous music in the piazza from two bands, and ended around 1.30am with a fireworks display - which we were lucky enough to watch from Alex &amp; Beryl’s roof top terrace.</p>

<p>All in all San Lupo was fantastic. Initially we were not sure what to expect - we have passed through some small towns before and had been given a poor impression - San Lupo was unlike any where in Italy we had been before. Everyone knew who we were and that we were Australians (or Kangaroos as we were sometimes referred to) visiting for the festa on our Honeymoon.</p>

<p>San Lupo was defiantly a highlight for Italy, and even our entire trip. It was a fantastic way to spend our last few days in Italy - we will leave with fond memories of this little town, and the people we met there.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
