<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title></title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>(Almost) Fathers Day</title>
	  <link>//almost-fathers-day</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2013-09-01T10:05:36+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//almost-fathers-day</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So to day was Fathers Day.</p>

<p>Apparently I qualify in the “soon to be category” (lets call it almost fathers day) and was able to bask in the moment for a while..</p>

<p>While we didn’t do anything quite as exciting as visiting Tropical Fruit world today we did hit Bris-Vagas…</p>

<p>Couldn’t have been a better day. The weather was perfectly warm. Roaming the south bank region of Brisy is amazing on days like this - even more so when you find a bar with Matilda Bay beer dominating the taps of the week - and pints for $8.50.</p>

<p>After spending most of our day in the south bank region of Brisy, we headed back to the shelter and serenity of Kingscliff.</p>

<p>An afternoon walk on the beach, a few quiet bevies if the suite while coming up to speed on Breaking Bad (apparently we are the only people on this rock not to have seen it yet!), and I now find myself sipping an Asahi while waiting for my take-away Thai order - what better way to finish my “Almost Father’s Day”.</p>

<p>So it’s back home tomorrow.. Reality always catches up with you at some point. Apparently Melbourne has been having some brilliant weather while we have been away. Spring is here and summer is not far away.</p>

<p>Sorry to think that this will likely be our last trip away for a few years. Time to focus on family!</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20130901-200603.jpg" alt="20130901-200603.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20130901-200618.jpg" alt="20130901-200618.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20130901-200626.jpg" alt="20130901-200626.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Just wandering around</title>
	  <link>//just-wandering-around</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2013-08-31T07:20:37+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//just-wandering-around</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Today’s plans evolved organically with more of a “why not” attitude rather than specific planning.</p>

<p>We headed down to Byron Bay early this morning - apparently we took the scenic route. Getting lost is sometime where you find the best hidden local secrets - we turned up an old sewage treatment plant that was now reclaimed land and a hangout for bird watchers… Not exactly the jackpot.</p>

<p>Eventually we put our trust in the GPS and made it into Byron. With nothing really we wanted to do or see, we simply relaxed and walked the streets. We dropped into one of the local cafes for a caffeine hit - street buskers outside playing some great mellow surfy tunes to reinforce the towns mellow vibe.</p>

<p>After a good few hours spent wandering Byron, we decided to check out Nimbin… A little further away than we thought - but a pleasant drive west all the same.</p>

<p>Arriving in Nimbin was almost exactly like what you would imaging it. Entering the town there are fences painted in every colour of the rainbow, hearts handing from almost everything, and people trying to sell you a deal every two feet.</p>

<p>Within the first 5 minutes of stepping out of the car we had been offered a deal no less than 10 times - I guess we fitted the target demographic more so than the bus load of elderly citizens who had pulled up at the same time.</p>

<p>The sweet smell of special herbs floated through the air - especially strong in and around the Hemp Embassy.</p>

<p>We popped into the Nimbin pub for bit of lunch - we were strangely hungry after our short walk around the town…</p>

<p>The Nimbin pub turned out quite a good meal, and sitting on the back deck soaking up the sun was just about as good as it gets.</p>

<p>From Nimbin we headed back to Kingscliff to spend the few remaining hours of sunshine sitting poolside with cocktails.</p>

<p>As chance would have it, we stumbled over Tropical Fruit World - here was my chance to buy up big on all those exotic tropical fruits I have never tried before. We ended up with a chewing gum fruit, chocolate pudding fruit and a custard apple.</p>

<p>Having now tried these exotic fruits, I can tick them off my bucket list and move on - unlikely to return. While they were not unpleasant they did not wow me either and I am certain I could live out the remainder of my days without another sampling of them.</p>

<p>Tomorrow will bring an early start as we plan to head into Brisbane for the morning before spending the arvo poolside again.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20130831-171931.jpg" alt="20130831-171931.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20130831-171950.jpg" alt="20130831-171950.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20130831-172002.jpg" alt="20130831-172002.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20130831-172012.jpg" alt="20130831-172012.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20130831-172023.jpg" alt="20130831-172023.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Chill out in Kingscliff ("The Babymoon")</title>
	  <link>//chill-out-in-kingscliff-the-babymoon</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2013-08-30T05:36:43+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//chill-out-in-kingscliff-the-babymoon</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>It’s a cold, wet and windy Melbourne morning… 3am, and the alarm goes off.</p>

<p>Rather than the normal roll over and press snooze reaction, I find myself rising quickly and competing with Laura to be first in line for the shower. I’m not quick enough out of the blocks though and find myself beaten.</p>

<p>This is no normal Friday morning… This is the start of our loooong weekend together… Some would call it our “Babymoon” on the account its likely to be our last getaway together before Laura is due early next year.</p>

<p>We are both excited - hence the unnatural levels of enthusiasm and alertness at 3am.</p>

<p>Peppers Salt Resort in Kingscliff on the northern beaches of New South Wales is our destination - a quiet, relaxing destination somewhere between Byron Bay and the Gold Coast.</p>

<p>An uneventful, but early, flight finds us landed in the Gold Coast - on what is turning out to be a spectacular day of sunshine and warmth (the two things we have both missed over the Melbourne winter).</p>

<p>We arrive at Peppers and immediately enter “chill out” mode. Laura crashes on the bed to catch up on some sleep from our early start, and I find myself in the pool side bar enjoying a refreshing Ale from the local Pickled Pig Brewery…</p>

<p>Time for another…<br />
Lets wait to see what tomorrow brings.</p>

<p><img src="//assets/images/20130830-155136.jpg" alt="20130830-155136.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
