<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title></title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>San Gimignano</title>
	  <link>/san-gimignano</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-23T19:52:00+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/san-gimignano</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>On Friday (24th July) we set out early and took a road trip to San Gimignano - about an hour or so away from where we were staying at the villa.</p>

<p>San Gimignano is a medieval hill top fortified city and is renowned for its many towers - everywhere you look there are more.</p>

<p>While San Gimignano is one of the smaller towns we have visited, it is by far one of the more beautiful. The medieval architecture combined with towers in every direction makes for post-card photos everywhere you look.</p>

<p>As you walk through the main city gates, the narrow cobble stone roads lead you up toward the main Piazza. This initial street is lined with shops (for the tourists).</p>

<p>We stopped in a nice little cafe to grab a snack and a coffee before heading into the main piazza. The cafe was full to the brim with beautiful biscotti and chocolates - so we had to sample a few - my favourite was a biscotti covered in pine nuts with a moist almond meal centre.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1bac2-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/03945-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Continuing our wandering through the main shopping street I recognised a deli that I visited last time I was here (in 2008). Last time I was here I drooled over the look, smell and taste of the local wild boar salami - however, for whatever reason, didn’t buy any…</p>

<p>I didn’t make that mistake twice, and sampled all of the varieties of salami that were on offer before making my purchase of some Salami Cinghiale (wild boar).</p>

<p>After a good wandering through the various shops in San Gimignano, we eventually made it up to the main piazza. From there we continued on walking to the highest point in the city and up onto some of the ancient walls for a spectacular view of both the city and the countryside that surrounds it.</p>

<p>You definitely get a sense for why cites were built on top of the hills in this part of Italy - you can see for miles around - and San Gimignano with its fortifications and many towers would have been well placed to defend itself from any foe.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/5d889-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fa2ba-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After some more wandering around the ancient city, we started to head back for the car - but not without stopping off at ‘the best gelato’ place in the world. Funnily enough there was another gelato store right across the street that was proclaiming the same thing.</p>

<p>The gelato was nice all the same - lemon and pistachio.</p>

<p>Once we made it back to the cars, our next stop was Siena train station. Today was Rod and Caz’s last day with us before heading back home - and they had to catch their train from Siena.</p>

<p>a short trip from San Gimignano got us into Siena in no time and had Rod and Caz on the train as scheduled.</p>

<p>We headed back home to the villa to spend the rest of the afternoon in the pool - until an afternoon thunderstorm rolled in and bought the rain with it. We didn’t complain though as it also bought the temperature down from about 38c to a much more bearable 25c.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/49291-img_7085.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/5a520-img_7089.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/b0d89-img_7111.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/7cc71-img_7114.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f8e09-img_7129.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ee982-img_7149.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/35e05-img_7150.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2d31b-img_7153.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/38609-img_7156.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/0fb03-img_7157.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f4445-img_7158.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/b9169-img_7162.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Vino e Pizza</title>
	  <link>/vino-e-pizza</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-22T19:51:00+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/vino-e-pizza</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So… We have been without Internet access for a few days, and the blog posts have been limited as a result of this. I have a lot to catch up on and as Internet access becomes available - and I have time - new blog posts will begin to show up.</p>

<p>Today (Thursday 23rd July) was a bit of a lay-day - we hung out at the villa and swam to keep cool. After lunch (and siesta) we decided to check out a local winery, <a href="http://www.trecciano.it/it/13/home.aspx">Tenuta di Trecciano</a>, which is about 5km down the road for some tastings.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/7fe0e-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The wine on offer was produced from grape varieties and in the styles typical of the local Tuscan region. We tried 1 white, 4 reds and a desert wine - all rather nice - and we ended up purchasing 4 of their bottles, 1 white and 3 of the red. Interestingly we were encouraged to drink the desert wine by dunking a piece of almond biscotti into it - it made for quite a delicious combination.</p>

<p>The owner took us for a walk through their facility so we could see the wine being bottled.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/31cd5-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After finishing up our tastings we continued on to a local ceramics factory we had found online. It took a bit of finding, but after 3 laps around the block we made it. Most of their ceramic work appeared to be targeted at the bulk commercial market - however they did sell certain pieces direct to the public from their factory.</p>

<p>The owner showed us upstairs to his show room - a small, hot, room full of nicely decorated ceramic plates, cups, bowls, verses, and platters. We all found a few pieces we liked and made our purchases before heading back home.</p>

<p>Once back home we all decided to jump in the pool again to cool off ahead of the Pizza night we had arranged with the owner. The owner and his staff were starting to make preparations - fetching wood for the Pizza oven, making the dough and preparing the ingredients for the toppings.</p>

<p>Watching the Pizza oven in operation was interesting - and extremely hot. The chef worked the oven like a master and put together some of the best pizza we have eaten - delicate thin crust, and extremely tasty toppings.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fab5c-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/cbaac-image.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>As with the night of the feast a few nights before, we started with a selection of antipasti. This was then followed by a procession of pizzas - one after the other - the continued to come until we could eat no more. We did finish the night with a Nutella pizza and some Limoncello however.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/34b67-img_6838.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/09ebb-img_6843.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/97013-img_6846.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/79477-img_6848.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/a3362-img_6851.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/72a63-img_6853.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2a2bc-img_6867.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/15c7e-img_6868.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fe108-img_6984.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/7b443-img_6996.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/75c73-img_7017.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/7432a-img_7062.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/74bc8-img_7064.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f9dd0-img_7079.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/830d8-img_7081.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/815b6-img_7082.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>A Tuscan Feast</title>
	  <link>/a-tuscan-feast</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-21T07:56:00+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/a-tuscan-feast</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>We arranged with Franco, the owner of the villa, to prepare us a traditional Tuscan feast (an option available to anyone staying at the villa) on Tuesday evening.</p>

<p>We all wanted to celebrate arriving in Tuscany and to mark the start of our holiday, but Tuesday was also Mum’s birthday - and what better excuse to kick back, relax and enjoy some awesome Tuscan food and wine together.</p>

<p>In the early afternoon the chefs and other staff arrived to start preparing the evening meal. The long table on the lawn was set, along with a large accompanying table which would hold all the food for the evening meal.</p>

<p>As the afternoon turned into early evening, we found ourselves heading out onto the lawn to enjoy a few beers in the cooler evening air - waiting in anticipation for the meal to commence.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/a6252-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Before dinner we come together for the obligatory group photo, inclusive of our custom made holiday t-shirts - “Pruscino &amp; Pals - Italian vacanza 2015”.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/5080c-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The feast commenced with an opening toast of Prosseco and a delightful selection of antipasti.</p>

<p>We all sat down and the feast commenced. Following the antipasti dishes were two types of pasta. The first pasta dish was a pappardelle bussola, amd was absolutely amazing, and easily the best pasta dish I have ever eaten. The flavours were amazing, with (what I believe to be) a local mushroom and wild boar ragu.</p>

<p>Following the pasta dishes we had cooked meats, including pork, chicken, sausage as well as roast potatoes, garlic and mixed salads. Needless to say the vino flowed throughout the entire meal.</p>

<p>Desert followed which included both amoretti cake and gelato.</p>

<p>Soon after dinner, given it was Mum’s birthday, we bought out some locally made biscotti, panforte and coffee as well as icy cold Limoncello.</p>

<p>We invited Franco (the owner) and his cooking team down to join us for a few drinks and thanked them for the wonderful feast. Franco bought out some grappa (grappa di pinot), which was passed around for all to enjoy.</p>

<p>Needless to say the evening was extremely enjoyable and went on long into the night - at least until the grappa and vino ran out.</p>

<p>I would really recommend to anyone staying at the <a href="http://www.podereincrociati.it">Podere Incrociati</a> villa to take-up the option of having the Tuscan feast cooked for them - it has been a real highlight.</p>

<p>On Thursday night we have arranged to have a pizza night - so the chefs will be back to cook up a storm on the wood fired pizza oven.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ced31-img_6681.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1904a-img_6682.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8ee31-img_6684.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/997a7-img_6685.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/bca84-img_6687.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/22cff-img_6688.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/18ce9-img_6689.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/241ab-img_6690.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/9e7f8-img_6691.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e4d2b-img_6697.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/023d6-img_6699.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/9b16e-img_6700.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/59f9c-img_6701.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/6008a-img_6703.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>An evening in Siena</title>
	  <link>/an-evening-in-siena</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-20T13:48:00+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/an-evening-in-siena</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Today we decided to venture out to nearby Siena for the evening - its too hot (38-40c) to be out and about with the kids during the heat of the day, and for us the time is much better spent cooling off and relaxing by the pool.</p>

<p>From our villa, Siena is roughly a 20km drive - initially through scenic hills which make for some exciting driving with blind hair-pin corners, narrow stone wall lined roads and stretches of tree lined avenues. Winding down from the hills takes us through a number of small townships and into a valley with paddocks full of sunflowers and others with freshly cut hay.</p>

<p>Driving into Siena was fairly straightforward and we followed our instincts and headed toward the train station and shopping centre to find car parking. Once in Siena the driving became a little more hectic but still manageable.</p>

<p>After missing the turn for the shopping centre car park there was a decision to be made - pull a u-turn right here right now or keep going and find a roundabout. We decided to find a roundabout - considering we were travelling in convoy with a 9-seater van. Unfortunately however for some other travellers, they did not make the same decision. As we rounded the round-about we saw their car pull a u-turn right in front of another oncoming car. The outcome was inevitable - and fortunately for us we were far enough away to avoid any involvement.</p>

<p>Entering the underground car park was a breeze in our small Fiat 500L, but a little more technical for those in the larger 9 seater van - we made it in however without a hitch.</p>

<p>From the shopping centre we headed up (and up, and up, and up) the length of escalators and travelators that take you up to the walled city of Siena.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/cc20f-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We headed in toward the centre of the city to find the Piazza del Campo. We found a nice restaurant on the edge of the Piazza and settled in for a refreshing few glasses of wine and a lovely dinner. By this time the heat of the day had passed and a lovely light breeze was moving through the Piazza - making for a wonderfully enjoyable evening.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/09864-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/bdf31-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After dinner we continued to explore the streets of Siena. The cooler air of the evening made this much more enjoyable, and the streets looked lovely in the light of dusk.</p>

<p>We wandered up to the Siena Cathedral (the Duomo), a spectacular black and white marble cathedral right in the middle of Siena. Unfortunately it was closed at night so we couldn’t go inside, but the architecture of the building from the outside was exceptional.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ab054-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/eaed9-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>By this time the kids were ready for home, so we walked back through Siena and headed for the shopping centre that would lead us back to the card.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2df6b-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/c953d-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Heading home from Siena was a challenge to say the least. Navigating in near pitch darkness for 20km in the Tuscan countryside means you need total confidence in your TomTom - something we didn’t have.</p>

<p>We started out well and the road seemed familiar, although only having travelled it once it was difficult to tell - although when the lines on the road disappeared and the TomTom started recommending washed out goat tracks with a 45 degree incline as ‘the best route’ we started to have our concerns.</p>

<p>Trusting to our own instincts we decided against the recommendations of the TomTom and doubled back to a main road. From here we were able to find our way back to more familiar areas before we resumed use of the not-so-trusted TomTom. While I am sure the TomTom would have got us to where we needed to go, I think it failed to recognise the Fiat 500L wasn’t equipped with a 4x4 pack.</p>

<p>Now travelling confidently through familiar areas we were well on the way to home - then TomTom recommended a right hand turn. Moments after taking the turn we recalled we had avoided this turn on a previous occasion in preference for a better road - however in the pitch dark of night this decision was not so simple to make. We travelled along the road, and while rough we eventually guessed where it would lead us to and were confident we were still on the right track (and it was a track).</p>

<p>Eventually we re-joined the main road again and continued confidently on - until we rounded a hairpin corner and a cat darted across the road and… thud… went under the car before any of us realised what had happened. We continued on and eventually made it safely home - over an hour after we had left Siena…</p>

<p>Needless to say a few beers were required to settle the stress levels from the drive home. We all decided that maybe we should impose the ‘Cinderella Policy’ and make sure we are home before dark next time - although where would the fun be in that…</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/59019-img_6524.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/c1929-img_6528.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/77fec-img_6536.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/bebdb-img_6572.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/a92c3-img_6575.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/9df29-img_6579.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Villa Podere Incrociati</title>
	  <link>/villa-podere-incrociati</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-19T13:46:54+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/villa-podere-incrociati</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So after a long few days of travel, we arrived yesterday evening at what will become our home for the next week - villa <a href="http://www.podereincrociati.it">Podere Incronciati</a> - a traditional Tuscan villa built in 1840 about 20km outside of Siena.</p>

<p>We were welcomed by the owner and offered complimentary wine, cheese, olives, fruit and other nibbles - which was much appreciated after the drive from Rome.</p>

<p>After settling on rooms, we unpacked before hitting the pool to cool down and relax for a bit - which was great in the 38c heat.</p>

<p>Later in the evening we all sat down at a long table outside on the lawn as a group and enjoyed dinner and a few drinks, with a light cooling breeze coming across the field.</p>

<p>We have only been here for a day so far, but we are already totally relaxed - mission accomplished.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8eb0f-img_6436.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/f741c-img_6437.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/b97a5-img_6438.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/3993a-img_6440.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/17ff4-img_6441.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/97021-img_6444.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/69585-img_6442.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/fa2eb-img_6445.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/6783d-img_6454.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ec6fb-img_6456.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/7d973-img_6450.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/b7059-img_6460.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/71ab3-img_6454.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/a9138-img_6467.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8fdd3-img_6471.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/7730f-img_6460.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/31c6e-img_6474.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/01fc3-img_6477.jpg" alt="" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Family Vacation - Let's Begin</title>
	  <link>/the-family-vacation-lets-begin</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-19T08:20:25+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/the-family-vacation-lets-begin</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So… The last few day have been hectic and somewhat full-on to say the least.</p>

<p>I was wanting to sit down at the end of each day, with a beer or a glass of wine, and take some time out to update the blog - however given the events of the past few days, this was not possible.</p>

<p>I now find myself sitting in a villa in Tuscany on morning one, a cup of tea and a piece of toast at my side, looking out across an open field towards some bushland, writing about the events leading to this point.</p>

<h2 id="prepare-for-departure">Prepare for Departure</h2>

<p>Early Wednesday evening we find ourselves arriving at Melbourne Airport to catch our flight from Melbourne to Dubai later that night.</p>

<p>At this point spirits are high, although there is some nervousness amongst the traveling group - especially those of us who are travelling with little ones for the first time - however we are well ahead of schedule so nothing can stop us now… Well except maybe a 1.5 hour wait to check in!!</p>

<p>Granted we are not ‘regular’ international travellers, but in the occasional adventures we have never encountered a check-in queue like this one before.</p>

<p>Rapidly we go from being ‘comfortably on-time’ to dancing ridiculously close to the line that results in missing a flight. Needless to say the significantly longer than expected check-in process upped the anxiety levels amongst the travelling group - and we still had to clear customs and get to the gate.</p>

<p>Luckily things flowed somewhat more ‘smoothly’ from that point. We got to the gate with (some) time to spare (they had started calling for us) and promptly took our seats.</p>

<p>The next 14hrs hours of flight is made up of brief naps, resettling our little ones - who were incredibly good throughout the flight - and putting the Wiggles on high repetition on the in-flight entertainment system when the little ones became unsettled.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/560b3-img_0600.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Needless to say we all arrived safely in Dubai just slightly ahead of schedule.</p>

<p>Having come from the ‘Antarctic vortex’ that saw Melbourne temperatures average around 12c, Dubai was defiantly a contrast with its 38c heat.</p>

<h2 id="dubai">Dubai</h2>

<p>Arriving in at Dubai airport, we disembarked the plane and made our way to the arrivals hall - it was here we realised we had forgotten Tiger - Archie’s little teddy bear. We headed back to the plane where the staff were very helpful and assisted us in reuniting Archie with his little Tiger teddy.</p>

<p>This brief interlude had allowed the rest of the passengers to clear customs - meaning a very quick passage through customs ourselves.</p>

<p>A brief (air-conditioned) drive from the airport takes us to our hotel where we settled, had some breakfast and set out to explore the local area. We hired a driver from the hotel who helped to show us around more of Dubai. This was great until our (very tired) son decided he wanted to run to find mum - at which point he tripped on his own feet and face planted into the stone pavers.</p>

<p>A blood nose and a bloody mouth and a lot of tears meant this was the end of our excursions for the afternoon. We were initially fearful Archie may have broken his front teeth - the blood made it very difficult to see what ws actually going on. By the time we arrived back at our hotel, the little guy was laughing and eating again - so we were confident that his teeth were ok.</p>

<p>The swimming pool was the next destination - and a welcome relief from the heat of the Dubai streets.</p>

<p>We all settled in for an early night as we were flying out early in the morning.</p>

<h2 id="dubai-to-rome-via-london">Dubai to Rome via London</h2>

<p>Dubai is where our travelling group split up. Most of our family were travelling with Emerites and were able to fly direct from Dubai to Rome. Unfortunately our ticket required us to transit via London - which was going to make for a very long day.</p>

<p>The flight to London was fairly uneventful, and again Archie was amazing - we were now getting comments from nearby passengers about how good he had been.</p>

<p>London’s Heathrow airport was busy to say the least - and a place I would like to avoid in future with an 18 month old (unfortunately we will be back there before the trip is complete).</p>

<p>4 hours of doing nothing in Heathrow airport is truly about as exciting as it sounds. It makes the long haul plane ride look great in comparison.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/aaee0-img.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>10 minutes before our boarding gate was to be announced all of the airport departure screens went out. This made for a more lively time - with everyone suddenly rushing the information desks in panic trying to find out what departure gate they needed to get to. We joined in the chaos and eventually found out what our next move was to be - Gate B32.</p>

<p>So off we went, and made it to the gate well ahead of time - given the flight was delayed… more waiting.</p>

<p>We eventually boarded our flight to Rome - with Archie sound asleep on my shoulder… this is where tired little ones in an airport has it advantages - straight to the front of the line and first to board.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/e7d32-img_0603.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="when-in-rome---wait">When in Rome - Wait</h2>

<p>Archie slept the whole flight to Rome, and Laura had a few cat-naps. We arrived into Rome after 11pm. Our plane pulled up to the air bridge and there we waited a further 30min, as the tug had misaligned the plane with the aero-bridge and no one was able to get off - and the tug had to be recalled to realign the plan.</p>

<p>After getting off the plane we cleared passport control easily and headed for the baggage area. Here we waited further. We collected most of our bags, but after further waiting, we soon realised we were not getting all of them. Our pram was missing, and so was a small backpack. Both were more comfort items rather than essential - but their loss was painful none the less. It was well after midnight by this time.</p>

<p>We headed for the lost baggage desk - only to find out that they could not help us and that we needed to speak directly with the airline desk… unfortunate no-one was able to tell us where that was.</p>

<p>So at 12:30am we find ourselves walking through the various terminals of Rome international airport in search of either someone who could help, or the airlines desk. We found neither - and after a very long day of travel and not much sleep we decided to just head for the hotel.</p>

<p>Our hotel was only a short drive from the airport - it should be simple to walk out the front of the airport and hail a cab - at least you would think… After a further 45min of walking between the various cab ranks, we eventually found where we were meant to be - unfortunately there were no cabs around.</p>

<p>At this point it seemed nothing was going our way - including a call to the hotel for assistance. Apparently there is a ‘local law’ that prohibits the hotel from calling some very tired travellers with an 18 month old in tow, a cab at 1am.</p>

<p>Eventually, after some more waiting, a cab did appear and we made it to the hotel. Check-in was simple but at 2am - to discover that we didn’t have a cot in the room (as requested in our booking) was pretty much the not-so-perfect end to a not-so-perfect day.</p>

<p>Grumpy, hot and tired we started to work on settling in for the evening to get some sleep. We stripped Archie off to get him ready to settle in for sleep - turning our back for a minute we hear a barely audible ‘thud’ - turning back around we see Archie has dropped a big poo in the middle of the floor. We looked at each other and all we could do was laugh. In one small action, our 18 month old had littery summed up our day - SHIT.</p>

<p>We cleaned up both Archie and the floor and headed to bed. 4 hours later we were re-united with our travelling group over breakfast.</p>

<p>Venturing out of the hotel a brave few of us headed back to the airport to try and track down our lost baggage. We received an email from the airline overnight indicating the pram had made it to London but thats where it stayed. Our backpack was still in Dubai.</p>

<p>Tracking down the airline lost baggage desk was no easier in the light of day than it was at midnight. We eventually found it and joined the queue at the makeshift trestle table in the back of the arrivals hall.</p>

<p>We decided to split up and start multi-tasking. Laura stayed at the lost property desk while I headed for the rental car office.</p>

<p>I could dedicate a whole blog post to the experience of renting a car at Rome airport. Not an experience I would like to repeat and would recommend against for anyone else travelling to Rome. It can only be described as pure chaos and I will keep it breif.</p>

<p>Getting to the car rental office at around 10:30am, I print a ticket which give me my place in the queue… Number 64 - they were currently serving 32. Not long to wait… like buggery!</p>

<p>I actually struggle to understand how it would even be possible to make the process of renting a car to take so long. People may not believe me if I say I did not leave the rental car office with key in hand until 1pm. It was truly insanity - and I really get the feeling this is ‘normal’.</p>

<h2 id="the-road-to-tuscany">The Road to Tuscany</h2>

<p>Arriving back to the hotel with our rental car, we met up with the rest of our family group and headed off toward Siena.</p>

<p>Driving in Italy for the first time was interesting to say the least - but we adapted pretty quickly, and the drive was actually reasonably straight forward down the auto strata.</p>

<p>We made it into Siena and picked up Mum from the train station. She piled into the other car (a 9 seater mini-van) and we headed out of Siena toward the Villa near Sovicille.</p>

<p>Pulling up at the Villa was exciting - and very picturesque - it was everything we had imagined it would be (pictures coming).</p>

<p>We unpacked and settled in for the evening - a brief swim helped relieve the heat of the afternoon. We dinned outside on a big long table with the family.</p>

<p>Let the holiday begin! Compared to the events of the past few days, the relaxing tranquility of the villa and surrounds is very enjoyable.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Only days away</title>
	  <link>/only-days-away</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-11T03:19:25+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/only-days-away</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>After almost 18 months of planning, we are now quickly approaching our departure date. Our bags are packed (well mostly), and we are ready to go.</p>

<p>In the past Laura and I have either travelled solo or more typically together as a couple - not this time however…</p>

<p>Since we last had the opportunity to travel abroad, a few things have changed… mainly the arrival of our son (now 18 months old) who will be heading off with us to experience the wonders of the big wide world.</p>

<p>Not only will our son be travelling with us, but a fair part of our immediate families are also joining - some 17 people at last count.</p>

<h2 id="so-where-exactly-are-we-all-headed">So where exactly are we all headed?</h2>

<p>The large (main) group are all set to converge on a villa we have booked in Tuscany - somewhere near Sienna. There we plan to enjoy each others company as we soak in the warmth of the Tuscan sun, and feast on delicious hearty Italian food and wine.</p>

<p>Most of us will also continue on travelling to the south of Italy to arrive in San Lupo - the small town where Laura’s family are originally from.</p>

<p>Following our time in Italy, most of the group will head back home, while we continue on heading into the north of Italy then spending some time in France before heading across to the U.K. where the European leg of our journey will end.</p>

<p>Finally we will head across the pond and spend some time in the U.S. before heading for home.</p>

<p>So so really exciting time ahead of us. The hardest part now is watching the clock slowly tick down to our departure date…</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Under the Tuscan Sun</title>
	  <link>/under-the-tuscan-sun</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2008-07-09T05:30:55+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/under-the-tuscan-sun</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="/assets/images/tuscany.jpg" alt="" title="Tuscany" />
The transport strike has finished, and so has our forced day of relaxation in Bologna (yes… we did absolutely nothing, and loved it!) - we grabbed the early train out of town and headed for Certaldo in Tuscany.</p>

<p>Certaldo is a cute little town south west of Florence (Firenze), and north of Siena. We are staying in a beautiful agriturismo B&amp;B, come self contained shared apartment - it has everything, free mountain bikes, kitchen &amp; fridge, internet, etc, and is immaculate.</p>

<p>The owners only speak Italian, so this is helping us to hone our skills - and Laura is actually doing quite well.</p>

<p>We spent the afternoon in San Gimignanao, which is a short train and bus ride from here. Its an absolutely beautiful old town that is enclosed in huge fortifications, and has many towers. The town itself appears to be rather touristy, however this doesn’t take away from its beauty at all.</p>

<p>I managed to pick us up some local wild boar salami, which we are looking forward to sampling very shortly.</p>

<p>Tomorrow we are planning to head off into Florence for the day, and then hopefully explore the old town of Certaldo in the afternoon.</p>

<p>If you want to check out where we are staying, their we site is - <a href="http://www.ilpianigiano.it">http://www.ilpianigiano.it</a></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
