<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lucasmodrich.github.io/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>Stories and experiences from our occasional travels</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>The Flying Saucer</title>
	  <link>/the-flying-saucer</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2013-01-27T07:30:26+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/the-flying-saucer</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So it’s a Sunday afternoon in Raleigh, North Carolina. I find myself downtown with not much to do - as most places are closed.</p>

<p>On a cool afternoon, I now find myself at <a href="http://www.beerknurd.com">The Flying Saucer</a> - possibly the best bar I have been to in the Northern Hemisphere (and defiantly the US!)</p>

<p>With over 200 beers available, made up from both local brew craft and imported, where else should I be for a belated solo Australian day party? These guys know how to do beer. Every option is covered - even direct from the cask.</p>

<p>Further the daily “fire sale” which is on local beers today, means I can sample the local drop (which is quite handy to be honest) at $3 a pint!!</p>

<p>To be honest, I never have the yanks credit for any beer I had ever tasted - up until now! They can brew it like the best when it comes to local brew craft style beers. Pity none of these make out shores back in Australia.</p>

<p>Today I have eventually settled on a beer from the New Belgium beer company called “Fat Tire”. It’s an Amber Ale (from Fort Collins, CO) and defiantly delivers.</p>

<p>My “runner-up” for today is one if the locals (from Raleigh, NC) - a wheat beer by Lonerider called “Shotgun Betty”. This was a classic wheat beer with a nice banana follow thru.</p>

<p>To be honest, I would quite happily sit on either of these beers all arvo. But with limited time and variety and experimentation the key I have ended up tasting a wide range of brews from across the US. These two I mention though are the finishers for the afternoon and will happily see me home tonight.</p>

<p>You can join up to the UFO club at the bar also. Members who manage to drink their way to 200 beers are immortalised on a flying saucer on the roof or wall of the bar. The putter ring of the saucer indicating how many times you have reached the 200 brew milestone.</p>

<p>Unfortunately with my short time here I doubt I will come close to qualifying for my own saucer.</p>

<p>Given I was in transit for 26 hours yesterday, I have declared today to be my own personal and informal Australia Day. And I find the Flying Saucer a most enjoyable place to celebrate the day.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20130127-165641.jpg" alt="20130127-165641.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20130127-165652.jpg" alt="20130127-165652.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20130127-165700.jpg" alt="20130127-165700.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20130127-165707.jpg" alt="20130127-165707.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20130127-165713.jpg" alt="20130127-165713.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20130127-165722.jpg" alt="20130127-165722.jpg" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/20130127-193141.jpg" alt="20130127-193141.jpg" /></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
